<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<response>

<lst name="responseHeader">
  <int name="status">0</int>
  <int name="QTime">0</int>
  <lst name="params">
    <str name="q">PSMB5</str>
    <str name="indent">true</str>
    <str name="fl">id, medline_abstract_text, medline_journal_title, medline_article_title</str>
    <str name="rows">5000</str>
    <str name="wt">xml</str>
  </lst>
</lst>
<result name="response" numFound="81" start="0">
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The proteasome is a multi-subunit protease responsible for the production of peptides presented by major histocompatibility complex class I molecules. Accumulated evidence indicates that, upon stimulation with interferon-gamma (IFN-gamma), three beta-type subunits, designated LMP2, LMP7, and PSMB10, are incorporated into the 20S proteasome by displacing the housekeeping beta-type subunits designated PSMB6, PSMB5, and PSMB7, respectively. These changes in the subunit composition appear to facilitate class I-mediated antigen presentation, presumably by altering the cleavage specificities of the proteasome. In the present study, we determined the organization of the mouse gene Psmb5, coding for the PSMB5 subunit. Psmb5 is made up of three exons, spanning approximately 5 kilobases. Its exon-intron organization differs radically from those of the other IFN-gamma-regulated, beta-type subunit genes including Lmp7 with which Psmb5 is believed to share an immediate common ancestor. The structure of the mouse Psmb5 gene is identical to that of its recently characterized human counterpart. Thus, the unique organization of the gene coding for the PSMB5 subunit appears to have been established before mammalian radiation. As well as the Psmb5 gene, the mouse genome contains a processed pseudogene designated Psmb5-ps. Interspecific backcross mapping showed that Psmb5 maps close to the Gtrgal2 locus on chromosome 14 and that Psmb5-ps is located in the vicinity of the Psme3 locus on chromosome 11. These results were confirmed by fluorescent in situ hybridization analysis that localized Psmb5 to band C2 to proximal D1 of chromosome 14 and Psmb5-ps to band D of chromosome 11.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Immunogenetics</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Structural analysis and chromosomal localization of the mouse Psmb5 gene coding for the constitutively expressed beta-type proteasome subunit.</str>
    <str name="id">9382924</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Leukemia research</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">No evidence of mutations of the PSMB5 (beta-5 subunit of proteasome) in a case of myeloma with clinical resistance to Bortezomib.</str>
    <str name="id">16081156</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The proteasome inhibitor bortezomib is a novel anticancer drug that has shown promise in the treatment of refractory multiple myeloma. However, its clinical efficacy has been hampered by the emergence of drug-resistance phenomena, the molecular basis of which remains elusive. Toward this end, we here developed high levels (45- to 129-fold) of acquired resistance to bortezomib in human myelomonocytic THP1 cells by exposure to stepwise increasing (2.5-200 nM) concentrations of bortezomib. Study of the molecular mechanism of bortezomib resistance in these cells revealed (1) an Ala49Thr mutation residing in a highly conserved bortezomib-binding pocket in the proteasome beta5-subunit (PSMB5) protein, (2) a dramatic overexpression (up to 60-fold) of PSMB5 protein but not of other proteasome subunits including PSMB6, PSMB7, and PSMA7, (3) high levels of cross-resistance to beta5 subunit-targeted cytotoxic peptides 4A6, MG132, MG262, and ALLN, but not to a broad spectrum of chemotherapeutic drugs, (4) no marked changes in chymotrypsin-like proteasome activity, and (5) restoration of bortezomib sensitivity in bortezomib-resistant cells by siRNA-mediated silencing of PSMB5 gene expression. Collectively, these findings establish a novel mechanism of bortezomib resistance associated with the selective overexpression of a mutant PSMB5 protein.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Blood</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Molecular basis of bortezomib resistance: proteasome subunit beta5 (PSMB5) gene mutation and overexpression of PSMB5 protein.</str>
    <str name="id">18565852</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Multipotent human bone marrow stromal cells (hBMSCs) potentially serve as a source for cell-based therapy in regenerative medicine. However, in vitro expansion was inescapably accompanied with cell senescence, characterized by inhibited proliferation and compromised pluripotency. We have previously demonstrated that this aging process is closely associated with reduced 20S proteasomal activity, with down-regulation of rate-limiting catalytic β-subunits particularly evident. In the present study, we confirmed that proteasomal activity directly contributes to senescence of hBMSCs, which could be reversed by overexpression of the β5-subunit (PSMB5). Knocking down PSMB5 led to decreased proteasomal activity concurrent with reduced cell proliferation in early-stage hBMSCs, which is similar to the senescent phenotype observed in late-stage cells. In contrast, overexpressing PSMB5 in late-stage cells efficiently restored the normal activity of 20S proteasomes and promoted cell growth, possibly via upregulating the Cyclin D1/CDK4 complex. Additionally, PSMB5 could enhance cell resistance to oxidative stress, as evidenced by the increased cell survival upon exposing senescent hBMSCs to hydrogen peroxide. Furthermore, PSMB5 overexpression retained the pluripotency of late-stage hBMSCs by facilitating their neural differentiation both in vitro and in vivo. Collectively, our work reveals a critical role of PSMB5 in 20S proteasome-mediated protection against replicative senescence, pointing to a possible strategy for maintaining the integrity of culture-expanded hBMSCs by manipulating the expression of PSMB5. </str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Biochemical and biophysical research communications</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Ameliorating replicative senescence of human bone marrow stromal cells by PSMB5 overexpression.</str>
    <str name="id">24393841</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Experimental hematology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Upregulated expression of the PSMB5 gene may contribute to drug resistance in patient with multiple myeloma when treated with bortezomib-based regimen.</str>
    <str name="id">21920470</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The LMP7 and PSMB5 genes were created through an ancient gene duplication event of their ancestral locus. These proteins contain an active site of proteolysis, and LMP7 replaces PSMB5 as a component of the 20S proteasome after stimulation of cells by interferon-gamma. Replacement of PSMB5 by LMP7 changes the profile of the products of 20S proteasome processing, predisposing digested peptides for transport to and display by the immune system. The purpose of this study is to investigate evolutionary forces influencing functional divergence between LMP7 and PSMB5 following duplication. Levels of synonymous and nonsynonymous substitution rates are estimated to infer differences in levels of natural selection. Estimates of substitution rates indicate that natural selection elevated rates of nonsynonymous substitution in LMP7 following gene duplication, whereas PSMB5 experienced an increase in substitution rate that was not likely due to diversifying natural selection following duplication. Following initial divergence, nearly neutral mutations have dominated gene evolution in both lineages. The LMP7 gene locus provides a rare example of a protein with specialized function arising from duplication and divergence of a housekeeping protein by way of natural selection.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Journal of molecular evolution</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Natural selection during functional divergence to LMP7 and proteasome subunit X (PSMB5) following gene duplication.</str>
    <str name="id">15785850</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Bortezomib is an effective agent for treating multiple myeloma (MM). To investigate the underlying mechanisms associated with acquired resistance to this agent, we established two bortezomib-resistant MM cell lines, KMS-11/BTZ and OPM-2/BTZ, the 50% inhibitory concentration values of which were respectively 24.7- and 16.6-fold higher than their parental cell lines. No activation of caspase and BH3-only proteins such as Noxa was noted in bortezomib-resistant cells after exposure to the drug. The accumulation of polyubiquitinated proteins was reduced in bortezomib-resistant cells compared with the parental cells, associated with avoidance of catastrophic ER stress as assessed by downregulation of CHOP expression. These resistant MM cells have a unique point mutation, G322A, in the gene encoding the proteasome beta5 subunit (PSMB5), likely resulting in conformational changes to the bortezomib-binding pocket of this subunit. KMS-11 parental cells transfected to express mutated PSMB5 also showed reduced bortezomib-induced apoptosis compared with those expressing wild-type PSMB5 or the parental cells. Expression of mutated PSMB5 was associated with the prevention of the accumulation of unfolded proteins. Thus, a fraction of MM cells may acquire bortezomib resistance by suppressing apoptotic signals through the inhibition of unfolded protein accumulation and subsequent excessive ER stress by a mutation of the PSMB5 gene.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Leukemia</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Bortezomib-resistant myeloma cell lines: a role for mutated PSMB5 in preventing the accumulation of unfolded proteins and fatal ER stress.</str>
    <str name="id">20555361</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To investigate the relationship between bortezomib resistance and mutations in the proteasome beta5 subunit (PSMB5) gene.</str>
      <str>Various bortezomib-resistant lymphoblastic lymphoma/leukemia lines were established by repeated cycles of bortezomib selection. Mutations were detected by sequencing the complementary DNA of the PSMB5 gene. Mutated clones were selected by limited dilution and cultured without bortezomib. Messenger RNA expression levels of PSMB5 in these mutated clones were measured by quantitative reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction. The degree of resistance was determined by cytotoxicity at various bortezomib concentrations. The chymotrypsin-like activities were assayed by measuring the release of the fluorescent 7-amido-4-methylcoumarin from the substrate N-succinyl-Leu-Leu-Val-Tyr-7-amido-4-methylcoumarin.</str>
      <str>In addition to the previously reported PSMB5 G322A mutant (Ala49Thr), a C323T mutant (Ala49Val), and G322A, C326T conjoined mutant (Ala49Thr and Ala50Val) were selected and clones containing these mutations (JurkatB-G322A, JurkatB-C323T, and JurkatB-G322A/C326T) were obtained. After being cultured without bortezomib for &gt;2 months, no significant difference in PSMB5 messenger RNA levels was detected between these JurkatB cells and parental Jurkat cells. JurkatB-G322A, JurkatB-C323T, and JurkatB-G322A/C326T clones displayed 22.0-fold, 39.4-fold, and 66.7-fold resistance, respectively, to bortezomib compared to Jurkat cells. There were no significant differences between the chymotrypsin-like activities of these mutants and Jurkat cells. The inhibitory effect of bortezomib on chymotrypsin-like activity was the weakest in JurkatB-G322A/C326T cells, and the strongest in JurkatB-G322A cells, with JurkatB-C323T cells falling in between.</str>
      <str>Mutations of the PSMB5 gene resulting in substitutions of Ala49 and Ala50 of PSMB5 protein can confer varying bortezomib resistance.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Experimental hematology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Different mutants of PSMB5 confer varying bortezomib resistance in T lymphoblastic lymphoma/leukemia cells derived from the Jurkat cell line.</str>
    <str name="id">19426847</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The ubiquitin-proteasome system facilitates the degradation of ubiquitin-tagged proteins and performs a regulatory role in cells. Elevated proteasome activity and subunit expression are found in several cancers. However, the inherent molecular mechanisms responsible for increased proteasome function in cancers remain unclear despite the well investigated and defined role of the mammalian proteasome. This study was initiated to elucidate the mechanisms involved in the regulation of β subunits of the mammalian proteasome. Suppression of STAT3 tyrosine phosphorylation coordinately decreased the mRNA and protein levels of the β subunits of the 20 S core complex in DU145 cells. Notably, PSMB5, a molecular target of bortezomib, was shown to be a target of STAT3. Knockdown of STAT3 decreased PSMB5 protein. Inhibition of phospho-STAT3 substantially reduced PSMB5 protein levels in cells expressing constitutively active-STAT3. Accumulation of activated STAT3 resulted in the induction of PSMB5 promoter and protein levels. In addition, a direct correlation was observed between the endogenous levels of PSMB5 and constitutively active STAT3. PSMB5 and STAT3 protein levels remained unaltered following the inhibition of proteasome activity. The EGF-induced concerted increase of β subunits was blocked by inhibition of the EGF receptor or STAT3 but not by the PI3K/AKT or MEK/ERK pathways. Decreased proteasome activities were due to reduced protein levels of catalytic subunits of the proteasome in STAT3-inhibited cells. Combined treatments with bortezomib and inhibitor of STAT3 abrogated proteasome activity and enhanced cellular apoptosis. Overall, we demonstrate that aberrant activation of STAT3 regulates the expression of β subunits, in particular PSMB5, and the catalytic activity of the proteasome. </str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">The Journal of biological chemistry</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Regulation of PSMB5 protein and β subunits of mammalian proteasome by constitutively activated signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 (STAT3): potential role in bortezomib-mediated anticancer therapy.</str>
    <str name="id">24627483</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The 26S proteasome is responsible for degradation of abnormal intracellular proteins, including oxidatively damaged proteins and may play a role as a component of a cellular antioxidative system. However, little is known about regulation of proteasome expression. In the present study, regulation of proteasome expression by the bifunctional enzyme inducer and a specific signaling pathway for this regulation were investigated in murine neuroblastoma cells. Expression of catalytic core subunits including PSMB5 and peptidase activities of the proteasome were elevated following incubation with 3-methylcholanthrene (3-MC). Studies using reporter genes containing the murine Psmb5 promoter showed that transcriptional activity of this gene was enhanced by 3-MC. Overexpression of AhR/Arnt did not affect activation of the Pmsb5 promoter by 3-MC and deletion of the xenobiotic response elements (XREs) from this promoter exerted modest effects on inducibility in response to 3-MC. However, mutation of the proximal AREs of the Psmb5 promoter largely abrogated its inducibility by 3-MC. In addition, this promoter showed a blunted response toward 3-MC in the absence of nrf2; 3-MC incubation increased nuclear levels of Nrf2 only in wild-type cells. Collectively, these results indicate that expression of proteasome subunit PSMB5 is modulated by bifunctional enzyme inducers in a manner independent of the AhR/Arnt-XRE pathway but dependent upon the Nrf2-ARE pathway.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Biochemical and biophysical research communications</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Induction of 26S proteasome subunit PSMB5 by the bifunctional inducer 3-methylcholanthrene through the Nrf2-ARE, but not the AhR/Arnt-XRE, pathway.</str>
    <str name="id">16723119</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To study the mechanism of acquired resistance to bortezomib, a new antitumor drug that is the first therapeutic proteasome inhibitor, we established a series of bortezomib-resistant T lymphoblastic lymphoma/leukemia cell lines, designated the JurkatBs, from the parental Jurkat line via repeated drug selection. There were no significant differences in the growth curves or colony formation between the JurkatB cells and parental Jurkat cells. The effects of bortezomib on cytotoxicity, cell cycle arrest, and induction of apoptosis were decreased in JurkatB cells compared with parental Jurkat cells. A mutation in the proteasome beta5 subunit (PSMB5) gene (G322A), which encodes an amino acid change from Ala to Thr at polypeptide position 108, was detected by sequencing full-length cDNA clones and direct polymerase chain reaction products of the PSMB5 gene. Bortezomib caused less inhibition of chymotrypsin-like activity in resistant cells. When the G322A mutant PSMB5 was retrovirally introduced into parental Jurkat cells, it conferred bortezomib resistance to these cells, resulting in decreased cytotoxicity, apoptosis, and inhibition of chymotrypsin-like activity. The predicted structure of A108T-mutated PSMB5 shows a conformational change that suggests decreased affinity to bortezomib. In short, the G322A mutation of the PSMB5 gene is a novel mechanism for bortezomib resistance.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">The Journal of pharmacology and experimental therapeutics</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Point mutation of the proteasome beta5 subunit gene is an important mechanism of bortezomib resistance in bortezomib-selected variants of Jurkat T cell lymphoblastic lymphoma/leukemia line.</str>
    <str name="id">18502982</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Reanalyses of vertebrate PSMB5 and PSMB8 genes were conducted with a newly obtained amphioxus sequence. The phylogenetic analysis indicated that the amphioxus sequence is an outgroup of both vertebrate PSMB5 and PSMB8 genes. The agnathan sequences were previously thought to be closer to PSMB5 than PSMB8 sequences. However, in this study the phylogenetic trees supported the clustering of agnathan sequences with PSMB8 rather than with PSMB5 sequences. In the alignment there are many sites in which the agnathan sequences are more similar to PSMB5 than PSMB8 sequences. Parsimony analysis showed that the amino acid pattern at these sites could be explained by one substitution on the ancestral branch leading to the jawed vertebrate PSMB8 cluster. The number of substitutions required at these sites was the same for different tree topologies with respect to the position of agnathans. The phylogenetic analyses of PSMB6/PSMB9 and PSMB7/PSMB10 genes indicated that all the interferon-gamma-inducible forms have evolved two to three times faster than the housekeeping forms in the jawed vertebrate lineage. Hence although the agnathan sequences cluster with the PSMB8 sequences, they have a slower rate of evolution similar to that of the housekeeping forms, and may be functioning as housekeeping forms.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Gene</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Sequencing of amphioxus PSMB5/8 gene and phylogenetic position of agnathan sequences.</str>
    <str name="id">11814690</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The proteasome inhibitor, bortezomib, a boronic dipeptide which reversibly inhibit the chymotrypsin-like activity at the β5-subunit of proteasome (PSMB5), has marked efficacy against multiple myeloma and several non-Hodgkin's lymphoma subtypes, and has a potential therapeutic role against other malignancy diseases. However, intrinsic and acquired resistance to bortezomib may limit its efficacy. In this article, we discuss recent advances in the molecular understanding of bortezomib resistance. Resistance mechanisms discussed include mutations of PSMB5 and the up-regulation of proteasome subunits, alterations of gene and protein expression in stress response, cell survival and antiapoptotic pathways, and multidrug resistance. </str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Biomarker research</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The resistance mechanisms of proteasome inhibitor bortezomib.</str>
    <str name="id">24252210</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>A proteasome is a multi-subunit protein complex, which plays a central role in ubiquitin-dependent protein degradation in all eukaryotic cells. The 26S proteasome is composed of a catalytic 20S core complex and one or two 19S regulatory complexes. The 20S core complex forms a cylinder consisting of four stacked rings of seven α (PSMA1-7) or β (PSMB1-7) subunits. Target proteins are degraded in the cavity of the 20S complex due to proteolytic activities of three β subunits having catalytic sites located on the inner surface of the cylinder. The aim of this study was the generation of polyclonal antibodies against human proteasome subunits PSMA3, PSMA5, and PSMB5 and characterization of their experimental applications. To construct GST-fusion proteins, DNA sequences encoding PSMA3, PSMA5, and PSMB5 were cloned into prokaryotic expression vectors pGEX-5X-1 or pGEX-4T-3. Recombinant proteins GST-PSMA3, GST-PSMA5, and GST-PSMB5 were highly expressed in E. coli BL21 (DE3) cells, purified by glutathione-affinity chromatography and further used for rabbit immunization. The activity and specificity of the obtained antibody-containing sera were evaluated using Western blot analysis and immunoprecipitation. We have shown by Western blot analysis that our anti-PSMA3, anti-PSMA5, and anti-PSMB5 antibodies recognized both recombinant and endogenous proteins from different human cell lines. We have also shown that anti-PSMA3 and anti-PSMA5 sera were able to recognize and immunoprecipitate native forms of both endogenous and overexpressed FLAG-tagged proteins PSMA3 and PSMA5, respectively. Thus, the antibodies generated against PSMA3, PSMA5, and PSMB5 can be used in various experimental applications, including the evaluation of cellular levels of proteasome subunits in cell extracts and affinity purification of the endogenous and/or overexpressed proteasome subunits, which facilitates subsequent analysis of their post-translational modifications as well as protein-protein interactions in vivo.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Hybridoma (2005)</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Polyclonal antibodies against human proteasome subunits PSMA3, PSMA5, and PSMB5.</str>
    <str name="id">22894781</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To study the mechanism of bortezomib resistance in JurkatB lines derived from T-lymphoblastic lymphoma/leukemia Jurkat line.</str>
      <str>Cytotoxicities of popular chemotherapeutic drugs to JurkatB cells were analyzed by trypan blue assay. Functional drug efflux in JurkatB cells was determined by flow cytometry utilizing daunorubicin and the expression of P-glycoprotein (P-gp) was detected by Western blot. mRNA expression levels of proteasome beta5 subunit (PSMB5) were measured by quantitation real-time reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction. In situ hybridization was performed to detect the amplification of PSMB5 gene. The chymotrypsin-like activities were assayed by measuring the release of the fluorescent 7-amido-4-methylcoumarin (AMC) from the substrate N-succinyl-Leu-Leu-Val-Tyr-AMC. Cytogenetic studies were performed using R-banded metaphases and fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH) analysis. IkappaB-alpha levels were detected by Western blot.</str>
      <str>No cross-resistance to daunorubicin, adriamycin, vindesine, and etoposide was found in JurkatB cells. No evidence of drug efflux was found in JurkatB cells and the expression of P-gp was negative. The PSMB5 mRNA was overexpressed in highly resistant JurkatB5 and JurkatB1 lines compared with parental Jurkat, corresponding well with the increase of chymotrypsin-like activity and a karyotype of i(14q). Amplification of PSMB5 gene was demonstrated by in situ hybridization and FISH. The decreased IkappaB-alpha level in JurkatB5 cells after bortezomib treatment indicating an upregulation of nuclear factor-kappaB (NF-kappaB) activity.</str>
      <str>The mechanism of bortezomib resistance is different from that of multidrug resistance. Overexpression of PSMB5 is an important mechanism for bortezomib resistance in JurkatB lines. NF-kappaB may play a critical role in evading the apoptotic effects.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Experimental hematology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Overexpression of the PSMB5 gene contributes to bortezomib resistance in T-lymphoblastic lymphoma/leukemia cells derived from Jurkat line.</str>
    <str name="id">18562081</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The thymoproteasome is a recently discovered, specialized form of 20S proteasomes expressed exclusively in the thymic cortex. Although the precise molecular mechanism by which the thymoproteasome exerts its function remains to be elucidated, accumulating evidence indicates that it plays a crucial role in positive selection of T cells. In the present study, we analyzed the evolution of the β5t subunit, a β-type catalytic subunit uniquely present in thymoproteasomes. The gene coding for the β5t subunit, designated PSMB11, was identified in the cartilaginous fish, the most divergent group of jawed vertebrates compared to the other jawed vertebrates, but not in jawless vertebrates or invertebrates. Interestingly, teleost fish have two copies of apparently functional PSMB11 genes, designated PSMB11a and PSMB11b, that encode β5t subunits with distinct amino acids in the S1 pocket. BLAST searches of genome databases suggest that birds such as chickens, turkey, and zebra finch lost the PSMB11 gene, and have neither thymoproteasomes nor immunoproteasomes. In mammals, reptiles, amphibians, and teleost fishes, the PSMB11 gene (the PSMB11a gene in teleost fish) is located next to the PSMB5 gene coding for the β5 subunit of the standard 20S proteasome, indicating that the PSMB11 gene arose by tandem duplication from the evolutionarily more ancient PSMB5 gene. The general absence of introns in PSMB11 and an unusual exon-intron structure of jawed vertebrate PSMB5 suggest that PSMB5 lost introns and duplicated in tandem in a common ancestor of jawed vertebrates, with PSMB5 subsequently gaining two introns and PSMB11 remaining intronless.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Immunogenetics</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Comparative genomic analysis of the proteasome β5t subunit gene: implications for the origin and evolution of thymoproteasomes.</str>
    <str name="id">21748441</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Bortezomib is a proteasome inhibitor approved for anticancer therapy. However, variable sensitivity of tumor cells exists in this therapy probably due to differences in the expression of proteasome subunits. G(alpha)(12/13) serves modulators or signal transducers in diverse pathways. This study investigated whether cancer cells display differential sensitivity to bortezomib with reference to G(alpha)(12/13) expression, and if so, whether G(alpha)(12/13) affects the expression of proteasome subunits and their activities. Bortezomib treatment exhibited greater sensitivities in Huh7 and SNU886 cells (epithelial type) than SK-Hep1 and SNU449 cells (mesenchymal type) that exhibited higher levels of G(alpha)(12/13). Overexpression of an active mutant of G(alpha)(12) (Galpha(12)QL) or G(alpha)(13) (G(alpha)(13)QL) diminished the ability of bortezomib to induce cytotoxicity in Huh7 cells. Moreover, transfection with the minigene that disturbs G protein-coupled receptor-G protein coupling (CT12 or CT13) increased it in SK-Hep1 cells. Consistently, MiaPaCa2 cells transfected with CT12 or CT13 exhibited a greater sensitivity to bortezomib. Evidence of G(alpha)(12/13)'s antagonism on the anticancer effect of bortezomib was verified in the reversal by G(alpha)(12)QL or G(alpha)(13)QL of the minigenes' enhancement of cytotoxity. Real-time polymerase chain reaction assay enabled us to identify PSMB5, multicatalytic endopeptidase complex-like-1, and proteasome activator subunit-1 repression by CT12 or CT13. Furthermore, G(alpha)(12/13) inhibition enhanced the ability of bortezomib to repress PSMB5, as shown by immunoblotting and proteasome activity assay. Moreover, this inhibitory effect on PSMB5 was attenuated by G(alpha)G(alpha)(12)QL or G(alpha)(13)QL. In conclusion, the inhibition of G(alpha)(12/13) activities may enhance the anticancer effect of bortezomib through PSMB5 repression, providing insight into the G(alpha)(12/13) pathway for the regulation of proteasomal activity.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Carcinogenesis</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">G(alpha)12/13 inhibition enhances the anticancer effect of bortezomib through PSMB5 downregulation.</str>
    <str name="id">20478922</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The proteasome is a multisubunit cellular organelle that functions as a nonlysosomal threonine protease. Proteasomes play a critical role in the degradation of proteins, regulating a variety of cellular processes, and they are also the target for antineoplastic proteasome inhibitors. Genetic variation in proteasome subunits could influence both proteasome function and response to drug therapy.</str>
      <str>We resequenced genes encoding the three active proteasome beta subunits using 240 DNA samples from four ethnic groups and the beta 5 subunit gene in 79 DNA samples from multiple myeloma patients who had been treated with the proteasome inhibitor bortezomib. Resequencing was followed by functional studies of polymorphisms identified in the coding region and 3'-flanking region (3'-FR) of PSMB5, the gene encoding the target for clinically useful proteasome inhibitors.</str>
      <str>Resequencing of 240 DNA samples identified a series of novel ethnic-specific polymorphisms that are not represented in public databases. The PSMB5 3'-FR 1042 G allele significantly increased transcription during reporter gene studies, observations confirmed by genotype-phenotype correlations between single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNP) in PSMB5 and mRNA expression in the 240 lymphoblastoid cell lines from which the resequenced DNA was obtained. Studies with patient DNA samples identified additional novel PSMB5 polymorphisms, including a SNP and an insertion in the 3'-FR. Reporter-gene studies indicated that these two novel polymorphisms might decrease transcription.</str>
      <str>These results show that nonsynonymous coding SNPs in the PSMB5 gene did not show significant effects on proteasome activity, but SNPs did influence transcription. Future studies might focus on regulatory region polymorphisms.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Clinical cancer research : an official journal of the American Association for Cancer Research</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Proteasome beta subunit pharmacogenomics: gene resequencing and functional genomics.</str>
    <str name="id">18519783</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>There is a huge body of evidence showing that long-termed diabetes mellitus is followed with hippocampal dysfunction. The goal of this work was to investigate the expression of proteasome subunits PSMB5 and PSMB9 mRNA in CA1, CA2 and CA3 areas of hippocampus in parallel with processes of cell death (apoptosis and necrosis) in development dynamics of streptozotocine-induced diabetes. We have studied hippocampal neurons using chromatine dye Hoechst-33342 and immunohistochemical detection of apoptotic cell death marker caspase-3. At day 3 and 7 after injection of streptozotocine we have performed visualization of caspase-3-immunopositive neurons showing signs of neurodegeneration in hippocampal sections using confocal microscope Olympus FV1000. The rate of proteasome subunits PSMB5 and PSMB9 mRNA expression was determined with RT-PCR. The results indicated elevation of PSMB9 mRNA content (from 4807 +/- 0.392 arbU up to 20,023 +/- 4949 arbU on day 3 and up to 20,253 +/- 5141 arbU on day 7). A maximal number of cells with signs of chromatin condensation was observed at day 3 and day 7 in CA2 and CA3 area (11.51% and 12.49% respectively). That indicates an intensification of proapoptotic processes. Summarizing the results presented above we can conclude that during the first week of diabetes mellitus development, hippocampal cells undergo the process of impairment and degeneration.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Fiziolohichnyĭ zhurnal (Kiev, Ukraine : 1994)</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">[Expression of proteasome subunits PSMB5 and PSMB9 mRNA in hippocampal neurons in experimental diabetes mellitus: link with apoptosis and necrosis].</str>
    <str name="id">20968039</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Journal of clinical oncology : official journal of the American Society of Clinical Oncology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Therapeutic landscape of carfilzomib and other modulators of the ubiquitin-proteasome pathway.</str>
    <str name="id">25605842</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Most Rho family GTPases serve as key molecular switches in a wide spectrum of biological processes. An increasing number of studies have expanded their roles to the spermatogenesis. Several members of Rho family have been confirmed to be essential for mammalian spermatogenesis, but the precise roles of this family in male reproduction have not been well studied yet. Here we report a surprising function of an atypical and testis-specific Rho GTPase, RSA-14-44 in spermatogenesis. Featured by unique structural and expressional patterns, RSA-14-44 is distinguished from three canonical members of Rho cluster. Thus, we define RSA-14-44 as a new member of Rho GTPases family and rename it RhoS (Rho in spermatogenic cells). RhoS associates with PSMB5, a catalytic subunit of the proteasome, in a series of stage-specific spermatogenic cells. More importantly, RhoS does not directly modulate the cellular proteasome activity, but participates in regulating the stability of "unincorporated" PSMB5 precursors. Meanwhile, our data demonstrate that the activation of RhoS is prerequisite for negatively regulating the stability of PSMB5 precursors. Therefore, our finding uncovers a direct and functional connection between the Rho GTPase family and the pathway of proteasome biogenesis and provide new clues for deciphering the secrets of spermatogenesis.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Molecular biology of the cell</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">A novel testis-specific GTPase serves as a link to proteasome biogenesis: functional characterization of RhoS/RSA-14-44 in spermatogenesis.</str>
    <str name="id">20980621</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Salinosporamide A (NPI-0052, marizomib) is a naturally occurring proteasome inhibitor derived from the marine actinobacterium Salinispora tropica, and represents a promising clinical agent in the treatment of hematologic malignancies. Recently, these actinobacteria were shown to harbor self-resistance properties to salinosporamide A by expressing redundant catalytically active mutants of the 20S proteasome β-subunit, reminiscent of PSMB5 mutations identified in cancer cells with acquired resistance to the founding proteasome inhibitor bortezomib (BTZ). Here, we assessed the growth inhibitory potential of salinosporamide A in human acute lymphocytic leukemia CCRF-CEM cells, and its 10-fold (CEM/BTZ7) and 123-fold (CEM/BTZ200) bortezomib-resistant sublines harboring PSMB5 mutations. Parental cells displayed sensitivity to salinosporamide A (IC50 = 5.1 nM), whereas their bortezomib-resistant sublines were 9- and 17-fold cross-resistant to salinosporamide A, respectively. Notably, combination experiments of salinosporamide A and bortezomib showed synergistic activity in CEM/BTZ200 cells. CEM cells gradually exposed to 20 nM salinosporamide A (CEM/S20) displayed stable 5-fold acquired resistance to salinosporamide A and were 3-fold cross-resistant to bortezomib. Consistent with the acquisition of a PSMB5 point mutation (M45V) in CEM/S20 cells, salinosporamide A displayed a markedly impaired capacity to inhibit β5-associated catalytic activity. Last, compared with parental CEM cells, CEM/S20 cells exhibited up to 2.5-fold upregulation of constitutive proteasome subunits, while retaining unaltered immunoproteasome subunit expression. In conclusion, salinosporamide A displayed potent antileukemic activity against bortezomib-resistant leukemia cells. β-Subunit point mutations as a common feature of acquired resistance to salinosporamide A and bortezomib in hematologic cells and S. tropica suggest an evolutionarily conserved mechanism of resistance to proteasome inhibitors. </str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Molecular pharmacology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Antileukemic activity and mechanism of drug resistance to the marine Salinispora tropica proteasome inhibitor salinosporamide A (Marizomib).</str>
    <str name="id">24737138</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The proteasome is a large multicatalytic proteinase that plays a role in the generation of peptides for presentation by major histocompatibility complex class I molecules. The 20S proteolytic core of mammalian proteasomes is assembled from a group of 17 protein subunits that generate a distinctive pattern of spots upon two-dimensional gel electrophoresis. The genes for most of these subunits have been cloned from humans and rats. We isolated cDNA clones for the mouse orthologues of ten of the subunits [PSMA1 (C2), PSMA2 (C3), PSMA3 (C8), PSMA4 (C9), PSMA5 (ZETA), PSMA6 (IOTA), PSMA7 (C6-I), PSMB2 (C7-I), PSMB3 (C10-II), and PSMB5 (X)] to complete the cloning of all of the mouse subunits. Using antisera raised against these subunits or their orthologues, we verified the identity of these proteins by two-dimensional NEPHGE-PAGE.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Immunogenetics</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The complete primary structure of mouse 20S proteasomes.</str>
    <str name="id">10436176</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Bortezomib (BTZ), a registered proteasome inhibitor (PI) for multiple myeloma, has also been proposed as a potential antirheumatic agent. Its reported side effects, however, make it unappealing for long-term administration, and resistance may also develop. To overcome this, second-generation PIs became available. Here, we investigated whether a novel class of peptide epoxyketone-based PIs, including carfilzomib, N-((S)-3-methoxy-1-(((S)-3-methoxy-1-(((S)-1-((R)-2-methyloxiran-2-yl)-1-oxo-3-phenylpropan-2-yl)amino)-1-oxopropan-2-yl)amino)-1-oxopropan-2-yl)-2-methylthiazole-5-carboxamide (ONX0912), and (S)-3-(4-methoxyphenyl)-N-((S)-1-((S)-2-methyloxiran-2-yl)-1-oxo-3-phenylpropan-2-yl)-2-((S)-2-(2-morpholinoacetamido)propanamido)propanamide (ONX0914), might escape two established BTZ-resistance mechanisms: 1) mutations in the proteasome β5 subunit (PSMB5) targeted by these PIs, and 2) drug efflux mediated by ATP-binding cassette transporters. THP1 myeloid sublines with acquired resistance to BTZ (54- to 235-fold) caused by mutations in the PSMB5 gene displayed marked cross-resistance but less pronounced cross-resistance to carfilzomib (9- to 32-fold), ONX0912 (39- to 62-fold), and ONX0914 (27- to 97-fold). As for ATP-binding cassette transporter-mediated efflux, lymphoid CEM/VLB cells with P-glycoprotein (Pgp)/multidrug resistance 1 overexpression exhibited substantial resistance to carfilzomib (114-fold), ONX0912 (23-fold), and ONX0914 (162-fold), whereas less resistance to BTZ (4.5-fold) was observed. Consistently, β5 subunit-associated chymotrypsin-like proteasome activity was significantly less inhibited in these CEM/VLB cells. Ex vivo analysis of peripheral blood mononuclear cells from therapy-naive patients with rheumatoid arthritis revealed that, although basal Pgp levels were low, P-glycoprotein expression compromised the inhibitory effect of carfilzomib and ONX0914. However, the use of P121 (reversin 121), a Pgp transport inhibitor, restored parental cell inhibitory levels in both CEM/VLB cells and peripheral blood mononuclear cells. These results indicate that the pharmacologic activity of these PIs may be hindered by drug resistance mechanisms involving PSMB5 mutations and PI extrusion via Pgp.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">The Journal of pharmacology and experimental therapeutics</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Inactivating PSMB5 mutations and P-glycoprotein (multidrug resistance-associated protein/ATP-binding cassette B1) mediate resistance to proteasome inhibitors: ex vivo efficacy of (immuno)proteasome inhibitors in mononuclear blood cells from patients with rheumatoid arthritis.</str>
    <str name="id">22235146</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Ubiquitin-dependent proteasomal proteolysis is crucialin the turnover of cardiomyocytes functional proteins (actin, myosin, ion channels at. al.), therefore, investigation of cell death after ubiquitin (UBB) gene silencing using RNA interference and anoxia-reoxygenation (AR) modeling appears to be attractive. Cardiomyocytes were transfected by siRNA to ubiquitin gene using electroporation procedure, and then primary culture was treated by 30 min of anoxia and 60 min of reoxygenation. The number of living, necrotic and apoptotic cardiomyocytes was determined by fluorescence microscopy. The level of UBB and proteasome subunits beta5 (PSMB5) and beta9 (PSMB9) mRNA expression was estimated by real-time PCR. It was shown that UBB mRNA expression was increased by 2.1 times after AR modelling (P &lt; 0.05). Small interference RNA injection in cell culture decreased ubiquitin, PSMB5 and PSMB9 expression by 2.4 (P &lt; 0.05), 1.3 (P &gt; 0.05) and 1.6 (P &lt; 0.05) times, respectively, compared with control (scrambled siRNA introduction). At the same time, the number of living cardiomyocytes decreased to 70.26 +/- 1.54%, P&lt;0.05, and the level of necrotic cells, apoptotic cells and cells with signs of autophagy augmented by 25.92 +/- 1.52%, (P = 0.38), 4.32 +/- 0.53% (P = 0.15) and 38.2 +/- 3.81% (P = 0.001), respectively. Ubiquitin silencing after AR (30 min/l h) increased the number of living cells by 3.7% and decreased the number of necrotic cells by 4.7% and did not alter the apoptotic and autophagic cells populations. The data obtained indicate that ubiquitin gene silencing, mRNA expression of which augmented during AR, induces necrotic and autophagic death of intact neonatal cardiomyocytes in culture, but enhances the AR resistance of these cells to some extent.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Fiziolohichnyĭ zhurnal (Kiev, Ukraine : 1994)</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">[Effects of ubiquitin gene silencing in anoxia-reoxygenation of cultured cardiomyocytes].</str>
    <str name="id">20968036</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Optineurin is a gene linked to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, Paget disease of bone, and glaucoma, a major blinding disease. Mutations such as E50K were identified in glaucoma patients. We investigated herein the involvement of ubiquitin-proteasome pathway (UPP) and autophagy, two major routes for protein clearance, in processing of optineurin in a retinal ganglion cell model line RGC5 and neuronal PC12 cells. It was found that the endogenous optineurin level in neuronal cells was increased by treatment of proteasomal inhibitor but not by autophagic and lysosomal inhibitors. Multiple bands immunoreactive to anti-ubiquitin were seen in the optineurin pulldown, indicating that optineurin was ubiquitinated. In cells overexpressing wild type and E50K optineurin, the level of the proteasome regulatory β5 subunit (PSMB5, indicative of proteasome activity) was reduced, whereas that for autophagy marker microtubule-associated protein 1 light chain 3 was enhanced compared with controls. Autophagosome formation was detected by electron microscopy. The foci formed after optineurin transfection were increased upon treatment of an autophagic inhibitor but were decreased by treatment of an inducer, rapamycin. Moreover, the level of optineurin-triggered apoptosis was reduced by rapamycin. This study thus provides compelling evidence that in a normal homeostatic situation, the turnover of endogenous optineurin involves mainly UPP. When optineurin is up-regulated or mutated, the UPP function is compromised, and autophagy comes into play. A decreased PSMB5 level and an induced autophagy were also demonstrated in vivo in retinal ganglion cells of E50K transgenic mice, validating and making relevant the in vitro findings.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">The Journal of biological chemistry</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Processing of optineurin in neuronal cells.</str>
    <str name="id">21059646</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The 26S proteasome is responsible for degradation of abnormal proteins and may play a role in cell survival upon oxidative stress. The indirect antioxidant sulforaphane (SFN) protects animal tissues from chemical toxicants by increasing the expression of several families of Nrf2-regulated genes. The role of induction of the 26S proteasome in cytoprotection by SFN was investigated in murine neuroblastoma Neuro2A cells. SFN enhanced the expression of the catalytic subunits of the proteasome, as well as proteasomal peptidase activities in these cells. Such treatment with SFN protected cells from hydrogen peroxide-mediated cytotoxicity in a manner dependent on proteasomal function. Inhibition of proteasome activities using pharmacological interventions significantly attenuated the protective effects of SFN against hydrogen peroxide cytotoxicity, as well as protein oxidation. Moreover, overexpression of the catalytic subunit PSMB5 enhanced proteasome function and led to elevated resistance against hydrogen peroxide toxicity and extent of protein oxidation compared to blank-plasmid-transfected cells. Pretreatment of PSMB5-overexpressing cells with SFN did not further enhance this resistance. Collectively, these results suggest that the cytoprotective effects of SFN against oxidative stress are in part due to up-regulation of the proteasome system. Therefore, inducers of proteasome expression may ameliorate the accumulation of damaged proteins associated with neurodegeneration and other diseases in whose etiologies protein oxidation plays a role.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Free radical biology &amp; medicine</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Role of increased expression of the proteasome in the protective effects of sulforaphane against hydrogen peroxide-mediated cytotoxicity in murine neuroblastoma cells.</str>
    <str name="id">17664144</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The PSMD14 (POH1, also known as Rpn11/MPR1/S13/CepP1) protein within the 19S complex (19S cap; PA700) is responsible for substrate deubiquitination during proteasomal degradation. The role of PSMD14 in cell proliferation and senescence was explored using siRNA knockdown in carcinoma cell lines. Our results reveal that down-regulation of PSMD14 by siRNA transfection had a considerable impact on cell viability causing cell arrest in the G0-G1 phase, ultimately leading to senescence. The molecular events associated with decreased cell proliferation, cell cycle arrest and senescence include down-regulation of cyclin B1-CDK1-CDC25C, down-regulation of cyclin D1 and up-regulation of p21(/Cip) and p27(/Kip1). Most notably, phosphorylation of the retinoblastoma protein was markedly reduced in PSMD14 knockdown cells. A comparative study with PSMB5, a subunit of the 20S proteasome, revealed that PSMB5 and PSMD14 have different effects on cell cycle, senescence and associated molecular events. These data support the view that the 19S and 20S subunits of the proteasome have distinct biological functions and imply that targeting 19S and 20S would have distinct molecular consequences on tumor cells.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Experimental cell research</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Knockdown of human deubiquitinase PSMD14 induces cell cycle arrest and senescence.</str>
    <str name="id">19732767</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Proteasomes degrade damaged proteins formed during oxidative stress, thereby promoting cell survival. Neurodegenerative and other age-related disorders are associated with reduced proteasome activity. We show herein that expression of most subunits of 20S and 19S proteasomes, which collectively assemble the 26S proteasome, was enhanced up to threefold in livers of mice following treatment with dithiolethiones, which act as indirect antioxidants. Subunit protein levels and proteasome activity were coordinately increased. No induction was seen in mice where the transcription factor Nrf2 was disrupted. Promoter activity of the PSMB5 subunit of the 20S proteasome increased with either Nrf2 overexpression or treatment with antioxidants in mouse embryonic fibroblasts. Tandem antioxidant response elements in the proximal promoter of PSMB5 that controlled these responses were identified. We propose that induction of the 26S proteasome through the Nrf2 pathway represents an important indirect action of these antioxidants that can contribute to their protective effects against chronic diseases.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Molecular and cellular biology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Antioxidants enhance mammalian proteasome expression through the Keap1-Nrf2 signaling pathway.</str>
    <str name="id">14612418</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The expression of a variety of cytoprotective genes is regulated by short cis-acting elements in their promoters, called antioxidant response elements (AREs). A central regulator of ARE-mediated gene expression is the NF-E2-related factor 2 (Nrf2). Human hepatitis B virus (HBV) induces a strong activation of Nrf2/ARE-regulated genes in vitro and in vivo. This is triggered by the HBV-regulatory proteins (HBx and LHBs) via c-Raf and MEK. The Nrf2/ARE-mediated induction of cytoprotective genes by HBV results in a better protection of HBV-positive cells against oxidative damage as compared with control cells. Furthermore, there is a significantly increased expression of the Nrf2/ARE-regulated proteasomal subunit PSMB5 in HBV-positive cells that is associated with a decreased level of the immunoproteasome subunit PSMB5i. In accordance with this finding, HBV-positive cells display a higher constitutive proteasome activity and a decreased activity of the immunoproteasome as compared with control cells even after interferon α/γ treatment. The HBV-dependent induction of Nrf2/ARE-regulated genes might ensure survival of the infected cell, shape the immune response to HBV, and thereby promote establishment of the infection.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">The Journal of biological chemistry</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Hepatitis B virus induces expression of antioxidant response element-regulated genes by activation of Nrf2.</str>
    <str name="id">20956535</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To determine whether the overexpression of the proteasome catalytic beta5 subunit (PSMB5) can induce the expression of the catalytic subunits beta1 and beta2, enhance proteasome activity, and exert a cytoprotective effect in lens epithelial cells.</str>
      <str>Cells from the human lens epithelial cell line SRA01/04 (LECs) were stably transfected either with a plasmid expressing the proteasome catalytic subunit beta5 or with an empty plasmid. beta-5-expressing LECs and controls were analyzed for the expression of beta1, beta2, beta5, and alpha6 proteasome subunits; chymotrypsin-like (CT-L) and peptidylglutamyl-peptide hydrolase (PGPH) catalytic activities; as well as for the accumulation of carbonylated proteins, rates of cell viability, and apoptosis after oxidative stress.</str>
      <str>Stable expression of the beta5 proteasome subunit resulted in increased expression of the catalytic subunits beta1 and beta2, increased CT-L and PGPH proteasome activities, and increased resistance to accumulation of carbonylated proteins and cell death after oxidative stress.</str>
      <str>The proteasome activity can be genetically "upregulated" in lens cells by overexpression of the beta5 catalytic subunit. The resulting increase in proteasome activity leads to a decrease in the accumulation of oxidized proteins and enhanced cell survival following oxidative stress.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Molecular vision</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Cytoprotective effects of proteasome beta5 subunit overexpression in lens epithelial cells.</str>
    <str name="id">17262013</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Variations within proteasome β (PSMB) genes, which encode the β subunits of the 20S proteasome, may affect proteasome function, assembly, and/or binding of proteasome inhibitors. To investigate the potential association between PSMB gene variants and treatment-emergent resistance to bortezomib and/or long-term outcomes, in the present study, PSMB gene sequence variation was characterized in tumor DNA samples from patients who participated in the phase 3 Assessment of Proteasome Inhibition for Extending Remissions (APEX) study of bortezomib versus high-dose dexamethasone for treatment of relapsed multiple myeloma. Twelve new PSMB variants were identified. No associations were found between PSMB single nucleotide polymorphism genotype frequency and clinical response to bortezomib or dexamethasone treatment or between PSMB single nucleotide polymorphism allelic frequency and pooled overall survival or time to progression. Although specific PSMB5 variants have been identified previously in preclinical models of bortezomib resistance, these variants were not detected in patient tumor samples collected after clinical relapse from bortezomib, which suggests that alternative mechanisms underlie bortezomib insensitivity.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Blood</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Sequence analysis of β-subunit genes of the 20S proteasome in patients with relapsed multiple myeloma treated with bortezomib or dexamethasone.</str>
    <str name="id">23018640</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>This study was purposed to investigate the differences of cyto biological characteristics and protein expression levels between bortezomib-resistant T-lymphoblastic lymphoma/leukemia cell lines JurkatB containing PSMB5 G322A mutation and their parent cell line Jurkat, The cytotoxicities of bortezomib and chemotherapeutic drugs to JurkatB5 cells (end selection concentration of bortezomib was 500 nmol/L), JurkatB8 (end selection concentration 800 nmol/L) and Jurkat cells were analyzed. The cell growth curves were drawn with viable cell counts by trypan blue assay, the colony formation rate were assayed by soft-agar colony culture, and the cell distributions in cell cycle were analyzed by flow cytometry, mRNA expression levels of multidrug resistance (MDR) genes MDR1, LRP and MRP were measured by real-time fluorescence quantitative RT-PCR, the differences of protein expression levels were detected by SpringBio antibody microarray containing 720 proteins. The results showed that the drug resistance multiples for 48 hours of JurkatB5 and JurkatB8 cells (relative to Jurkat) to bortezomib were increased by 33.52 and 39.04 times, respectively. JurkatB5 and JurkatB8 cells did not display significant cross-resistance to daunorubicin, adriamycin, vindesine, and etoposide after exposure for 48 hours. There were no significant differences in the cell growth curve, colony formation rate and cell distributions in cell cycle between JurkatB5, JurkatB8 and Jurkat cells (p &gt; 0.05). There were no significant differences of mRNA expression levels of MDR1, LRP, MRP between JurkatB5 and Jurkat cells (p &gt; 0.05). There were 264 analyzable expression points detected by antibody microarray. Among them, 252 protein expression levels were not significantly different between JurkatB5, JurkatB8 and Jurkat cells (&lt; 2-fold), including 15 drug resistance-related proteins. 12 proteins were detected at higher or lower expression levels in JurkatB5 or JurkatB8 cells then that in Jurkat cells (cell division cycle protein 34, cell division cycle protein 37, CD34 Type II, matrix metalloproteinase-2, tenascin, Golgi complex, involucrin, histone deacetylase 1, perforin, prolactin, retinoic acid receptor β, integrin β-1), but no proteins were detected in JurkatB5 and JurkatB8 cells with higher or lower expression levels than that in Jurkat cells. It is concluded that there are no significant differences in the characteristics of cellular biology between Jurkat and JurkatB with bortezomib-resistant and PSMB5 G322A mutation. There are no significant phenotype change of MDR and overexpression of genes related to MDR in PSMB5 mutated cells. There are no significantly differential expressions of a majority of known proteins related to drug resistance, tumor cells growth, proliferation, apoptosis, malignancy degree, aggressiveness.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Zhongguo shi yan xue ye xue za zhi / Zhongguo bing li sheng li xue hui = Journal of experimental hematology / Chinese Association of Pathophysiology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">[Comparison of protein expression profiles between bortezomib-resistant JurkatB cells with PSMB5 mutation and their parent cells].</str>
    <str name="id">21867604</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The purpose of this work was to investigate the role of the ubiquitin-proteasome network (UPN) in prostate cancer (PCA) and to elicit potential markers for this disease. The UPN represents a key factor in the maintenance of cellular homoeostasis as a result of its fundamental function in the regulation of intracellular protein degradation. Members of this network have a role in the biology of haematological and solid tumours. Tumour cells and normal epithelial cells from 22 prostatectomy specimens were isolated by laser microdissection. Prostate biopsy samples from healthy individuals served for technical calibration and as controls. Transcript levels of eight selected genes with E3 ubiquitin ligase activity (labelling target proteins for proteasome degradation) and two genes belonging to the proteasome-multienzyme complex itself were analysed by quantitative real-time RT-PCR. The proteasome genes PSMC4 and PSMB5 and the E3 ubiquitin ligase NEDD4L were significantly and coherently upregulated in PCA cells compared with the corresponding adjacent normal prostate tissue. Transcription of the E3 ubiquitin ligase SMURF2 was significantly higher in organ-confined tumours (pT2) compared with non-organ-confined cancers (pT3). The results indicate a role for PSMC4 and PSMB5 and the E3 ubiquitin ligase NEDD4L in prostate tumourigenesis, whereas SMURF2 downregulation could be associated with clinical progression. NEDD4L and SMURF2 both target transforming growth factor (TGF)-β for degradation. This reflects the pleiotropic role of the TGF-β signalling pathway acting as a tumour suppressor in normal and pre-cancerous cells, but having oncogenic properties in progressing cancer. Further studies have to elucidate whether these alterations could represent clinically relevant PCA-diagnostic and progression markers.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Prostate cancer and prostatic diseases</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Transcription alterations of members of the ubiquitin-proteasome network in prostate carcinoma.</str>
    <str name="id">21102547</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Even after five decades of use, the mood stabilizer lithium continues to be the mainstay of treatment for bipolar disorder in many countries. The mechanism of action for lithium, however, remains unclear.</str>
      <str>In this study, microarray analysis was used to identify genes and cellular pathways that are altered in the mouse brain after treatment with lithium at human therapeutic concentrations. Mice received daily injections of lithium chloride for 7 consecutive days. Whole-brain total RNA was used as a template for microarray gene expression profiling.</str>
      <str>This study has identified 19 transcripts that are differentially expressed by four-fold when compared with control untreated mice. The altered expression of these genes was validated by quantitative PCR analysis with five genes showing significant differential expression. Lithium was found to significantly decrease the expression of metallothionein 3 (MT3), ATPase, Na/K transporting, alpha1 polypeptide (ATP1A1), transcription elongation factor B (SIII)-polypeptide 2 (TCEB2), proteasome subunit beta type 5 (PSMB5), and guanine nucleotide binding protein beta1 (GNB1).</str>
      <str>These genes are involved in a diverse range of biological functions, including maintaining metal ion homeostasis and chemical/electrical gradients across membranes, regulating RNA polymerase II, protein degradation, and G-protein-coupled signal transduction. These results indicate that lithium can regulate a large number of different cellular pathways in the brain. Understanding the molecular and cellular mechanisms by which lithium achieves its therapeutic action represents a valuable step in clarifying the pathophysiology of bipolar disorder.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Psychiatric genetics</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Microarray gene expression profiling of mouse brain mRNA in a model of lithium treatment.</str>
    <str name="id">18349697</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Decreases in the 26S proteasome are related to the toxicities of abnormal protein aggregates and may contribute to pathogenesis of degenerative diseases. Therefore, maintenance of proteasome function can be a novel strategy to protect cells against abnormal protein-mediated toxicity. In the present study, we have demonstrated the tissue specific increase of the catalytic subunits of the proteasome in mice following oral administration of 3H-1,2-dithiole-3-thione (D3T, 0.5 mmol/kg), which functions as a cancer preventive agent in animal and human studies. Expression of the 20S catalytic core subunits PSMB5, PSMB6, and PSMB7 were increased in liver, lung, small intestine, and colon of mice at 24 h after D3T treatment. Elevated expression of proteasome catalytic subunits led to increases in proteasomal peptidase activities in these tissues. Oral administration of D3T also exerted a pharmacodynamic action in some brain regions of these mice and proteasomal peptidase activities were significantly elevated in the cerebral cortex-hippocampus. Moreover, tissue extracts from D3T-treated mice and cell lysates obtained from D3T-incubated murine neuroblastoma cells exhibited the enhanced capacity to degrade mutant human SOD1G93A protein. These results indicate that the catalytic subunits of the 26S proteasome are inducible in multiple tissues of mouse including brain by exogenous chemical treatment. Increased proteasome expression by inducers may have a role in protection/attenuation of protein aggregate-mediated disorders.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Life sciences</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Tissue specific increase of the catalytic subunits of the 26S proteasome by indirect antioxidant dithiolethione in mice: enhanced activity for degradation of abnormal protein.</str>
    <str name="id">17521679</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The proteasome is a multi-subunit proteolytic complex that plays a central role in protein degradation in all eukaryotic cells. It regulates many vital cellular processes therefore its dysfunction can lead to various pathologies including cancer and neurodegeneration. Isolation of enzymatically active proteasomes is a key step to the successful study of the proteasome regulation and functions. Here we describe a simple and efficient protocol for immunoaffinity purification of the functional 20S proteasomes from human HEK 293T cells after transient overexpression of specific proteasome subunits tagged with 3xFLAG. To construct 3xFLAG-fusion proteins, DNA sequences encoding the 20S proteasome subunits PSMB5, PSMA5, and PSMA3 were cloned into mammalian expression vector pIRES-hrGFP-1a. The corresponding recombinant proteins PSMB5-3xFLAG, PSMA5-3xFLAG, or PSMA3-3xFLAG were transiently overexpressed in human HEK 293T cells and were shown to be partially incorporated into the intact proteasome complexes. 20S proteasomes were immunoprecipitated from HEK 293T cell extracts under mild conditions using antibodies against FLAG peptide. Isolation of highly purified 20S proteasomes were confirmed by SDS-PAGE and Western blotting using antibodies against different proteasome subunits. Affinity purified 20S proteasomes were shown to possess chymotrypsin- and trypsin-like peptidase activities confirming their functionality. This simple single-step affinity method of the 20S proteasome purification can be instrumental to subsequent functional studies of proteasomes in human cells. </str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Protein expression and purification</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Immunoaffinity purification of the functional 20S proteasome from human cells via transient overexpression of specific proteasome subunits.</str>
    <str name="id">24583181</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>PR-924 is a novel prototypic immunoproteasome inhibitor bearing markedly enhanced specificity for the β5i immunoproteasome subunit, compared to the classical proteasome inhibitor bortezomib. Here, we assessed the growth inhibitory potential of PR-924 in three human hematologic malignancy cell lines (CCRF-CEM, THP1, and 8226) and their bortezomib-resistant sublines. Parental cells displayed equal sensitivity to PR-924 (IC₅₀: 1.5-2.8 μM), whereas their bortezomib-resistant tumor lines displayed a 10-12 fold cross-resistance to PR-924. However, PR-924 cross-resistance factors for bortezomib-resistant sublines were markedly lower compared to the resistance factors to bortezomib. Proteasome inhibition experiments confirmed that PR-924 specifically inhibited β5i activity, even far below concentrations that exerted anti-proliferative activity. We further determined whether PR-924 activity might be compromised by acquisition of drug resistance phenomena. Indeed, CEM cells rendered stepwise resistant to 20 μM PR-924 (CEM/PR20) displayed 13-fold PR-924-resistance and 10-fold cross-resistance to bortezomib. CEM/PR20 cells were devoid of mutations in the PSMB8 gene (encoding β5i), but acquired Met45Ile mutation in the PSMB5 gene (encoding constitutive β5), consistent with β5 mutations observed in bortezomib-resistant cells. Furthermore, compared to parental CEM cells, CEM/PR20 cells exhibited 2.5-fold upregulation of constitutive proteasome subunit expression, whereas immunoproteasome subunit expression was 2-fold decreased. In conclusion, PR-924 displayed potent anti-leukemic activity including toward bortezomib-resistant leukemia cells. Despite the specificity of PR-924 to the β5i immunoproteasome subunit, its anti-leukemic effect required concentrations that blocked both β5 and β5i subunits. This is underscored by the emergence of mutations in PSMB5 rather than in PSMB8.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Biochemical pharmacology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Anti-leukemic activity and mechanisms underlying resistance to the novel immunoproteasome inhibitor PR-924.</str>
    <str name="id">24552657</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Reproductive biotechnologies such as in vitro fertilization (IVF) and somatic cell nuclear transfer (SCNT) enable improved reproductive efficiency of animals. However, the birth rate of in vitro-derived embryos still lags behind that of their in vivo counterparts. Thus, it is critical to develop an accurate evaluation and prediction system of embryo competence, both for commercial purposes and for scientific research. Previous works have demonstrated that in vitro culture systems induce alterations in the relative abundance (RA) of diverse transcripts and thus compromise embryo quality. The aim of this work was to analyze the RA of a set of genes involved in cellular stress (heat shock protein 70-kDa, HSP70), endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress (immunoglobulin heavy chain binding protein, Bip; proteasome subunit β5, PSMB5) and apoptosis (BCL-2 associated X protein, Bax; cysteine aspartate protease-3, Caspase-3) in bovine blastocysts produced by IVF or SCNT and compare it with that of their in vivo counterparts. Poly (A) + mRNA was isolated from three pools of 10 blastocysts per treatment and analyzed by real-time RT-PCR. The RA of three of the stress indicators analyzed (Bax, PSMB5 and Bip) was significantly increased in SCNT embryos as compared with that of in vivo-derived blastocysts. No significant differences were found in the RA of HSP70 and Caspase-3 gene transcripts. This study could potentially complement morphological analyses in the development of an effective and accurate technique for the diagnosis of embryo quality, ultimately aiding to improve the efficiency of assisted reproductive techniques (ART). </str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">PloS one</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Expression profile of genes as indicators of developmental competence and quality of in vitro fertilization and somatic cell nuclear transfer bovine embryos.</str>
    <str name="id">25269019</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The ubiquitin-proteasome system plays a central role in protein quality control through endoplasmic reticulum (ER)-associated degradation (ERAD) of unfolded and misfolded proteins. NF-E2-related factor 2 (Nrf2) is a transcription factor that controls the expression of an array of phase II detoxification and antioxidant genes. Nrf2 signaling has additionally been shown to upregulate the expression of the proteasome catalytic subunits in several cell types. Here, we investigated the role of Nrf2 in tunicamycin-induced ER stress using a murine insulinoma β-cell line, βTC-6. shRNA-mediated silencing of Nrf2 expression in βTC-6 cells significantly increased tunicamycin-induced cytotoxicity, elevated the expression of the pro-apoptotic ER stress marker Chop10, and inhibited tunicamycin-inducible expression of the proteasomal catalytic subunits Psmb5 and Psmb6. The effects of 3H-1,2-dithiole-3-thione (D3T), a small molecule Nrf2 activator, on ER stress were also examined in βTC-6 cells. D3T pretreatment reduced tunicamycin cytotoxicity and attenuated the tunicamycin-inducible Chop10 and protein kinase RNA-activated-like ER kinase (Perk). The protective effect of D3T was shown to be associated with increased ERAD. D3T increased the expression of Psmb5 and Psmb6 and elevated chymotrypsin-like peptidase activity; proteasome inhibitor treatment blocked D3T effects on tunicamycin cytotoxicity and ER stress marker changes. Similarly, silencing of Nrf2 abolished the protective effect of D3T against ER stress. These results indicate that the Nrf2 pathway contributes to the ER stress response in pancreatic β-cells by enhancing proteasome-mediated ERAD.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Toxicology and applied pharmacology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Involvement of the Nrf2-proteasome pathway in the endoplasmic reticulum stress response in pancreatic β-cells.</str>
    <str name="id">22959925</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Optineurin is a gene associated with normal tension glaucoma and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. It has been reported previously that in cultured RGC5 cells, the turnover of endogenous optineurin involves mainly the ubiquitin-proteasome pathway (UPP). When optineurin is upregulated or mutated, the UPP function is compromised as evidenced by a decreased proteasome β5 subunit (PSMB5) level and autophagy is induced for clearance of the optineurin protein.</str>
      <str>Adeno-associated type 2 viral (AAV2) vectors for green fluorescence protein (GFP) only, GFP-tagged wild-type and Glu50Lys (E50K) mutated optineurin were intravitreally injected into rats for expression in retinal ganglion cells (RGCs). Following intravitreal injections, eyes that received optineurin vectors exhibited retinal thinning, as well as RGC and axonal loss compared to GFP controls. By immunostaining and Western blotting, the level of PSMB5 and autophagic substrate degradation marker p62 was reduced, and the level of autophagic marker microtubule associated protein 1 light chain 3 (LC3) was enhanced. The UPP impairment and autophagy induction evidently occurred in vivo as in vitro. The optineurin level, RGC and axonal counts, and apoptosis in AAV2-E50K-GFP-injected rat eyes were averted to closer to normal limits after treatment with rapamycin, an autophagic enhancer.</str>
      <str>The UPP function was reduced and autophagy was induced when wild-type and E50K optineurin was overexpressed in rat eyes. This study validates the in vitro findings, confirming that UPP impairment and autophagy induction also occur in vivo. In addition, rapamycin is demonstrated to clear the accumulated mutant optineurin. This agent may potentially be useful for rescuing of the adverse optineurin phenotypes in vivo.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">BMC cell biology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Induction of autophagy in rats upon overexpression of wild-type and mutant optineurin gene.</str>
    <str name="id">25943884</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Myocilin (MYOC) is a gene linked directly to juvenile- and adult-onset open angle glaucoma. Mutations including Pro370Leu (P370L) and Gln368stop (Q368X) have been identified in patients. In the present study, we investigated the processing of myocilin in human trabecular meshwork (TM) cells as well as in inducible, stable RGC5 cell lines.</str>
      <str>The turnover and photoactivation experiments revealed that the endogenous myocilin in human trabecular meshwork (TM) cells was a short-lived protein. It was found that the endogenous myocilin level in TM cells was increased by treatment of lysosomal and proteasomal inhibitors, but not by autophagic inhibitor. Multiple bands immunoreactive to anti-ubiquitin were seen in the myocilin pull down, indicating that myocilin was ubiquitinated. In inducible cell lines, the turnover rate of overexpressed wild-type and mutant P370L and Q368X myocilin-GFP fusion proteins was much prolonged. The proteasome function was compromised and autophagy was induced. A decreased PSMB5 level and an increased level of autophagic marker, LC3, were demonstrated.</str>
      <str>The current study provided evidence that in normal homeostatic situation, the turnover of endogenous myocilin involves ubiquitin-proteasome and lysosomal pathways. When myocilin was upregulated or mutated, the ubiquitin-proteasome function is compromised and autophagy is induced. Knowledge of the degradation pathways acting on myocilin can help in design of novel therapeutic strategies for myocilin-related glaucoma.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">PloS one</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Cellular processing of myocilin.</str>
    <str name="id">24732711</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The molecular target(s) cooperating with proteasome inhibition in multiple myeloma (MM) remain unknown. We therefore measured proliferation in MM cells transfected with 13 984 small interfering RNAs in the absence or presence of increasing concentrations of bortezomib. We identified 37 genes, which when silenced, are not directly cytotoxic but do synergistically potentiate the growth inhibitory effects of bortezomib. To focus on bortezomib sensitizers, genes that also sensitized MM to melphalan were excluded. When suppressed, the strongest bortezomib sensitizers were the proteasome subunits PSMA5, PSMB2, PSMB3, and PSMB7 providing internal validation, but others included BAZ1B, CDK5, CDC42SE2, MDM4, NME7, RAB8B, TFE3, TNFAIP3, TNK1, TOP1, VAMP2, and YY1. The strongest hit CDK5 also featured prominently in pathway analysis of primary screen data. Cyclin-dependent kinase 5 (CDK5) is expressed at high levels in MM and neural tissues with relatively low expression in other organs. Viral shRNA knockdown of CDK5 consistently sensitized 5 genetically variable MM cell lines to proteasome inhibitors (bortezomib and carfilzomib). Small-molecule CDK5 inhibitors were demonstrated to synergize with bortezomib to induce cytotoxicity of primary myeloma cells and myeloma cell lines. CDK5 regulation of proteasome subunit PSMB5 was identified as a probable route to sensitization.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Blood</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">RNAi screen of the druggable genome identifies modulators of proteasome inhibitor sensitivity in myeloma including CDK5.</str>
    <str name="id">21289309</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The 26S proteasome plays a major role in degradation of abnormal proteins within the cell. The indirect antioxidant including sulforaphane (SFN) protects cells from oxidative damage by increasing the expression of Nrf2-target genes. It has been observed that the expression of multiple subunits of the proteasome was up-regulated by indirect antioxidants through the Nrf2 pathway. In the current study, the role of SFN in amyloid beta(1-42) (Abeta(1-42))-induced cytotoxicity has been investigated in murine neuroblastoma cells. Treatment with SFN protected cells from Abeta(1-42)-mediated cell death in Neuro2A and N1E 115 cells. Inhibition of proteasome activities by MG132 could abolish the protective effect of SFN against Abeta(1-42). Neuro2A cells, which were stably overexpressing the catalytic subunit of the proteasome PSMB5, showed an elevated resistance toward Abeta(1-42) toxicity compared to control cells. Furthermore, the in vitro assay demonstrated that the Abeta(1-42) peptide is degraded by the proteasome fraction. These results suggest that proteasome-inducing indirect antioxidants may facilitate the removal of the Abeta(1-42) peptide and lead to the amelioration of abnormal protein-associated etiologies.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Archives of pharmacal research</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Protection against amyloid beta cytotoxicity by sulforaphane: role of the proteasome.</str>
    <str name="id">19183883</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>We have previously shown that overexpression of RASSF1A inhibits the growth of human gastric cancer SGC7901 cells, but the underlying mechanism remains unknown. In this study, the differential protein expression by RASSF1A gene in human gastric cancer cell line SGC7901 was determined by 2-D gel electrophoresis combined with matrix-assisted laser desorption/ionization-time of flight mass spectrometry (MALDI-TOF MS) and bioinformatics. Differential expression analysis of the protein profiles by RASSF1A gene identified a total of 35 protein spots, of which 10 were up-regulated and 25 were down-regulated. Eight proteins were identified by MALDI-TOF MS: Galectin-1, TRP-14, ACBP, PSMB5, PSMB4, TIM, vimentin, CD79α. RASSF1A up-regulated the mRNA expression of Galectin-1, TRP-14, ABCP in SGC7901. RASSF1A also led to an increased expression of Galectin-1 protein in SGC7901 confirmed by western blotting and immunocytochemistry analysis. RASSF1A inhibited the activity of NF-κB in SGC7901 cells. These data indicated that Galectin-1 may be playing a role in RASSF1A signaling in SGC7901.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">APMIS : acta pathologica, microbiologica, et immunologica Scandinavica</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Galectin-1 is up-regulated by RASSF1A gene in human gastric carcinoma cell line SGC7901.</str>
    <str name="id">22716213</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Proteasomes catalyze the non-lysosomal, ATP-dependent selective breakdown of ubiquitinated proteins and are thought to be responsible for MHC class I-restricted antigen presentation. Recently, we reported that gamma interferon (IFN-gamma) induced not only marked synthesis of the MHC-encoded proteasome subunits LMP2 and LMP7, but also almost complete loss of two unidentified proteasome subunits tentatively designated as X and Y in various human cells. Here, we show that subunit X is a new proteasomal subunit highly homologous to LMP7, and that subunit Y is identical to the LMP2-related proteasomal subunit delta. Thus, IFN-gamma appears to induce subunit replacements of X and Y by LMP7 and LMP2, respectively, producing 'immuno-proteasomes' with the functional diversity responsible for processing of endogenous antigens.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">FEBS letters</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Replacement of proteasome subunits X and Y by LMP7 and LMP2 induced by interferon-gamma for acquirement of the functional diversity responsible for antigen processing.</str>
    <str name="id">8163024</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The mechanisms involved in the progressive malfunction of the trabecular meshwork (TM) in glaucoma are not yet understood. To study age-related changes in human TM cells, we isolated primary TM cell cultures from young (ages 9, 14, and 25) and old (ages 66, 70, and 73) donors, and compared levels of oxidized proteins, autofluorescence, proteasome function, and markers for cellular senescence. TM cells from old donors showed a 3-fold increase in oxidized proteins and a 7.5-fold decrease of proteasome activity. Loss of proteasome function was not associated with decreased proteasome content but with partial replacement of the proteolytic subunit PSMB5 with the inducible subunit LMP7. Cells from old donors also demonstrated features characteristic of cellular senescence associated with phosphorylation of p38MAPK but only a modest increase in p53. These data suggest that age-related proteasome inhibition and cellular senescence could contribute to the pathophysiological alterations of the TM in glaucoma.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Biochemical and biophysical research communications</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Effects of donor age on proteasome activity and senescence in trabecular meshwork cells.</str>
    <str name="id">15381105</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Human bone marrow stromal cells (hBMSCs) could be used in clinics as precursors of multiple cell lineages following proper induction. Such application is impeded by their characteristically short lifespan, together with the increasing loss of proliferation capability and progressive reduction of differentiation potential after the prolonged culture expansion. In the current study, we addressed the possible role of 20S proteasomes in this process. Consistent with prior reports, long-term in vitro expansion of hBMSCs decreased cell proliferation and increased replicative senescence, accompanied by reduced activity and expression of the catalytic subunits PSMB5 and PSMB1, and the 20S proteasome overall. Application of the proteasome inhibitor MG132 produced a senescence-like phenotype in early passages, whereas treating late-passage cells with 18α-glycyrrhetinic acid (18α-GA), an agonist of 20S proteasomes, delayed the senescence progress, enhancing the proliferation and recovering the capability of differentiation. The data demonstrate that activation of 20S proteasomes assists in counteracting replicative senescence of hBMSCs expanded in vitro.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Biochemical and biophysical research communications</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Potential role of 20S proteasome in maintaining stem cell integrity of human bone marrow stromal cells in prolonged culture expansion.</str>
    <str name="id">22564728</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Nuclear factor, erythroid 2 related factor 2 (Nrf2) belongs to the Cap'n'collar/basic region leucine zipper (CNC-bZIP) transcription factor family, and is activated by diverse oxidants, pro-oxidants, antioxidants, and chemopreventive agents. After phosphorylation and dissociation from the cytoplasmic inhibitor, Kelch-like ECH-associated protein 1 (Keap1), Nrf2 translocates to the nucleus and binds to an antioxidant response element (ARE). Through transcriptional induction of ARE-bearing genes that encode antioxidant-detoxifying proteins, Nrf2 activates cellular rescue pathways against oxidative injury, inflammation/immunity, apoptosis, and carcinogenesis. ARE-driven genes include direct antioxidants (e.g., GPx), thiol metabolism-associated detoxifying enzymes (e.g., GSTs), stress-response genes (e.g., HO-1), and others (e.g., PSMB5). Application of nrf2 germ-line mutant mice elucidated protective roles for Nrf2 in various models of human disorders in the liver, lung, kidney, brain, and circulation. In the lung, deficiency of nrf2 augmented injury caused by bleomycin and environmental oxidants including hyperoxia, diesel exhaust particles, and cigarette smoke. Microarray analyses of lungs from nrf2-deficient and -sufficient mice identified Nrf2-dependent genes that might be critical in pulmonary protection. Observations from these studies highlight the importance of the Nrf2-antioxidant pathway and may provide new therapeutic strategies for acute respiratory distress syndrome, idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis, cancer, and emphysema in which oxidative stress is implicated.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Antioxidants &amp; redox signaling</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Nrf2 defends the lung from oxidative stress.</str>
    <str name="id">16487040</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Eukaryotes have two major intracellular protein degradation pathways, namely the ubiquitin-proteasome system (UPS) and autophagy. Inhibition of proteasomal activities has been previously shown to induce autophagy, indicating a coordinated and complementary relationship between these two systems. However, little is known about the regulation of the UPS by autophagy. In this study, we showed for the first time that proteasomes were activated in response to pharmacological inhibition of autophagy as well as disruption of autophagy-related genes by RNA interference under nutrient-deficient conditions in cultured human colon cancer cells. The induction was evidenced by the increased proteasomal activities and the upregulation of proteasomal subunits, including the proteasome β5 subunit, PSMB5. Co-inhibition of the proteasome and autophagy also synergistically increased the accumulation of polyubiquitinated proteins. Collectively, our findings suggest that proteasomes are activated in a compensatory manner for protein degradation upon autophagy inhibition. Our studies unveiled a novel regulatory mechanism between the two protein degradation pathways. </str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Autophagy</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">A novel crosstalk between two major protein degradation systems: regulation of proteasomal activity by autophagy.</str>
    <str name="id">23934082</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Immunohistochemical analyses of archival tumor specimens were used for pre-planned exploratory analyses of protocol-specified candidate biomarkers of bortezomib activity in 73 patients with relapsed/refractory mantle cell lymphoma in the phase 2 PINNACLE study. Consistent with other studies, elevated Ki-67 was a marker of poor prognosis, demonstrating significant associations with shorter time to progression and overall survival. Elevated NF-kappaB p65 and low PSMA5 expression demonstrated a trend for better response and were significantly associated with longer time to progression; elevated NF-kappaB p65 demonstrated a trend toward longer overall survival. This is consistent with myeloma clinical genomics research, suggesting biomarker relevance across tumor types. Elevated p27 was significantly associated with longer overall survival. Overall survival analyses by International Prognostic Index and Mantle Cell Lymphoma International Prognostic Index confirmed differential prognosis by both scores. These biomarkers data begin to illuminate bortezomib's mechanism of action in lymphoma.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Leukemia &amp; lymphoma</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Potential biomarkers of bortezomib activity in mantle cell lymphoma from the phase 2 PINNACLE trial.</str>
    <str name="id">20572799</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Proteasomes are the proteolytic complex responsible for major histocompatibility complex (MHC) class I-restricted antigen presentation. Interferon gamma treatment increases expression MHC-encoded LMP2 and LMP7 subunits of the proteasome and decreases expression of two proteasome subunits, named X and Y, which alters the proteolytic specificity of proteasomes. Molecular cloning of complementary DNAs encoding X and Y showed that their proteins are proteasomal subunits with high amino acid similarity to LMP7 and LMP2, respectively. Thus, interferon gamma may induce subunit replacements of X and Y by LMP7 and LMP2, respectively, producing proteasomes perhaps more appropriate for the immunological processing of endogenous antigens.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Science (New York, N.Y.)</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">cDNA cloning and interferon gamma down-regulation of proteasomal subunits X and Y.</str>
    <str name="id">8066462</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Stability of proteins is largely controlled by post-translational covalent modifications. Among those, ubiquitylation plays a central role as it marks the proteins for proteasome-dependent degradation. Proteolytic activities of proteasomes are critical for execution of various cellular processes, including DNA damage signaling and repair. However, very little is known about the regulation of proteasomal activity in cells during genotoxic stress. Here we investigated post-translational modifications of the 20S proteasomal subunits upon DNA damage induced by doxorubicin. Using mass-spectrometry, we found novel sites of phosphorylation and ubiquitylation in multiple proteasome subunits upon doxorubicin treatment. Ectopic co-expression of proteasome subunits and tagged ubiquitin confirmed the presence of ubiquitylated forms of PSMA5, PSMA1, PSMA3 and PSMB5 in cells. Moreover, we demonstrated that ubiquitylation in vitro inhibited chymotrypsin-like and caspase-like activities of proteasomes. In vivo, doxorubicin increased the activity of proteasomes, paralleling with attenuation of the overall level of proteasome ubiquitylation. Collectively, our results suggest a novel mechanism whereby the proteolytic activities of proteasomes are dynamically regulated by ubiquitylation upon DNA damage. </str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Oncotarget</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">DNA damage-induced ubiquitylation of proteasome controls its proteolytic activity.</str>
    <str name="id">23907514</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Large multisubunit proteasomal complexes, catalyzing an extralysosomal, ATP-dependent pathway for selective degradation of unnecessary proteins, are thought to be responsible for major histocompatibility complex (MHC) class I-restricted antigen presentation. Two proteasomal polymorphic genes, LMP2 and LMP7, are localized within the MHC class II region, closely linked to the TAP1 and TAP2 genes that are responsible for the ATP-dependent, size- and sequence-selective transport of antigenic peptides generated in the cytoplasm into the endoplasmic reticulum. Interferon-gamma (IFN-gamma) alters the peptide-degrading specificity of proteasomes and appears to produce an immunoproteasome responsible for accelerated processing of nonself endogenous antigens by inducing the replacement of subunits X and Y by LMP7 and LMP2, respectively. This IFN-gamma-induced change in the subunits of proteasomes by IFN-gamma is a new mechanism for an immunomodulatory action, differing from that for marked increases of TAP transporter and MHC molecules, which are possibly due to changes in transcriptional levels in cells. Based on these findings, I propose alteration of the subunit assembly of proteasomes in response to extracellular stimuli as a novel mechanism for the acquisition of their functional diversity that plays a central role in the immune response.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Journal of leukocyte biology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Role of proteasomes modified by interferon-gamma in antigen processing.</str>
    <str name="id">7964165</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Bortezomib is a proteasome inhibitor important to the therapy of multiple myeloma (MM), though a number of patients show resistance to this drug. To study the cellular basis of this resistance we have generated a MM cell line displaying enhanced (5-6-fold) resistance to bortezomib by serial cultivation of RPMI 8226 cells with increasing concentrations of this drug. Bortezomib-resistant cells (8226/7B) became bigger in size than parental cells and nearly doubled the amount of DNA per cell, evolving from hypotriploidy to near-tetraploidy. 8226/7B displayed lowered Noxa accumulation and reduced caspase-3 activation in response to bortezomib. Resistant 8226/7B cells overexpressed the PSMβ5 proteasome subunit, the molecular target of bortezomib, both at the mRNA and protein level. No mutations were detected in the PSMβ5 gene. Bortezomib-resistant cells were roughly as sensitive as parental cells to other chemotherapeutic drugs, including doxorubicin, melphalan, vincristine, BMS-214662 and BMS-345541. 8226/7B cells showed partial and high cross-resistance to the proteasome inhibitors epoxomicin and MG-132, respectively. Co-treatment with the histone deacetylase inhibitor trichostatin A (TSA) potentiated bortezomib-induced apoptosis in parental RPMI 8226 cells but did not revert bortezomib resistance in 8226/7B cells. Therefore, treatment of bortezomib-refractory myeloma with drugs targeting molecular structures other than proteasome seems to be the more suitable therapeutic strategy to overcome bortezomib resistance.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Leukemia research</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Bortezomib resistance in a myeloma cell line is associated to PSMβ5 overexpression and polyploidy.</str>
    <str name="id">21978467</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>A single heat shock factor (HSF), mediating the heat shock response, exists from yeast to Drosophila, whereas several related HSFs have been found in mammals. This raises the question of the specific or redundant functions of the different members of the HSF family and in particular of HSF1 and HSF2, which are both ubiquitously expressed. Using immortalized mouse embryonic fibroblasts (iMEFs) derived from wild-type, Hsf1(-/-), Hsf2(-/-) or double-mutant mice, we observed the distinctive behaviors of these mutants with respect to proteasome inhibition. This proteotoxic stress reduces to the same extent the viability of Hsf1(-/-)- and Hsf2(-/-)-deficient cells, but through different underlying mechanisms. Contrary to Hsf2(-/-) cells, Hsf1(-/-) cells are unable to induce pro-survival heat shock protein expression. Conversely, proteasome activity is lower in Hsf2(-/-) cells and the expression of some proteasome subunits, such as Psmb5 and gankyrin, is decreased. As gankyrin is an oncoprotein involved in p53 degradation, we analyzed the status of p53 in HSF-deficient iMEFs and observed that it was strongly stabilized in Hsf2(-/-) cells. This study points a new role for HSF2 in the regulation of protein degradation and suggests that pan-HSF inhibitors could be valuable tools to reduce chemoresistance to proteasome inhibition observed in cancer therapy.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Oncogene</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Roles of heat shock factor 1 and 2 in response to proteasome inhibition: consequence on p53 stability.</str>
    <str name="id">20498630</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Theophylline (THP) and 1,3-dinitrobenzene (DNB) are thought to induce infertility by incapacitating the nurturing Sertoli cells and causing germ cell apoptosis in the testicular seminiferous epithelium, respectively. We hypothesized that THP and DNB exposure would alter the expression of the genes within the ubiquitin-proteasome pathway (UPP), implicated in spermatogenesis and epididymal sperm quality control. Rats were fed 0 or 8000 ppm of THP and necropsied on Days 18, 30, and 42 or administered 0, 2, or 6 mg/kg DNB via oral gavage and necropsied on Day 7. Tissues were collected from the testis and the caput, corpus, and cauda regions of the epididymis for transcriptional profiling by semiquantitative RT-PCR, real-time RT-PCR, and histopathology. Target UPP genes included those encoding for constitutive the 20S proteasomal core subunits Psmb1 (beta1), Psmb2 (beta2), and Psmb5 (beta5); the inducible 20S core subunits Psmb9 (LMP2), Psmb8 (LMP7), and Psmb10 (LMP10); and Ube1 (ubiquitin-activating enzyme E1), Ube2d3 (ubiquitin-conjugating enzyme E2), and Uchl1 (ubiquitin C-terminal hydrolase PGP9.5). Spermatozoa were collected from the cauda epididymis for analysis by light microscopy and flow cytometric evaluation of sperm surface ubiquitin. These data show that reprotoxic exposure alters the tissue-specific expression of UPP genes in the testis and epididymis, which may contribute to the aberrant spermatogenesis and epididymal processing of both normal and defective spermatozoa. Transcriptional profiling and flow cytometric analysis of the UPP thus captures the prodromal effects of reproductive toxicity not captured by conventional histology and functional cytology. Complementing seminal analysis with these measures may be useful in screening drug-induced toxicity or environmental infertility.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Biology of reproduction</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Differential expression of genes encoding constitutive and inducible 20S proteasomal core subunits in the testis and epididymis of theophylline- or 1,3-dinitrobenzene-exposed rats.</str>
    <str name="id">16988215</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Genomic clones were obtained for the genes encoding the beta subunits of the human proteasome and for the associated proteasome activators PA28alpha and beta (PSME1 and PSME2, respectively). Fluorescence in situ hybridization was used to map the gene encoding the beta subunit PSMB3 (beta3 hs, HsC10-II) to chromosome band 2q35, PSMB2 (beta4 hs, HsC7-I) to band 1p34.2, and PSMB4 (beta7 hs, HSBpros 26) to band 1q21. Genes encoding the alpha and beta subunits of the PA28 complex were found closely linked on chromosome band 14q11.2, within 1 Mb of the beta proteasome locus PSMB5 (beta5 hs, MB1, X). These data complete the mapping of the human proteasome beta subunit loci. With the exception of the genes encoding the PSMB9 and PSMB8 (LMP2 and LMP7, respectively) subunits, the beta genes were not closely linked in the human genome. Both PSMB2 and PSMB4 mapped to a region of chromosome 1 that is proposed to be paralogous to other regions of the human genome where beta proteasome genes map: chromosome 6 containing the major histocompatibility complex (MHC) and chromosome 9. The independent regulation of expression of all of these genes, implied by this study, is consistent with a key role for proteasome assembly in coordination of the complex.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Genomics</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Genetic relationships of the genes encoding the human proteasome beta subunits and the proteasome PA28 complex.</str>
    <str name="id">9344661</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The gastrointestinal trefoil factor family (TFF1, TFF2, TFF3) peptides are considered to play an important role in maintaining the integrity of the mucosa. The physiological role of TFF2 in the protection of the GI tract was investigated in TFF2 deficiency.</str>
      <str>TFF2-/- mice were generated and differential expression of various genes was assessed by using a mouse expression microarray, quantitative real time PCR, Northern blots or immunohistochemistry.</str>
      <str>On an mRNA level we found 128 differentially expressed genes. We observed modulation of a number of crucial genes involved in innate and adaptive immunity in the TFF2-/- mice. Expression of proteasomal subunits genes (LMP2, LMP7 and PSMB5) involved in the MHC class I presentation pathway were modulated indicating the formation of immunoproteasomes improving antigen presentation. Expression of one subunit of a transporter (TAP1) responsible for importing degraded antigens into ER was increased, similarly to the BAG2 gene that modulates chaperone activity in ER helping proper loading on MHC class I molecules. Several mouse defensin (cryptdin) genes coding important intestinal microbicidal proteins were up-regulated as a consequence of TFF2 deficiency. Normally moderate expression of TFF3 was highly increased in stomach.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Cellular physiology and biochemistry : international journal of experimental cellular physiology, biochemistry, and pharmacology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Trefoil factor 2 (TFF2) deficiency in murine digestive tract influences the immune system.</str>
    <str name="id">16121031</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>New evidence indicates the involvement of protein degradation dysfunctions in neurodegeneration, innate immunity response and alcohol hepatotoxicity. We recently demonstrated that ethanol increases brain proinflammatory mediators and causes brain damage by activating Toll-like receptor 4 (TLR4) signaling in glia. However, it is uncertain if the ubiquitin-proteasome and autophagy-lysosome pathways are involved in ethanol-induced brain damage and whether the TLR4 response is implicated in proteolytic processes. Using the cerebral cortex of WT and TLR4-knockout mice with and without chronic ethanol treatment, we demonstrate that ethanol induces poly-ubiquitinated proteins accumulation and promotes immunoproteasome activation by inducing the expression of β2i, β5i and PA28α, although it decreases the 20S constitutive proteasome subunits (α2, β5). Ethanol also upregulates mTOR phosphorylation, leading to a downregulation of the autophagy-lysosome pathway (ATG12, ATG5, cathepsin B, p62, LC3) and alters the volume of autophagic vacuoles. Notably, mice lacking TLR4 receptors are protected against ethanol-induced alterations in protein degradation pathways. In summary, the present results provide the first evidence demonstrating that chronic ethanol treatment causes proteolysis dysfunctions in the mouse cerebral cortex and that these events are TLR4 dependent. These findings could provide insight into the mechanisms underlying ethanol-induced brain damage. </str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Cell death &amp; disease</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">TLR4 mediates the impairment of ubiquitin-proteasome and autophagy-lysosome pathways induced by ethanol treatment in brain.</str>
    <str name="id">24556681</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Sequencing of zebrafish (Danio rerio) bacterial artificial chromosome and P1 artificial chromosome genomic clone fragments and of cDNA clones has led to the identification of five new loci coding for beta subunits of proteasomes (PSMB). Together with the four genes identified previously, nine PSMB genes have now been defined in the zebrafish. Six of the nine genes reside in the zebrafish MHC (Mhc) class I region, four of them reside in a single cluster closely associated with TAP2 on a 26-kb long genomic fragment, and two reside at some distance from the fragment. In addition to homologues of the human genes PSMB5 through PSMB9, two new genes, PSMB11 and PSMB12, have been found for which there are no known corresponding genes in humans. The new genes reside in the PSMB cluster in the Mhc. Homology and promoter region analysis suggest that the Mhc-associated genes might be inducible by IFN-gamma. The zebrafish class I region contains representatives of three phylogenetically distinguishable groups of PSMB genes, X, Y, and Z. It is proposed that these genes were present in the ancestral PSMB region before Mhc class I genes became associated with it.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Journal of immunology (Baltimore, Md. : 1950)</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Analysis of a 26-kb region linked to the Mhc in zebrafish: genomic organization of the proteasome component beta/transporter associated with antigen processing-2 gene cluster and identification of five new proteasome beta subunit genes.</str>
    <str name="id">10453006</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Nakajo-Nishimura syndrome (NNS) (MIM256040, ORPHA2615) is a distinct inherited inflammatory and wasting disease, which usually begins in early infancy with a pernio-like rash. The patients develop periodic high fever and nodular erythema-like eruptions, and gradually progress lipomuscular atrophy in the upper body, mainly the face and the upper extremities, to show the characteristic long clubbed fingers with joint contractures. So far about 30 cases have been reported from Kansai, especially Wakayama and Osaka, Tohoku and Kanto areas. In addition to 10 cases in Kansai area, which have been confirmed to be alive by national surveillance, an infant case has newly been discovered in Wakayama and more cases will be added. Although cause of the disease has long been undefined, a homozygous mutation of the PSMB8 gene, which encodes the β5i subunit of immunoproteasome, has been identified by homozygosity mapping. By analyses of the patients-derived cells and tissues, it has been suggested that accumulation of ubiquitinated and oxidated proteins due to deficiency of proteasome activities cause hyperactivation of p38 MAPK and overproduction of IL-6. Similar diseases with PSMB8 mutations have recently been reported from Europe and the U.S.A., and therefore, it is becoming clear that proteasome deficiency syndromes are globally distributed as a new category of the autoinflammatory diseases.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Nihon Rinshō Men'eki Gakkai kaishi = Japanese journal of clinical immunology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">[Nakajo-Nishimura syndrome].</str>
    <str name="id">22041427</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Proteasomal subunit PSMB4 was suggested to be a survival gene in an animal model of hepatocellular carcinoma and in glioblastoma cell lines. In pulmonary adenocarcinoma, a high expression of these genes was found to be associated with poor differentiation and survival. This study investigates the gene expression levels of 26S proteasome subunits in human pulmonary neuroendocrine tumours including typical (TC) and atypical (AC) carcinoid tumours as well as small cell (SCLC) and large cell (LCNEC) neuroendocrine carcinomas.</str>
      <str>Gene expression levels of proteasomal subunits (PSMA1, PSMA5, PSMB4, PSMB5 and PSMD1) were investigated in 80 neuroendocrine pulmonary tumours (each 20 TC, AC, LCNLC and SCLC) and compared to controls. mRNA levels were determined by using TaqMan assays. Immunohistochemistry on tissue microarrays (TMA) was performed to determine the expression of ki67, cleaved caspase 3 and PSMB4.</str>
      <str>All proteasomal subunit gene expressions were significantly upregulated in TC, AC, SCLC and LCNEC compared to controls. PSMB4 mRNA is differently expressed between all neuroendocrine tumour subtypes demonstrating the highest expression and greatest range in LCNEC (p=0.043), and is significantly associated with proliferative activity (p=0.039).</str>
      <str>In line with other 26S proteasomal subunits PSMB4 is significantly increased, but differently expressed between pulmonary neuroendocrine tumours and is associated with the proliferative activity. Unlike in pulmonary adenocarcinomas, no association with biological behaviour was observed, suggesting that increased proteasomal subunit gene expression is a common and probably early event in the tumorigenesis of pulmonary neuroendocrine tumours regardless of their differentiation.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Journal of Cancer</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Gene Expression Analysis of the 26S Proteasome Subunit PSMB4 Reveals Significant Upregulation, Different Expression and Association with Proliferation in Human Pulmonary Neuroendocrine Tumours.</str>
    <str name="id">25157275</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>In idiopathic inflammatory myopathies (IIM) infiltration of immune cells into muscle and upregulation of MHC-I expression implies increased antigen presentation and involvement of the proteasome system. To decipher the role of immunoproteasomes in myositis, we investigated individual cell types and muscle tissues and focused on possible immune triggers.</str>
      <str>Expression of constitutive (PSMB5, -6, -7) and corresponding immunoproteasomal subunits (PSMB8, -9, -10) was analyzed by real-time RT-PCR in muscle biopsies and sorted peripheral blood cells of patients with IIM, non-inflammatory myopathies (NIM) and healthy donors (HD). Protein analysis in muscle biopsies was performed by western blot. Affymetrix HG-U133 platform derived transcriptome data from biopsies of different muscle diseases and from immune cell types as well as monocyte stimulation experiments were used for validation, coregulation and coexpression analyses.</str>
      <str>Real-time RT-PCR revealed significantly increased expression of immunoproteasomal subunits (PSMB8/-9/-10) in DC, monocytes and CD8+ T-cells in IIM. In muscle biopsies, the immunosubunits were elevated in IIM compared to NIM and exceeded levels of matched blood samples. Proteins of PSMB8 and -9 were found only in IIM but not NIM muscle biopsies. Reanalysis of 78 myositis and 20 healthy muscle transcriptomes confirmed these results and revealed involvement of the antigen processing and presentation pathway. Comparison with reference profiles of sorted immune cells and healthy muscle confirmed upregulation of PSMB8 and -9 in myositis biopsies beyond infiltration related changes. This upregulation correlated highest with STAT1, IRF1 and IFNγ expression. Elevation of T-cell specific transcripts in active IIM muscles was accompanied by increased expression of DC and monocyte marker genes and thus reflects the cell type specific involvement observed in peripheral blood.</str>
      <str>Immunoproteasomes seem to indicate IIM activity and suggest that dominant involvement of antigen processing and presentation may qualify these diseases exemplarily for the evolving therapeutic concepts of immunoproteasome specific inhibition.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">PloS one</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Upregulation of immunoproteasome subunits in myositis indicates active inflammation with involvement of antigen presenting cells, CD8 T-cells and IFNΓ.</str>
    <str name="id">25098831</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str/>
      <str>In clinical and experimental settings, antibody-based anti-CD20/rituximab and small molecule proteasome inhibitor (PI) bortezomib (BTZ) treatment proved effective modalities for B cell depletion in lymphoproliferative disorders as well as autoimmune diseases. However, the chronic nature of these diseases requires either prolonged or re-treatment, often with acquired resistance as a consequence.</str>
      <str>Here we studied the molecular basis of acquired resistance to BTZ in JY human B lymphoblastic cells following prolonged exposure to this drug and examined possibilities to overcome resistance by next generation PIs and anti-CD20/rituximab-mediated complement-dependent cytotoxicity (CDC).</str>
      <str>Characterization of BTZ-resistant JY/BTZ cells compared to parental JY/WT cells revealed the following features: (a) 10-12 fold resistance to BTZ associated with the acquisition of a mutation in the PSMB5 gene (encoding the constitutive β5 proteasome subunit) introducing an amino acid substitution (Met45Ile) in the BTZ-binding pocket, (b) a significant 2-4 fold increase in the mRNA and protein levels of the constitutive β5 proteasome subunit along with unaltered immunoproteasome expression, (c) full sensitivity to the irreversible epoxyketone-based PIs carfilzomib and (to a lesser extent) the immunoproteasome inhibitor ONX 0914. Finally, in association with impaired ubiquitination and attenuated breakdown of CD20, JY/BTZ cells harbored a net 3-fold increase in CD20 cell surface expression, which was functionally implicated in conferring a significantly increased anti-CD20/rituximab-mediated CDC.</str>
      <str>These results demonstrate that acquired resistance to BTZ in B cells can be overcome by next generation PIs and by anti-CD20/rituximab-induced CDC, thereby paving the way for salvage therapy in BTZ-resistant disease.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Experimental hematology &amp; oncology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Overcoming bortezomib resistance in human B cells by anti-CD20/rituximab-mediated complement-dependent cytotoxicity and epoxyketone-based irreversible proteasome inhibitors.</str>
    <str name="id">23305345</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The aim of this study was to identify conceptus-derived proteins, in addition to IFNT, that may facilitate pregnancy recognition in cattle. Analysis of the protein content of the uterine luminal fluid (ULF) from cyclic heifers on Day 16 by nano liquid chromatography tandem mass spectrometry identified 334 proteins. Comparison of these data with 299 proteins identified in the ULF of pregnant heifers on Day 16 identified 85 proteins only present in the ULF of pregnant heifers. Analysis of Day 16 conceptus-conditioned culture medium revealed the presence of 1005 proteins of which 30 proteins were unique to ULF from Day 16 pregnant heifers. Of these 30 proteins, 12 had mRNA expression values at least 2-fold higher in abundance (P &lt; 0.05) in the conceptus compared to the endometrium (ARPC5L, CAPG, CKMT1, CSTB, HSPA8, HSPE1, LGALS3, MSN, NUTF2, P4HB, PRKAR2A, TKT) as determined by RNA sequencing. In addition, genes that have a significant biological interaction with the proteins (ACO2, CKMT1, CSTB, EEF2, GDI1, GLB1, GPLD1, HNRNPA1, HNRNPA2B1, HNRNPF, HSPA8, HSPE1, IDH2, KRT75, LGALS3, MSN, NUTF2, P4HB, PRKAR2A, PSMA4, PSMB5, PSMC4, SERPINA3, TKT) were differentially expressed in the endometrium of pregnant compared to cyclic heifers during the pregnancy recognition period (Days 16-18). These results indicate that 30 proteins unique to ULF from pregnant heifers and produced by short-term in vitro cultured Day 16 conceptuses could potentially be involved in facilitating the interactions between the conceptus and the endometrium during the pregnancy recognition period. </str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Biology of reproduction</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">'Conceptualizing' the Endometrium: Identification of Conceptus-Derived Proteins During Early Pregnancy in Cattle.</str>
    <str name="id">25947061</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Interferon (IFN) gamma induces replacements of the proteasomal subunits X and Y by LMP7 and LMP2, respectively, resulting in an alteration of the proteolytic specificity. We found a third pair of proteasome subunits expressed reciprocally in response to IFN-gamma. Molecular cloning of a cDNA encoding one subunit designated as Z, downregulated by IFN-gamma, showed that it is a novel proteasomal subunit with high homology to MECL1, which is markedly induced by IFN-gamma. Thus, IFN-gamma induces subunit replacements of not only X and Y by LMP7 and LMP2, respectively, but also of Z by MECL1, producing proteasomes responsible for immunological processing of endogenous antigens. When processed from their precursors, three pairs of the 10 homologous, but distinct, beta-type subunits of eukaryotic proteasomes, that is, X/LMP7, Y/LMP2, and Z/MECL1, have an NH2-terminal threonine residue, assumed to be part of a catalytic center. These findings suggest that the altered molecular organization of the proteasome induced by IFN-gamma may be responsible for acquisition of its functional change.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">The Journal of experimental medicine</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Newly identified pair of proteasomal subunits regulated reciprocally by interferon gamma.</str>
    <str name="id">8666937</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis and high performance liquid chromatography of multicatalytic proteinase complexes (MPC) isolated from bovine pituitary, lung, and liver showed marked differences in the pattern of subunits. The concentrations of LMP7 in the lung and liver were 10 and 5 times, respectively, greater than those in the pituitary, whereas the chymotrypsin-like activity and the amount of a subunit (BO2), necessary for its expression, were markedly decreased in the lung and moderately decreased in the liver. Lower trypsin-like, small neutral amino acid preferring, and peptidyl-glutamyl-peptide hydrolyzing activities were also found in the lung and liver. The activity of the branched chain amino acid preferring component (BrAAP), predominantly latent in the pituitary, was highly activated in the lung and liver, as evidenced by a greatly decreased Km and a 20-fold increase of the specificity constant Vmax/Km, indicating facilitated substrate access to its active site and increased affinity toward substrates with branched chain amino acids in the P1 position. It is suggested that overexpression of LMP7 in the lung is related to increased exposure of the airways to foreign antigens. The possible association between amounts of LMP7 and the activation of the BrAAP component needs further examination.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">The Journal of biological chemistry</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Differences in catalytic activities and subunit pattern of multicatalytic proteinase complexes (proteasomes) isolated from bovine pituitary, lung, and liver. Changes in LMP7 and the component necessary for expression of the chymotrypsin-like activity.</str>
    <str name="id">7673255</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Although oligonucleotide chips, cDNA microarrays, differential display reverse transcription-PCR, and other approaches have been used to screen implantation-related molecules, the mechanism by which embryo implantation occurs is still unknown. The aim of this study was to profile the differential gene expression between interimplantation site and implantation site in mouse uterus on day 5 of pregnancy by serial analysis of gene expression (SAGE). In our two SAGE libraries of 11-bp tags, the total numbers of tags sequenced were 48,121 for the interimplantation site and 50,227 for the implantation site. There were 1,039 tags specifically expressed at interimplantation site, and 1,252 tags specifically expressed at the implantation site. Based on the p value, there were 195 tags significantly up-regulated at the interimplantation site and 261 tags significantly up-regulated at the implantation site, of which 100 genes were single matched at the interimplantation site and 127 genes were single matched at the implantation site, respectively. By reverse transcription-PCR, the tag ratio between the implantation site and interimplantation site was verified on 14 significantly changed genes. Using in situ hybridization, 1810014L12Rik, Psmb5, Cd63, Npm1, Fads3, and Tagln2 were shown to be highly expressed at the implantation site compared with the interimplantation site. Compared with the interimplantation site, Ddx39 was strongly expressed in the subluminal stromal cells at the implantation site on day 5 of pregnancy. Ddx39 expression at the implantation site was specifically induced by active blastocysts. Additionally, Ddx39 expression was significantly up-regulated by estrogen in the ovariectomized mice. In our SAGE data, many implantation-related genes were identified in mouse uterus. Our data could be a valuable source for future study on embryo implantation.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">The Journal of biological chemistry</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Serial analysis of gene expression in mouse uterus at the implantation site.</str>
    <str name="id">16434403</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The ubiquitin-proteasome system facilitates the degradation of damaged proteins and regulators of growth and stress response. Alterations in this proteolytic system are associated with a variety of human pathologies. By restriction fragment differential display polymerase chain reaction (RFDD-PCR) and matrix-assisted laser desorption/ionization tandem time-of-flight mass spectrometry (MALDI-TOF-TOF MS) based on two-dimensional polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis (2-DE), differentially expressed genes and proteins of ubiquitin specific proteases (USPs), proteasome subuinits (PSs) and ubiquitin protein ligase E3A (UBE3A) were analyzed between breast cancer and adjacent normal tissues. Some of them were further verified as over-expression by immunohistochemical stain. Five genes of proteasome subunits (PSs), including PSMB5, PSMD1, PSMD2, PSMD8 and PSMD11, four genes of USPs, including USP9X, USP9Y, USP10 and USP25, and ubiquitin protein ligase E3A (UBE3A) were over-expressed (&gt;3-fold) in breast cancer tissue compared to adjacent normal tissue, and over-expression (&gt;4-fold) of proteins of PSMA1 and SMT3A were observed in breast cancer tissue. PSMD8, PSMD11 and UBE3A were further verified as over-expression by immunohistochemical stain. The action of ubiquitin-proteasome system were obviously enhanced in breast cancer, and selectively intervention in action of ubiquitin-proteasome system may be a useful method of treating human breast cancer.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Breast cancer research and treatment</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Over-expression of genes and proteins of ubiquitin specific peptidases (USPs) and proteasome subunits (PSs) in breast cancer tissue observed by the methods of RFDD-PCR and proteomics.</str>
    <str name="id">17004105</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>G protein-coupled receptor kinase (GRK) 2 plays a crucial role in regulating the extent of desensitization and resensitization of G protein-coupled receptors (GPCRs). We have shown that the expression level of GRK2 in lymphocytes decreases during inflammatory diseases such as arthritis. Reactive oxygen species play an important role in a variety of inflammatory conditions, including arthritis. We demonstrate herein that oxidative stress, induced by exposure of lymphocytes to H(2)O(2), results in a 50% reduction in GRK2 protein levels and GRK activity with no changes in mRNA expression. Treatment of lymphocytes with the tyrosine kinase inhibitor genistein partially reverses the effect of H(2)O(2) on GRK2 levels, although we did not detect direct tyrosine phosphorylation of GRK2. Inhibition of the nonproteasomal protease calpain by calpeptin can prevent the H(2)O(2)-induced GRK2 decrease. In vitro experiments confirm that GRK2 is partially digested by m-calpain in a calcium-dependent way. Functionally, H(2)O(2)-induced decrease in GRK2 levels is associated with an ~70% decrease in agonist-induced beta(2)-adrenergic receptor sequestration. We describe oxidative stress as a novel mechanism for regulation of the intracellular level of GRK2 during inflammatory processes. Moreover, our data demonstrate that oxidative stress may change the functioning of GPCRs via calpain-dependent regulation of GRK2 levels.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Molecular pharmacology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Oxidative stress decreases G protein-coupled receptor kinase 2 in lymphocytes via a calpain-dependent mechanism.</str>
    <str name="id">12130691</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Sulforaphane [SUL, 1-isothiocyanato-4-(methylsulfinyl)butane] is an isothiocyanate derived from glucoraphanin present in cruciferous vegetables, and it has a variety of potential chemopreventive actions. We analyzed the effects of SUL on the proliferation of human breast cancer cells and on the expression of estrogen receptor alpha (ERalpha) protein and mRNA in MCF-7 cells. Sulforaphane inhibited cell proliferation with IC(50) values at 24 and 48 h of 12.5 and 7.5 muM doses, respectively, and decreased ERalpha protein expression at concentrations between 2.5 and 30 muM. Inhibition of ERalpha protein expression was also accompanied by decreased progesterone receptor expression. MCF-7 ERalpha mRNA expression was inhibited by SUL at a dose of 30 muM, but not at lower SUL concentrations. At SUL doses &lt;30 muM, the SUL-induced suppression of ERalpha protein was reversed by preincubation with the proteasome inhibitor MG132 and was accompanied by an increase in protein levels of the 20S catalytic core subunit PSMB5. Therefore, SUL can inhibit the expression of ERalpha protein in MCF-7 cells in part by inhibition of ERalpha mRNA transcription as well as by a mechanism that may involve increased proteasome-mediated degradation. These data provide new insights into mechanisms by which SUL inhibits proliferation of and down-regulates hormone receptor expression in MCF-7 cells.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">The Journal of nutritional biochemistry</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Regulation of estrogen receptor alpha expression in human breast cancer cells by sulforaphane.</str>
    <str name="id">18602823</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>In this study, the coordinated activation of ubiquitin-proteasome pathway (UPP), autophagy-lysosomal pathway (ALP), and mitochondrial remodeling including mitophagy was assessed by measuring protein markers during ultra-endurance running exercise in human skeletal muscle. Eleven male, experienced ultra-endurance athletes ran for 24 h on a treadmill. Muscle biopsy samples were taken from the vastus lateralis muscle 2 h before starting and immediately after finishing exercise. Athletes ran 149.8 ± 16.3 km with an effective running time of 18 h 42 min ( ± 41 min). The phosphorylation state of Akt (-74 ± 5%; P &lt; 0.001), FOXO3a (-49 ± 9%; P &lt; 0.001), mTOR Ser2448 (-32 ± 14%; P = 0.028), and 4E-BP1 (-34 ± 7%; P &lt; 0.001) was decreased, whereas AMPK phosphorylation state increased by 247 ± 170% (P = 0.042). Proteasome β2 subunit activity increased by 95 ± 44% (P = 0.028), whereas the activities associated with the β1 and β5 subunits remained unchanged. MuRF1 protein level increased by 55 ± 26% (P = 0.034), whereas MAFbx protein and ubiquitin-conjugated protein levels did not change. LC3bII increased by 554 ± 256% (P = 0.005), and the form of ATG12 conjugated to ATG5 increased by 36 ± 17% (P = 0.042). The mitochondrial fission marker phospho-DRP1 increased by 110 ± 47% (P = 0.003), whereas the fusion marker Mfn1 and the mitophagy markers Parkin and PINK1 remained unchanged. These results fit well with a coordinated regulation of ALP and UPP triggered by FOXO3 and AMPK during ultra-endurance exercise.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Journal of applied physiology (Bethesda, Md. : 1985)</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Modulation of autophagy and ubiquitin-proteasome pathways during ultra-endurance running.</str>
    <str name="id">22345427</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>This study describes the investigation of the efficiency of conjugated linoleic acid (CLA) isomers in reducing cancer cells viability exploring the role of the oxidative stress and acylpeptide hydrolase (APEH)/proteasome mediated pathways on pro-apoptotic activity of the isomer trans10,cis12 (t10,c12)-CLA. The basal activity/expression levels of APEH and proteasome (β-5 subunit) were preliminarily measured in eight cancer cell lines and the functional relationship between these enzymes was clearly demonstrated through their strong positive correlation. t10,c12-CLA efficiently inhibited the activity of APEH and proteasome isoforms in cell-free assays and the negative correlation between cell viability and caspase 3 activity confirmed the pro-apoptotic role of this isomer. Finally, modulatory effects of t10,c12-CLA on cellular redox status (intracellular glutathione, mRNA levels of antioxidant/detoxifying enzymes activated through NF-E2-related factor 2, Nrf2, pathway) and on APEH/β-5 activity/expression levels, were investigated in A375 melanoma cells. Dose- and time-dependent variations of the considered parameters were established and the resulting pro-apoptotic effects were shown to be associated with an alteration of the redox status and a down-regulation of APEH/proteasome pathway. Therefore, our results support the idea that these events are involved in ROS-dependent apoptosis of t10,c12-CLA-treated A375 cells. The combined inhibition, triggered by t10,c12-CLA, via the modulation of APEH/proteasome and Nrf2 pathway for treating melanoma, is suggested as a subject for further in vivo studies. </str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">PloS one</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">RedOx status, proteasome and APEH: insights into anticancer mechanisms of t10,c12-conjugated linoleic acid isomer on A375 melanoma cells.</str>
    <str name="id">24260504</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Most antigenic peptides presented on major histocompatibility complex class I molecules are generated by proteasomes. Interferon-gamma, which stimulates antigen presentation, induces new proteasome beta-subunits LMP2 and LMP7, which replace the homologous beta-subunits Y (delta) and X (epsilon). As a result, the capacity of the proteasome to cleave model peptides increases after hydrophobic and basic residues and falls after acidic residues. To clarify the function of these subunits, we examined the effects of overexpressing subunits X (delta) and Y (epsilon). Transfection of the Y gene into HeLa cells stimulated the proteasomal cleavage after acidic residues without altering other peptidase activities. This effect was proportional to the amount of the Y subunits and opposite to the effect of its homolog, LMP2. Y appears to promote cleavages after acidic residues. Furthermore, in mutants lacking the LMP genes (in contrast to wild-type cells), interferon-gamma treatment increased the proteasome content of Y subunits and enhanced postacidic cleavages. Transfection with cDNA for the X subunit reduced hydrolysis after hydrophobic and basic residues, an effect opposite to transfection of LMP2 and LMP7. Surprisingly, transfection of X increased the amounts not only of X, but also of Y, while decreasing LMP2 content. Thus, the loss of the Y subunit upon interferon-gamma treatment or LMP2 transfection accounts for the suppression of postacidic cleavages, and the loss of X contributes to the increased hydrolysis after hydrophobic and basic residues. These adaptations should favor the production of the kinds of peptides that are presented on major histocompatibility complex class I molecules.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">The Journal of biological chemistry</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Proteasome subunits X and Y alter peptidase activities in opposite ways to the interferon-gamma-induced subunits LMP2 and LMP7.</str>
    <str name="id">8663318</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Despite encouraging results with the proteasome inhibitor bortezomib in the treatment of hematologic malignancies, emergence of resistance can limit its efficacy, hence calling for novel strategies to overcome bortezomib-resistance. We previously showed that bortezomib-resistant human leukemia cell lines expressed significantly lower levels of immunoproteasome at the expense of constitutive proteasomes, which harbored point mutations in exon 2 of the PSMB5 gene encoding the β5 subunit. Here we investigated whether up-regulation of immunoproteasomes by exposure to interferon-γ restores sensitivity to bortezomib in myeloma and leukemia cell lines with acquired resistance to bortezomib.</str>
      <str>RPMI-8226 myeloma, THP1 monocytic/macrophage and CCRF-CEM (T) parental cells and sub lines with acquired resistance to bortezomib were exposed to Interferon-γ for 24-48 h where after the effects on proteasome subunit expression and activity were measured, next to sensitivity measurements to proteasome inhibitors bortezomib, carfilzomib, and the immunoproteasome selective inhibitor ONX 0914. At last, siRNA knockdown experiments of β5i and β1i were performed to identify the contribution of these subunits to sensitivity to proteasome inhibition. Statistical significance of the differences were determined using the Mann-Whitney U test.</str>
      <str>Interferon-γ exposure markedly increased immunoproteasome subunit mRNA to a significantly higher level in bortezomib-resistant cells (up to 30-fold, 10-fold, and 6-fold, in β1i, β5i, and β2i, respectively) than in parental cells. These increases were paralleled by elevated immunoproteasome protein levels and catalytic activity, as well as HLA class-I. Moreover, interferon-γ exposure reinforced sensitization of bortezomib-resistant tumor cells to bortezomib and carfilzomib, but most prominently to ONX 0914, as confirmed by cell growth inhibition studies, proteasome inhibitor-induced apoptosis, activation of PARP cleavage and accumulation of polyubiquitinated proteins. This sensitization was abrogated by siRNA silencing of β5i but not by β1i silencing, prior to pulse exposure to interferon-γ.</str>
      <str>Downregulation of β5i subunit expression is a major determinant in acquisition of bortezomib-resistance and enhancement of its proteasomal assembly after induction by interferon-γ facilitates restoration of sensitivity in bortezomib-resistant leukemia cells towards bortezomib and next generation (immuno) proteasome inhibitors.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Journal of hematology &amp; oncology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Interferon-γ-induced upregulation of immunoproteasome subunit assembly overcomes bortezomib resistance in human hematological cell lines.</str>
    <str name="id">24418325</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Exposure to [14C]-3,4-dichloroisocoumarin (DCI) of multicatalytic proteinase complexes (MPC) isolated from bovine pituitary and spleen leads to label incorporation into several beta-type subunits, to rapid inactivation of the chymotrypsin-like (ChT-L) activity, and to a slower inactivation of other activities of the MPC. The pituitary and spleen MPCs differ in that the first contains almost exclusively the X, Y, and Z subunits, whereas in the latter these subunits are largely replaced by LMP2, LMP7, and MECL1. Preincubation with two peptidyl aledhyde inhibitors of the ChT-L activity protected the X subunit in the pituitary MPC and unexpectedly the LMP2 subunit in the spleen MPC from label incorporation, despite the greater amino acid sequence homology of the LMP7 subunit to that of the X subunit. Losses in the yield of amino acids in both subunits, shown by amino acid sequencing, and lability of the DCI-protein bond indicated formation of an acyl derivative by reaction of DCI with the threonine OH group. Brief exposure to [14C]-DCI led to preferential incorporation of label into the LMP2 and X subunits, consistent with the high inactivation rate constants of the ChT-L activity. Z-LLF-CHO, an inhibitor of ChT-L activity, but not Z-GPFL-CHO, an inhibitor of the branched chain amino acid preferring component, prevented incorporation of radioactivity into the X subunits, whereas both inhibitors prevented label incorporation into LMP2, indicating differences in susceptibility to inhibition between the two components. These and other data are consistent with involvement of the X and LMP2 subunits in expression of the ChT-L activity in the pituitary and spleen MPC, respectively, and suggest the catalytic functions of two other beta-subunits.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Biochemistry</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Reactions of [14C]-3,4-dichloroisocoumarin with subunits of pituitary and spleen multicatalytic proteinase complexes (proteasomes).</str>
    <str name="id">9374874</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The ubiquitin proteasome system plays an exceptional biological role in the antigen processing and immune response and it could potentially be involved in pathogenesis of many immunity-related diseases, including juvenile idiopathic arthritis (JIA).</str>
      <str>The PSMB5 (rs11543947), PSMA6 (rs2277460, rs1048990), PSMC6 (rs2295826, rs2295827), and PSMA3 (rs2348071) proteasomal genes were genotyped on JIA subtype- and sex-specific association; plasma proteasome levels was measured in patients having risk and protective four-locus genotypes and eventual functional significance of allele substitutions was evaluated in silico.</str>
      <str>Loci rs11543947 and rs1048990 were identified as disease neutral and other loci as disease susceptible (p &lt; 0.05). The rs2277460, rs2295826, and rs2295827 loci had the strongest association with oligoarthritis [odds ratio (OR) = 2.024, 95% confidence interval (CI) 1.101-3.722; OR = 2.371, 95% CI 1.390-4.044; OR = 2.183, 95% CI 1.272-2.737, respectively), but the rs2348071 locus was associated with polyarthritis in females (OR = 3.438, 95% CI 1.626-7.265). A strong (p &lt; 0.001) association was detected between the rs2277460/rs2295826/rs2295827/rs2348071 four-locus genotypes and the healthy phenotype when all loci were homozygous on common alleles (OR 0.439, 95% CI 0.283-0.681) and with the disease phenotype when the rs2348071 and the rs2295826 and/or rs2295827 loci were represented by risk genotypes simultaneously (OR 4.674, 95% CI 2.096-10.425). Rarely observed in controls, the double rs2277460/rs2348071 heterozygotes were rather frequent in affected males and more strongly associated with polyarthritis (p &lt; 0.05). Haplotypes carrying the rare rs2295826/rs2295827 and rs2277460 alleles showed a strong (p &lt; 0.001) association with oligo- and polyarthritis, respectively. The plasma proteasome level was found to be significantly higher in females having four-locus risk genotypes compared with protective genotypes (p &lt; 0.001). Sequence affinity to transcription factors and similarity to splicing signals, microRNAs and/or hairpin precursors potentially depend on allele substitutions in disease susceptible loci.</str>
      <str>We demonstrate for the first time evidence of a sex-specific association of PSMA6/PSMC6/PSMA3 genetic variants with subtypes of JIA and plasma proteasome concentrations. Theoretical models of the functional significance of allele substitutions are discussed.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Pediatrics and neonatology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Juvenile idiopathic arthritis subtype- and sex-specific associations with genetic variants in the PSMA6/PSMC6/PSMA3 gene cluster.</str>
    <str name="id">24875235</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Proteasomes are the major enzyme complexes for non-lysosomal protein degradation in eukaryotic cells. Mammals express two sets of catalytic subunits: the constitutive subunits β1, β2 and β5 and the immunosubunits LMP2 (β1i), MECL-1 (β2i) and LMP7 (β5i). The LMP7-propeptide (proLMP7) is required for optimal maturation of LMP2/MECL-1-containing precursors to mature immunoproteasomes, but can also mediate efficient integration into mixed proteasomes containing β1 and β2. In contrast, the β5-propeptide (proβ5) has been suggested to promote preferential integration into β1/β2-containing precursors, consequently favouring the formation of constitutive proteasomes. Here, we show that proβ5 predominantly promotes integration into LMP2/MECL-1-containing precursors in IFNγ-stimulated, LMP7-deficient cells and infected LMP7-deficient mice. This demonstrates that proβ5 does not direct preferential integration into β1/β2-containing precursors, but instead promotes the formation of mixed LMP2/MECL-1/β5 proteasomes under inflammatory conditions. Moreover, the propeptides substantially differ in their capacity to promote proteasome maturation, with proLMP7 showing a significantly higher chaperone activity as compared to proβ5. Increased efficiency of proteasome maturation mediated by proLMP7 is required for optimal MHC class I cell surface expression and is equally important as the catalytic activity of immunoproteasomes. Intriguingly, induction of LMP7 by infection not only results in rapid exchange of constitutive by immunosubunits, as previously suggested, but also increases the total proteasome abundance within the infected tissue. Hence our data identify a novel LMP7-dependend mechanism to enhance the activity of the proteasome system in infection, which is based on the high chaperone activity of proLMP7 and relies on accelerated maturation of active proteasome complexes.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">PloS one</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The proteasome system in infection: impact of β5 and LMP7 on composition, maturation and quantity of active proteasome complexes.</str>
    <str name="id">22768135</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Stimulation of mouse macrophages with LPS leads to tumor necrosis factor (TNF-α) secretion and nitric oxide (NO) release at different times through independent signaling pathways. While the precise regulatory mechanisms responsible for these distinct phenotypic responses have not been fully delineated, results of our recent studies strongly implicate the cellular cytoplasmic ubiquitin-proteasome pathway as a key regulator of LPS-induced macrophage inflammatory responses. Our objective in this study was to define the relative contribution of specific proteasomal active-sites in induction of TNF-α and NO after LPS treatment of RAW 264.7 macrophages using selective inhibitors of these active sites. Our data provide evidence that LPS stimulation of mouse macrophages triggers a selective increase in the levels of gene and protein expression of the immunoproteasomes, resulting in a modulation of specific functional activities of the proteasome and a corresponding increase in NO production as compared to untreated controls. These findings suggest the LPS-dependent induction of immunoproteasome. In contrast, we also demonstrate that TNF-α expression is primarily dependent on both the chymotrypsin- and the trypsin-like activities of X, Y, Z subunits of the proteasome. Proteasome-associated post-acidic activity alone also contributes to LPS-induced expression of TNF-α. Taken together; our results indicate that LPS-induced TNF-α in macrophages is differentially regulated by each of the three proteasome activities. Since addition of proteasome inhibitors to mouse macrophages profoundly affects the degradation of proteins involved in signal transduction, we conclude that proteasome-specific degradation of several signaling proteins is likely involved in differential regulation of LPS-dependent secretion of proinflammatory mediators.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Cell biochemistry and biophysics</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">LPS-induced formation of immunoproteasomes: TNF-α and nitric oxide production are regulated by altered composition of proteasome-active sites.</str>
    <str name="id">21455682</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Bortezomib, a proteasome-specific inhibitor, has emerged as a promising cancer therapeutic agent. However, development of resistance to bortezomib may pose a challenge to effective anticancer therapy. Therefore, characterization of cellular mechanisms involved in bortezomib resistance and development of effective strategies to overcome this resistance represent important steps in the advancement of bortezomib-mediated cancer therapy.</str>
      <str>The present study reports the development of I-45-BTZ-R, a bortezomib-resistant cell line, from the bortezomib-sensitive mesothelioma cell line I-45. I-45-BTZ-R cells showed no cross-resistance to the chemotherapeutic drugs cisplatin, 5-fluorouracil, and doxorubicin. Moreover, the bortezomib-adapted I-45-BTZ-R cells had decreased growth kinemics and did not over express proteasome subunit beta5 (PSMB5) as compared to parental I-45 cells. I-45-BTZ-R cells and parental I-45 cells showed similar inhibition of proteasome activity, but I-45-BTZ-R cells exhibited much less accumulation of ubiquitinated proteins following exposure to 40 nm bortezomib. Further studies revealed that relatively low doses of bortezomib did not induce an unfolded protein response (UPR) in the bortezomib-adapted cells, while higher doses induced UPR with concomitant cell death, as evidenced by higher expression of the mitochondrial chaperone protein Bip and the endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress-related pro-apoptotic protein CHOP. In addition, bortezomib exposure did not induce the accumulation of the pro-apoptotic proteins p53, Mcl-1S, and noxa in the bortezomib-adapted cells.</str>
      <str>These results suggest that UPR evasion, together with reduced pro-apoptotic gene induction, accounts for bortezomib resistance in the bortezomib-adapted mesothelioma cell line I-45-BTZ-R.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Molecular cancer</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Characterization of bortezomib-adapted I-45 mesothelioma cells.</str>
    <str name="id">20482802</str></doc>
</result>
</response>
