<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<response>

<lst name="responseHeader">
  <int name="status">0</int>
  <int name="QTime">1</int>
  <lst name="params">
    <str name="q">25297588
24467809
23533340
23063462
22161108
21983725
21839020
18686606
18374127
17459061
16331565
15847661
12366770
9760178
9226185
9122901
9054453
7912436
2118655
25239830
25101798
24665114
24527852
22053055
19137814
18205178
18155296
18023290
17922418
15487706
15476160
10330445
9745152
9299444
1763885
24593306
19572973
12652076
7768954
7656588
16490787
23372041
20506485
24941225
12697902
21060863
23824729
11698403
21926972
22082156
15146197
15489334
12477932</str>
    <str name="indent">true</str>
    <str name="fl">id, medline_article_title, medline_abstract_text</str>
    <str name="rows">105</str>
    <str name="wt">xml</str>
  </lst>
</lst>
<result name="response" numFound="53" start="0">
  <doc>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Molecular genetic analysis for the para-Bombay blood group revealing two novel alleles in the FUT1 gene.</str>
    <str name="id">21839020</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Families segregating for deficiency of the H alpha-2-L-fucosyltransferase, FUT1, have been investigated for linkage between FUT1 and other markers on chromosome 19. The results provide evidence for close linkage between FUT1 and FUT2 and for looser linkage between FUT1 and APOC2 and between FUT1 and D19S7. Pairwise linkage data are also reported between other markers investigated.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The human chromosome 19 linkage group FUT1 (H), FUT2 (SE), LE, LU, PEPD, C3, APOC2, D19S7 and D19S9.</str>
    <str name="id">1763885</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The National Institutes of Health Mammalian Gene Collection (MGC) Program is a multiinstitutional effort to identify and sequence a cDNA clone containing a complete ORF for each human and mouse gene. ESTs were generated from libraries enriched for full-length cDNAs and analyzed to identify candidate full-ORF clones, which then were sequenced to high accuracy. The MGC has currently sequenced and verified the full ORF for a nonredundant set of &gt;9,000 human and &gt;6,000 mouse genes. Candidate full-ORF clones for an additional 7,800 human and 3,500 mouse genes also have been identified. All MGC sequences and clones are available without restriction through public databases and clone distribution networks (see http:mgc.nci.nih.gov).</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Generation and initial analysis of more than 15,000 full-length human and mouse cDNA sequences.</str>
    <str name="id">12477932</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Notch receptor signaling regulates cell growth and differentiation, and core components of Notch signaling pathways are conserved from Drosophila to humans. Fringe glycosyltransferases are crucial modulators of Notch signaling that act on epidermal growth factor (EGF)-like repeats in the Notch receptor extracellular domain. The substrate of Fringe is EGF-O-fucose and the transfer of fucose to Notch by protein O-fucosyltransferase 1 is necessary for Fringe to function. O-fucose also occurs on Cripto and on Notch ligands. Here we show that mouse embryos lacking protein O-fucosyltransferase 1 die at midgestation with severe defects in somitogenesis, vasculogenesis, cardiogenesis, and neurogenesis. The phenotype is similar to that of embryos lacking downstream effectors of all Notch signaling pathways such as presenilins or RBP-J kappa, and is different from Cripto, Notch receptor, Notch ligand, or Fringe null phenotypes. Protein O-fucosyltransferase 1 is therefore an essential core member of Notch signaling pathways in mammals.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Protein O-fucosyltransferase 1 is an essential component of Notch signaling pathways.</str>
    <str name="id">12697902</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Dietary intake of macronutrients (carbohydrate, protein, and fat) has been associated with risk of chronic conditions such as obesity and diabetes. Family studies have reported a moderate contribution of genetics to variation in macronutrient intake. In a genome-wide meta-analysis of a population-based discovery cohort (n = 33 533), rs838133 in FGF21 (19q13.33), rs197273 near TRAF family member-associated NF-kappa-B activator (TANK) (2p24.2), and rs10163409 in FTO (16q12.2) were among the top associations (P &lt; 10(-5)) for percentage of total caloric intake from protein and carbohydrate. rs838133 was replicated in silico in an independent sample from the Cohorts for Heart and Aging Research in Genomic Epidemiology Consortium (CHARGE) Nutrition Working Group (n = 38 360) and attained genome-wide significance in combined analysis (Pjoint = 7.9 × 10(-9)). A cytokine involved in cellular metabolism, FGF21 is a potential susceptibility gene for obesity and type 2 diabetes. Our results highlight the potential of genetic variation for determining dietary macronutrient intake.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Novel locus including FGF21 is associated with dietary macronutrient intake.</str>
    <str name="id">23372041</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The Bombay phenotype fails to express the ABH antigens of ABO blood group system on red blood cells and in secretions because of a lack in activities of the H gene (FUT1)- and Secretor gene (FUT2)-encoded alpha (1,2)fucosyltransferases. In this study, we have examined the FUT1 and the FUT2 from three unrelated Indian individuals with the Bombay phenotype. These three individuals were found to be homozygous for a T725G mutation in the coding region of the FUT1, which inactivated the enzyme activity. In addition, we did not detect any hybridized band corresponding to the FUT2 by Southern blot analysis using the catalytic domain of the FUT2 as a probe, indicating that the three individuals were homozygous for a gene deletion in the FUT2. These results suggest that the T725G mutation of FUT1 and the gene deletion of FUT2 are responsible for the classical Indian Bombay phenotype.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Missense mutation of FUT1 and deletion of FUT2 are responsible for Indian Bombay phenotype of ABO blood group system.</str>
    <str name="id">9299444</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To study two cases of rare para-Bombay blood types Bmh and Amh in order to determine clinical strategies of blood transfusion.</str>
      <str>ABO blood type was determined with serological assays. The samples were also genotyped with polymerase chain reaction-sequence specific primer (PCR-SSP) for potential mutations in α-1,2-fucosyltransferase gene (FUT1). The results were verified with direct sequencing.</str>
      <str>Two rare para-Bombay blood types, namely Bmh and Amh, were identified by serological method, with one being BO1 which contained a FUT1 allele 547-548delAG deletion (h1h1), and another being A205O2 which contained FUT1 allele a 547-548delAG deletion and a FUT1 allele 658C/T missense mutation (h1h3).</str>
      <str>FUT1 allele 547-548delAG deletion and 658C&gt;T missense mutation in part form the molecular basis of para-Bombay blood types. As Bmh and Amh contain anti-HI in sera, great attention should be paid to avoid adverse reaction of blood transfusion in clinics.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">[Mutational analysis for FUT1 gene in two cases with para-Bombay blood type].</str>
    <str name="id">22161108</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Lewis antigens are terminal fucosylated oligosaccharides synthesized by the sequential action of several glycosyltransferases. The fucosyltransferases are the enzymes responsible for the addition of terminal fucose to precursor oligosaccharides attached to proteins or lipids. These oligosaccharides, defined as cell surface markers, have been implicated in different types of intercellular interactions and in adhesion and invasion processes. Transfection of HT-29/M3 colon cancer cells with the full length of human fucosyltransferase (FUT1), induces the synthesis of H type 2 and Lewis y antigens, associated with a decrease of sialyl-Lewis x. The capacity to develop primary tumors when cells were injected intrasplenically was similar in parental and FUT1-transfected cells, but the capacity to colonize the liver after spleen removal was significantly reduced in M3/FUT1 transfected cells. These results indicate that the expression of FUT1 induces changes in the metastatic capacity of HT-29/M3 colon cancer cells, as a consequence of the altered expression pattern of type 2 Lewis antigens. Also, an association between MUC5AC expression and the degree of gland differentiation in both primary splenic tumors and hepatic metastases was detected.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Changes in the invasive and metastatic capacities of HT-29/M3 cells induced by the expression of fucosyltransferase 1.</str>
    <str name="id">17459061</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To explore the effect of α -1,2 fucosyltransferase (FUT1) gene 682A&gt; G and 547_552delAG mutations on the expression of FUT1 mRNA and activity of α -1,2 fucosyltransferase.</str>
      <str>Recombinant expression vectors of FUT1 682A&gt; G and FUT1 547_552delAG were constructed and transfected into COS-7 cells for stable expression screening. Expression of FUT1 mRNA was determined using real-time quantitative PCR. The activity of FUT1 was measured with high-performance liquid chromatography.</str>
      <str>Stably transfected COS-7 cells with wild type FUT1, FUT1 682A&gt; G and FUT1 547_552delAG were respectively obtained. The FUT1 mRNA level of transfected cells with 682A&gt; G and 547_552delAG recombination vectors have measured 101.69% and 102.79% compared with that of wild type FUT1 transfected cells. A specific protein band with about 46 kD was confirmed in the 682A&gt; G transfected cell lysates by SDS-PAGE electrophoresis and Western blotting with 6× His Tag antibody. Similar protein was not identified in the 547_552delAG cells lysates. Enzymes activity of FUT1 682A&gt; G has measured 61.01% compared with wild type FUT1 protein, whilst the activity of FUT1 547_557delAG was completely abolished.</str>
      <str>FUT1 682A&gt; G and 547_552delAG mutations do not affect the transcript efficiency, although various mutations have different impact on the enzyme's activity.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">[Effect of α -1,2 fucosyltransferase gene 682A&gt; G and 547_552delAG mutations on the activity of fucosyltransferase].</str>
    <str name="id">25297588</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To investigate the h4 allele (C35T) frequency of alpha-1,2-fucosyltransferase gene in Chinese population.</str>
      <str>The polymerase chain reaction-restriction fragment length polymorphism (PCR-RFLP) method for identifying C35T variant was established by using PCR to amplify a 125 bp FUT1 gene fragment, including C35T variant sequence, and the PCR product was digested by Hae III restriction enzyme. One hundred and fifty-eight random samples from Chinese blood donor were screened by PCR-RFLP.</str>
      <str>Among 158 Chinese individuals with normal ABO and H blood group phenotypes, 8 and 83 were homozygous with 35T/T and 35C/C, respectively, while 67 were heterozygous with 35C/T. The allele frequencies were compatible with Hardy-Weinberg equilibrium.</str>
      <str>The C35T substitution of FUT1 gene is not a mutation which gives rise to a non-functional h allele responsible for para-Bombay phenotype but a single nucleotide polymorphism in Chinese population.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">[Study on the frequency of alpha-1,2-fucosyltransferase gene h4 allele (C35T) in Chinese population].</str>
    <str name="id">16331565</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Definition of the molecular basis of the Reunion and the Bombay red cell and salivary H-deficient phenotypes.</str>
      <str>Sequence and expression of FUT1 and FUT2 genes from H-deficient individuals. Family segregation analysis of the mutations responsible for the fucosyltransferase defects of H, secretor and Lewis systems.</str>
      <str>The Indian red cell H null Bombay phenotype depends on a new mutation of the FUT1 gene. T725--&gt;G changing Leu242--&gt;Arg. Their salivary nonsecretor phenotype is secondary to a complete deletion of the FUT2 gene. The red cell H weak Reunion phenotype depends on another new mutation of FUT1, C349--&gt;T which induces a change of His117--&gt;Tyr. Their salivary nonsecretor phenotype is due to the known Caucasian inactivating mutation G428--&gt;A.</str>
      <str>Single prevalent FUT1 and FUT2 point mutations and a deletion are responsible for the Indian Bombay H null and the Reunion H weak phenotypes found on Reunion island. This is in contrast with other H-deficient phenotypes where sporadic nonprevalent inactivating mutations are the rule.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Point mutations and deletion responsible for the Bombay H null and the Reunion H weak blood groups.</str>
    <str name="id">9745152</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Upon cellular entry retroviruses must avoid innate restriction factors produced by the host cell. For human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) human restriction factors, APOBEC3 (apolipoprotein-B-mRNA-editing-enzyme), p21 and tetherin are well characterised.</str>
      <str>To identify intrinsic resistance factors to HIV-1 replication we screened 19,121 human genes and identified 114 factors with significant inhibition of infection. Those with a known function are involved in a broad spectrum of cellular processes including receptor signalling, vesicle trafficking, transcription, apoptosis, cross-nuclear membrane transport, meiosis, DNA damage repair, ubiquitination and RNA processing. We focused on the PAF1 complex which has been previously implicated in gene transcription, cell cycle control and mRNA surveillance. Knockdown of all members of the PAF1 family of proteins enhanced HIV-1 reverse transcription and integration of provirus. Over-expression of PAF1 in host cells renders them refractory to HIV-1. Simian Immunodeficiency Viruses and HIV-2 are also restricted in PAF1 expressing cells. PAF1 is expressed in primary monocytes, macrophages and T-lymphocytes and we demonstrate strong activity in MonoMac1, a monocyte cell line.</str>
      <str>We propose that the PAF1c establishes an anti-viral state to prevent infection by incoming retroviruses. This previously unrecognised mechanism of restriction could have implications for invasion of cells by any pathogen.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">A whole genome screen for HIV restriction factors.</str>
    <str name="id">22082156</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The α(1,2)-fucosyltransferase gene 1 (FUT1) and 2 (FUT2), respectively, regulate H antigen synthesis in red blood cells and body fluids. Genetic polymorphisms of FUT1 and FUT2 are ethnically and geographically specific.</str>
      <str>Healthy unrelated Tibetan blood donors (n = 200) from the Tibet Autonomous Region of China were recruited for this study. The entire FUT1 and FUT2 coding regions were amplified and sequenced. The haplotypes including novel single-nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) were determined by clone sequencing.</str>
      <str>In Tibetans, the major FUT1 allele was wild-type allele with a frequency of 97.75%. One novel FUT1 allele was defined by a novel synonymous mutation (846T&gt;G). The two most common FUT2 alleles were functional allele Se(357) with a frequency of 32.75% and nonfunctional allele se(357,385) with a frequency of 55%. Two new FUT2 alleles were found at low frequency. They were characterized by two novel SNPs on the basis of se(357,385) : 617 T&gt;G (V206G) and 841 G&gt;A (G281R).</str>
      <str>Three new alleles in FUT1 and FUT2 genes were identified in the study. The allelic polymorphisms of FUT1 and FUT2 in Tibetans show a population-specific manner.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Sequence analysis of the human fucosyltransferase 1 and 2 genes in Tibetan blood donors: identification of three novel alleles.</str>
    <str name="id">24527852</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Kawasaki disease (KD) is a diffuse and acute small-vessel vasculitis observed in children, and has genetic and autoimmune components. We genotyped 112 case-parent trios of European decent (confirmed by ancestry informative markers) using the immunoChip array, and performed association analyses with susceptibility to KD and intravenous immunoglobulin (IVIG) non-response. KD susceptibility was assessed using the transmission disequilibrium test, whereas IVIG non-response was evaluated using multivariable logistic regression analysis. We replicated single-nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) in three gene regions (FCGR, CD40/CDH22 and HLA-DQB2/HLA-DOB) that have been previously associated with KD and provide support to other findings of several novel SNPs in genes with a potential pathway in KD pathogenesis. SNP rs838143 in the 3'-untranslated region of the FUT1 gene (2.7 × 10(-5)) and rs9847915 in the intergenic region of LOC730109 | BRD7P2 (6.81 × 10(-7)) were the top hits for KD susceptibility in additive and dominant models, respectively. The top hits for IVIG responsiveness were rs1200332 in the intergenic region of BAZ1A | C14orf19 (1.4 × 10(-4)) and rs4889606 in the intron of the STX1B gene (6.95 × 10(-5)) in additive and dominant models, respectively. Our study suggests that genes and biological pathways involved in autoimmune diseases have an important role in the pathogenesis of KD and IVIG response mechanism. </str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">High-density genotyping of immune loci in Kawasaki disease and IVIG treatment response in European-American case-parent trio study.</str>
    <str name="id">25101798</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Alpha 1, 2-fucosyltransferase (FUT 1/2) is a rate-limiting enzyme that catalyzes the synthesis of Lewis y, a cell membrane-associated carbohydrate antigen. In human ovarian cancer, the upregulated expression of FUT1 and Lewis y is associated with advanced pathological stages and involved in cell proliferation, migration and invasion. However, the mechanism underlying the upregulation of FUT1 is largely unknown. Here, we identify an AP-1 binding site in FUT1 promoter in ovarian cancer cells. c-Jun promotes FUT1 expression, thereby enhancing Lewis y biosynthesis in various ovarian cancer cell lines. Moreover, EMSA, luciferase activity and ChIP assays demonstrate c-Jun directly interacts with FUT1 promoter. Furthermore, FUT1 mediates c-Jun-induced cell proliferation in ovarian cancer cells. In human ovarian cancer samples, c-Jun overexpression is linked to malignant degree and positively correlated to FUT1 and Lewis y expression. Taken together, c-Jun could transcriptionally modulate FUT1 expression in ovarian cancer, implicating the potential application of c-Jun inhibitors for human ovarian cancer therapy. </str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">c-Jun transcriptionally regulates alpha 1, 2-fucosyltransferase 1 (FUT1) in ovarian cancer.</str>
    <str name="id">25239830</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>We conducted a combined genome-wide association study (GWAS) of 7,481 individuals with bipolar disorder (cases) and 9,250 controls as part of the Psychiatric GWAS Consortium. Our replication study tested 34 SNPs in 4,496 independent cases with bipolar disorder and 42,422 independent controls and found that 18 of 34 SNPs had P &lt; 0.05, with 31 of 34 SNPs having signals with the same direction of effect (P = 3.8 × 10(-7)). An analysis of all 11,974 bipolar disorder cases and 51,792 controls confirmed genome-wide significant evidence of association for CACNA1C and identified a new intronic variant in ODZ4. We identified a pathway comprised of subunits of calcium channels enriched in bipolar disorder association intervals. Finally, a combined GWAS analysis of schizophrenia and bipolar disorder yielded strong association evidence for SNPs in CACNA1C and in the region of NEK4-ITIH1-ITIH3-ITIH4. Our replication results imply that increasing sample sizes in bipolar disorder will confirm many additional loci.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Large-scale genome-wide association analysis of bipolar disorder identifies a new susceptibility locus near ODZ4.</str>
    <str name="id">21926972</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Cartilage engineering is the object of intense research as a result of major medical needs and therapeutic prospects. Porcine xenogeneic cells/tissues may help in the development of clinical applications such as articular cartilage repair. However, unmodified porcine cartilage is rejected in primates by humoral and cellular mechanisms. We previously showed that porcine articular chondrocytes (PAC) isolated from H-transferase (HT) transgenic pigs show markedly reduced expression of the Galalpha1,3Gal antigen (alphaGal) and prolonged survival when transplanted into alpha1,3galactosyltransferase-deficient mice. In this work, we further studied the protective mechanisms of HT transgenic expression in cartilage, particularly its effects on monocyte adhesion. To this end, PAC isolated from control and HT transgenic pigs were assayed for human complement deposition and adhesion to the human monoblastic cell line U937. Consistent with a reduction in complement activation by the classical pathway, the HT transgenic PAC showed a 2-fold reduction in the deposition of complement components C4 and C3 relative to controls. Adhesion of U937 cells to HT PAC was also diminished under various conditions. This reduction was more dramatic at high effector:target ratios and especially observed when combined with anti-alphaGal antibodies (5-fold difference). Nevertheless, this effect was also observed in the absence of anti-alphaGal. antibodies and after tumor necrosis factor treatment. These results suggest that HT expression on porcine chondrocytes protects them from both humoral and cellular rejection.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Characterization of cartilage from H-transferase transgenic pigs.</str>
    <str name="id">18374127</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Genes for fucosyltransferases 1 (FUT1:H), 2 (FUT2:Secretor), and 3 (FUT3:Lewis) encode enzymes crucial for ABH and Lewis blood group antigen synthesis. They are highly polymorphic and ethnically and geographically specific.</str>
      <str>Genetic variations and allele frequencies of FUT1, FUT2, and FUT3 encoding regions and flanking sequences were analyzed in 100 Styrian blood donors by systematic sequencing. Haplotypes were verified with sequence-specific primers. To identify discrepancies, serologically determined ABO and Lewis blood groups were correlated to respective genotypes.</str>
      <str>Two novel FUT1 alleles were defined by 9C&gt;T (silent) and 991C&gt;A (P331T) mutations, the latter located in the catalytic domain of the enzyme. Five new alleles of FUT2 were found: three were characterized by new variants and two resulted from new combinations of known polymorphisms. The new 412G&gt;A (G138S) mutation also is located in the catalytic domain. A new nonsecretor allele, based on the presence of 428G&gt;A (nonsense), was found. Another FUT2 allele may have resulted from an intragenic crossover event. FUT3 analysis revealed seven novel alleles, partly based on the new mutations 41G&gt;A (R14H), 1060C&gt;G (R354G), 735G&gt;C (silent), and 882C&gt;T (silent). While 41G&gt;A is placed in the cytoplasmic domain and functional, 1060C&gt;G is placed in the catalytic domain.</str>
      <str>Multiple common and sporadic sequence variations including 14 new alleles at FUT1, FUT2, and FUT3 loci were identified. Four novel mutations result in amino acid substitution in the protein. Three of them are predicted to have adverse effects on the enzyme activity. A novel nonsecretor allele was found.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Identification of 14 new alleles at the fucosyltransferase 1, 2, and 3 loci in Styrian blood donors, Austria.</str>
    <str name="id">19572973</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>In its fundamental attributes, the secretion pathway of the pancreatic bile salt-dependent lipase (BSDL) followed that described for all enzymes involved in regulated secretion. This route was inhibited by drugs that affect protein synthesis and intracellular transport. In the presence of monensin, BSDL was solely detected in microsome membrane fractions. The association of BSDL with intracellular membranes involved a protein complex, formed by at least two proteins of 94 and 56 kDa. In cells experiencing the metabolic stress due to azetidine-2-carboxylic acid, BSDL was additionally associated with a protein of 46 kDa. Affinity blotting showed that BSDL bound directly to the 94-kDa protein (p94). It was suggested that p94 could be a molecular chaperone, further identified as related to the 94-kDa glucose regulated protein (Grp 94). The membrane-associated BSDL (i.e. BSDL bound to the Grp 94-related p94) was O- and N-glycosylated and consequently appeared released from membranes in the trans-Golgi compartment. Therefore and for the first time, it is suggested that a multiprotein complex including the chaperone Grp 94-related p94 protein may play an essential role in the folding and transport of BSDL. One hypothesis is that the association of BSDL with membrane via the Grp 94-related p94 along its secretion pathway is required for its complete O-glycosylation, which occurs on the extended mucin-like structures present on the C-terminal part of the protein.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Chaperone function of a Grp 94-related protein for folding and transport of the pancreatic bile salt-dependent lipase.</str>
    <str name="id">7768954</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Molecular genetic analysis of FUT1 and FUT2 gene was performed for seven Chinese Han individuals serologically typed as para-Bombay.</str>
      <str>Seven DNA samples were studied by polymerase chain reaction and then by direct sequencing. Molecular cloning sequencing was done for an individual with a novel FUT1 allele. Family segregation analysis of the novel FUT1 allele was done to explore whether the allele was responsible for the fucosyltransferase defects of H.</str>
      <str>The FUT1 genotypes of seven para-Bombay individuals were h1h1 (four individuals), h2h2 (two individuals), h328hnew (one individual), alleles h1 lost one of the three AG repeats located at the nucleotides 547-552 of the FUT1 gene, h2 lost two of the three T repeats located at the nucleotides 880-882, h328 (nt328G&gt;A) was a missense mutation, all of them were known mutations, while allele hnew deleted GGTATTCCGCATCACCCTGCCCGTGCTGGCCCC at nt360-400, total 33 bases, and the frame-shift mutation was not previously reported. The segregation of the hnew allele in his family showed that his father genotype was Hh328, and his mother was Hhnew, while two brother were h328hnew. The FUT2 genotypes of seven para-Bombay individuals were Se357 Se357 (three individuals), Se357 Se357,385 (three individuals), Se357,716Se357,716(one individual), the functional Se357(nt357C&gt;T), Se716(nt716G&gt;A) and the weakly functional Se385(nt385A&gt;T) were known. The seven para-Bombay individuals carried at least one copy of a functional FUT2 allele was consistent with their secretor status.</str>
      <str>A novel FUT1 allele was identified in a para-Bombay Chinese individual, which was responsible for the inactivation of the FUT1-encoded enzyme activity.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">[Molecular genetic analysis of FUT1 and FUT2 gene in para-Bombay Chinese: a novel FUT1 allele is identified].</str>
    <str name="id">17922418</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The National Institutes of Health's Mammalian Gene Collection (MGC) project was designed to generate and sequence a publicly accessible cDNA resource containing a complete open reading frame (ORF) for every human and mouse gene. The project initially used a random strategy to select clones from a large number of cDNA libraries from diverse tissues. Candidate clones were chosen based on 5'-EST sequences, and then fully sequenced to high accuracy and analyzed by algorithms developed for this project. Currently, more than 11,000 human and 10,000 mouse genes are represented in MGC by at least one clone with a full ORF. The random selection approach is now reaching a saturation point, and a transition to protocols targeted at the missing transcripts is now required to complete the mouse and human collections. Comparison of the sequence of the MGC clones to reference genome sequences reveals that most cDNA clones are of very high sequence quality, although it is likely that some cDNAs may carry missense variants as a consequence of experimental artifact, such as PCR, cloning, or reverse transcriptase errors. Recently, a rat cDNA component was added to the project, and ongoing frog (Xenopus) and zebrafish (Danio) cDNA projects were expanded to take advantage of the high-throughput MGC pipeline.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The status, quality, and expansion of the NIH full-length cDNA project: the Mammalian Gene Collection (MGC).</str>
    <str name="id">15489334</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Fucosylation regulates various pathological events in cells. We reported that different levels of CRT (calreticulin) affect the cell adhesion and metastasis of bladder cancer. However, the precise mechanism of tumour metastasis regulated by CRT remains unclear. Using a DNA array, we identified FUT1 (fucosyltransferase 1) as a gene regulated by CRT expression levels. CRT regulated cell adhesion through α1,2-linked fucosylation of β1 integrin and this modification was catalysed by FUT1. To clarify the roles for FUT1 in bladder cancer, we transfected the human FUT1 gene into CRT-RNAi stable cell lines. FUT1 overexpression in CRT-RNAi cells resulted in increased levels of β1 integrin fucosylation and rescued cell adhesion to type-I collagen. Treatment with UEA-1 (Ulex europaeus agglutinin-1), a lectin that recognizes FUT1-modified glycosylation structures, did not affect cell adhesion. In contrast, a FUT1-specific fucosidase diminished the activation of β1 integrin. These results indicated that α1,2-fucosylation of β1 integrin was not involved in integrin-collagen interaction, but promoted β1 integrin activation. Moreover, we demonstrated that CRT regulated FUT1 mRNA degradation at the 3'-UTR. In conclusion, the results of the present study suggest that CRT stabilized FUT1 mRNA, thereby leading to an increase in fucosylation of β1 integrin. Furthermore, increased fucosylation levels activate β1 integrin, rather than directly modifying the integrin-binding sites. </str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Calreticulin activates β1 integrin via fucosylation by fucosyltransferase 1 in J82 human bladder cancer cells.</str>
    <str name="id">24593306</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>CD4(+) T cells play an important role in antitumor immune responses and autoimmune and infectious diseases. Although many major histocompatibility complex (MHC) class I-restricted tumor antigens have been identified in the last few years, little is known about MHC class II- restricted human tumor antigens recognized by CD4(+) T cells. Here, we describe the identification of a novel melanoma antigen recognized by an human histocompatibility leukocyte antigen (HLA)-DR1-restricted CD4(+) tumor-infiltrating lymphocyte (TIL)1363 using a genetic cloning approach. DNA sequencing analysis indicated that this was a fusion gene generated by a low density lipid receptor (LDLR) gene in the 5' end fused to a GDP-L-fucose:beta-D-galactoside 2-alpha-L-fucosyltransferase (FUT) in an antisense orientation in the 3' end. The fusion gene encoded the first five ligand binding repeats of LDLR in the NH2 terminus followed by a new polypeptide translated in frame with LDLR from the FUT gene in an antisense direction. Southern blot analysis showed that chromosomal DNA rearrangements occurred in the 1363mel cell line. Northern blot analysis detected two fusion RNA transcripts present only in the autologous 1363mel, but not in other cell lines or normal tissues tested. Two minimal peptides were identified from the COOH terminus of the fusion protein. This represents the first demonstration that a fusion protein resulting from a chromosomal rearrangement in tumor cells serves as an immune target recognized by CD4(+) T cells.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Identification of a novel major histocompatibility complex class II-restricted tumor antigen resulting from a chromosomal rearrangement recognized by CD4(+) T cells.</str>
    <str name="id">10330445</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The α 1,2-fucosyltransferase I (FUT1) enzyme is important for the biosynthesis of H antigens, Lewis B, and Lewis Y. In this study, we clarified the transcriptional regulation of FUT1 in the DLD-1 colon cancer cell line, which has high expression of Lewis B and Lewis Y antigens, expresses the FUT1 gene, and shows α 1,2-fucosyltransferase (FUT) activity. 5'-rapid amplification of cDNA ends revealed a FUT1 transcriptional start site -10 nucleotides upstream of the site registered at NM_000148 in the DataBase of Human Transcription Start Sites (DBTSS). Using the dual luciferase assay, FUT1 gene expression was shown to be regulated at the region -91 to -81 nt to the transcriptional start site, which contains the Elk-1 binding site. Site-directed mutagenesis of this region revealed the Elk-1 binding site to be essential for FUT1 transcription. Furthermore, transfection of the dominant negative Elk-1 gene, and the chromatin immunoprecipitation (CHIp) assay, supported Elk-1-dependent transcriptional regulation of FUT1 gene expression in DLD-1 cells. These results suggest that a defined region in the 5'-flanking region of FUT1 is critical for FUT1 transcription and that constitutive gene expression of FUT1 is regulated by Elk-1 in DLD-1 cells.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Transcriptional regulation of fucosyltransferase 1 gene expression in colon cancer cells.</str>
    <str name="id">23533340</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Recently, we have reported that in normal gastric epithelium, the expression of gastric apomucins MUC5AC and MUC6 is associated with the specific expression of type 1 and type 2 Lewis antigens, and FUT2 and FUT1 fucosyltransferases, respectively. Until now, there are no data demonstrating the direct implication of specific glycosyltransferases in the specific patterns of apomucin glycosylation. HT29/M3 colon cancer cell line express MUC1, MUC5AC, type 1 Lewis antigens and FUT2 but not type 2 structures and FUT1, as it occurs in the epithelial cells of the gastric superficial epithelium. These cells were transfected with the cDNA of human FUT1, the alpha-1,2-fucosyltransferase responsible for the synthesis of type 2 Lewis antigens, to assess the implication of FUT1 in the glycosylation of MUC1 and MUC5AC. The M3-FUT1 clones obtained express high levels of type 2 Lewis antigens: H type 2 and Ley antigens. Immunoprecipitation of MUC1 and MUC5AC apomucins gives the direct evidence that FUT1 catalyses the addition of alpha-1,2-fucose to these apomucins, supporting the hypothesis that the pattern of apomucin glycosylation is not only instructed by the mucin primary sequence but also by the set of glycosyltransferases expressed in each specific cell type.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The expression of human FUT1 in HT-29/M3 colon cancer cells instructs the glycosylation of MUC1 and MUC5AC apomucins.</str>
    <str name="id">12652076</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Human embryonic stem (hES) cells hold promise for generating an unlimited supply of cells for replacement therapies. To characterize hES cells at the molecular level, we obtained 148,453 expressed sequence tags (ESTs) from undifferentiated hES cells and three differentiated derivative subpopulations. Over 32,000 different transcripts expressed in hES cells were identified, of which more than 16,000 do not match closely any gene in the UniGene public database. Queries to this EST database revealed 532 significantly upregulated and 140 significantly downregulated genes in undifferentiated hES cells. These data highlight changes in the transcriptional network that occur when hES cells differentiate. Among the differentially regulated genes are several components of signaling pathways and transcriptional regulators that likely play key roles in hES cell growth and differentiation. The genomic data presented here may facilitate the derivation of clinically useful cell types from hES cells.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Transcriptome characterization elucidates signaling networks that control human ES cell growth and differentiation.</str>
    <str name="id">15146197</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Prostate cancer cell lines were examined for proteins that partnered with the transcription factor C/EBPalpha by use of a pull-down assay with S-tagged C/EBPalpha combined with matrix-assisted laser desorption ionization time-of-flight mass spectroscopy analysis. Ku70, Ku80, and poly(ADP-ribose) polymerase-1 (PARP-1) were identified as proteins that associated with C/EBPalpha. The physical interaction of C/EBPalpha with these partner proteins was further demonstrated by glutathione S-transferase (GST) pull-downs using purified protein expressed in Escherichia coli. The strongest binding was between C/EBPalpha and PARP-1. Immunoprecipitation of C/EBPalpha expressed in prostate cancer cells co-precipitated Ku70, Ku80, and PARP-1. Deletion analysis of C/EBPalpha indicated that the C terminus of C/EBPalpha was essential for the interaction of C/EBPalpha with Ku70, Ku80, and PARP-1. Functional analysis of the interaction between C/EBPalpha and the Ku proteins as well as PARP-1 showed that cells exhibiting these interactions had increased radiation sensitivity and decreased ability to repair double strand DNA breaks. Deficient DNA repair was dependent on the prostate cancer cell line tested, suggesting a complex process. We conclude that the association of C/EBPalpha with Ku proteins and PARP-1 raises the likelihood that C/EBPalpha-expressing prostate cancer cells may be more sensitive to DNA-damaging agents and may be important in the design of new prostate cancer therapies.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">In prostate cancer cells the interaction of C/EBPalpha with Ku70, Ku80, and poly(ADP-ribose) polymerase-1 increases sensitivity to DNA damage.</str>
    <str name="id">16490787</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The epithelial cell surface of the endometrium undergoes substantial biochemical changes to allow embryo attachment and implantation in early pregnancy. We hypothesized that tissue macrophages influence these events to promote uterine receptivity. To investigate the role of macrophages in regulating epithelial cell expression of genes linked to glycan-mediated embryo adhesion, Ishikawa, RL95-2 and HEC1A endometrial epithelial cells were cultured alone or with unactivated or lipopolysaccharide-activated monocytic U937 cells, separated using transwell inserts. Expression of mRNAs encoding two α1,2-fucosyltransferases (FUT1, FUT2) was increased in all three epithelial cell lines following co-culture with U937 cells, and was associated with increased fucosylation of cell surface glycoproteins detected using lectins from Ulex europaeus (UEA-1) and Dolichos biflorus (DBA). FUT1 induction by U937 cells also occurred in primary endometrial epithelial cells collected in luteal but not proliferative phase. Activation of the interleukin-6 (IL6)/leukemia inhibitory factor (LIF) cytokine signaling pathway with phosphorylation of STAT3 and elevated SOCS3 mRNA expression was evident in epithelial cells stimulated by U937 co-culture. Several recombinant macrophage-secreted cytokines exerted stimulatory or inhibitory effects on FUT1 and FUT2 mRNA expression, and the macrophage-derived cytokine LIF partially replicated the effects of U937 cells on both FUT1 and FUT2 expression and UEA-1 and DBA lectin reactivity in Ishikawa cells. These results suggest that macrophage-derived factors including LIF might facilitate development of an implantation-receptive endometrium by regulating surface glycan structures in epithelial cells. Abnormal phenotypes or altered abundance of uterine macrophages could contribute to the pathophysiology of primary unexplained infertility in women.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Macrophages regulate expression of α1,2-fucosyltransferase genes in human endometrial epithelial cells.</str>
    <str name="id">22053055</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The para-Bombay phenotype is characterized by H-deficient or H-partially deficient red blood cells (RBCs) in persons who secrete ABH antigens in their saliva. The studies that determined the genotypes for two Chinese individuals with the para-Bombay phenotype are described.</str>
      <str>RBC phenotypes were characterized by conventional serologic methods. Exons 6 and 7 of the ABO gene were amplified, as well as the entire coding region for FUT1 and FUT2, with four independence polymerase chain reactions (PCRs) from genomic DNA. PCR products were excised, purified from agarose gels, and sequenced directly. Mutations of FUT1 were identified by TOPO cloning sequencing.</str>
      <str>For both individuals, RBC ABO genotypes correlated with ABH substances in their saliva. One individual (a patient) had two heterozygous mutations of FUT1 by direct DNA sequencing, namely, a C--&gt;T heterozygous mutation at position 293(C293T) and AG heterozygous deletion (CAGAGAG--&gt;CAGAG) at position 547 to 552. These two mutations were confirmed to be compound heterozygotes; that is, each mutation was determined to be on a separate homologous chromosome by TOPO cloning sequencing. The FUT2 genotype was Se(357)Se(357). The other individual (a blood donor) had an AG deletion at position 547 to 552 homozygous allele in FUT1. The FUT2 genotype was Se(357)Se(357,385). C293T mutation can cause Thr/Met at amino acid position 98. AG deletion at position 547 to 552 caused a reading frameshift and a premature stop codon.</str>
      <str>A novel nonfunctional FUT1 allele C293T was identified in a person with the para-Bombay phenotype. This rare H-deficient phenotype may result from different nonfunctional alleles.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Molecular basis for para-Bombay phenotypes in Chinese persons, including a novel nonfunctional FUT1 allele.</str>
    <str name="id">15847661</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The expression of the ABO antigens on erythrocyte membranes is regulated by H gene (FUT1)-encoded alpha(1,2)fucosyltransferase activity. We have examined the expression of the FUT1 in several tumor cell lines, including erythroid lineage and normal bone marrow cells, by Northern blot and/or reverse transcription-polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) analyses. RT-PCR indicated that bone marrow cells, erythroleukemic cells (HEL), and highly undifferentiated leukemic cells (K562) that have erythroid characteristics expressed the FUT1 mRNA while four leukemic cell lines did not. The FUT1 mRNA was also demonstrated in gastric, colonic, and ovarian (MCAS) cancer cell lines by RT-PCR. Northern blot analysis indicated that a 4. 0-kilobase FUT1 transcript was expressed in some of these tumor cell lines. Rapid amplification of 5' cDNA end (RACE) analysis suggested that the FUT1 transcript had several forms generated by two distinct transcription start sites and alternative splicing. The results of RT-PCR using specific primers for each starting exon suggested that two transcription initiation sites (exon 1A and exon 2A) of the FUT1 were identified in gastric cancer cells and in ovarian cancer cells. Only exon 1A was identified as a transcription start site in another gastric cancer cell line, two colonic cancer cell lines, and in K562 cells, whereas only exon 2A was identified in HEL cells and in bone marrow cells. These two transcription start sites were located 1.8 kilobases apart. Therefore, two distinct promoters appeared to be present in the FUT1. The distinct promoters of the FUT1 and alternative splicing of the FUT1 mRNA may be associated with time- and tissue-specific expression of the FUT1.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Structure and expression of H-type GDP-L-fucose:beta-D-galactoside 2-alpha-L-fucosyltransferase gene (FUT1). Two transcription start sites and alternative splicing generate several forms of FUT1 mRNA.</str>
    <str name="id">9054453</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Current polymerase chain reaction-based strategies for phenotype prediction often fail when sporadic nonfunctional alleles are encountered. The population frequency of such mutations was not known for any gene under low selection pressure and may be best examined in blood groups systems lacking prevalent nonfunctional alleles. The frequency of the very rare Bombay blood group (Oh, genotype hh sese) was recently determined in a systematic survey of more than 600,000 white individuals.</str>
      <str>With this survey used in conjunction with additional blood samples, the population frequency of nonfunctional alleles of the gene encoding the alpha (1,2)fucosyltransferase (H or FUT1) was determined.</str>
      <str>Seven different h alleles were found in five unrelated individuals, three of whom were homozygous for unique alleles. There was no prevalent h allele. Five missense and one frameshift mutations were observed, that were the presumptive causes of the null phenotype; the coding sequence of one h allele was identical to the H sequence. The average inbreeding factor alpha was 0.00116. The frequency of nonfunctional alleles at the H gene locus was calculated as 1 in 347 in a large white population (95% CI: 1:185-1:824).</str>
      <str>The Bombay blood group phenotype in white is due to diverse, sporadic, nonfunctional alleles without any prevalent allele. Assuming similar rates of nonfunctional alleles in glycosyltransferase genes like ABO, current genotyping strategies may fail as often as once in about 300 individuals of blood group O. Sporadic neutral alleles may also pose a serious obstacle for population-wide screening of many disease-associated genes.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Polymorphism of the h allele and the population frequency of sporadic nonfunctional alleles.</str>
    <str name="id">9122901</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Glycosylation of cell surface proteins is important in thymocyte maturation. In particular, the level of sialylation of key glycoproteins such as CD45 is believed to play a major role in regulating TCR signaling, adhesion and apoptosis of developing thymocytes. We show here that transgenic expression of human alpha1-2 fucosyltransferase (hFUT1) in mice resulted in a marked shift from sialylation to fucosylation of thymocyte glycoproteins. This was associated with a significant reduction in thymocyte number, an increased rate of apoptosis in double positive and single positive thymocytes, and a maturation arrest at TCR-dependent developmental transitions reminiscent of CD45 deficiency. Indeed, CD45RB dimerization was elevated in hFUT1 thymocytes, consistent with its hyposialylation, and there was a corresponding increase in phosphorylation of the TCR-associated protein Lck. However, contrary to the reduced TCR signaling in CD45 null mice, basal and stimulated TCR signaling was higher in hFUT1 thymocytes than in wild type thymocytes. Our results therefore demonstrate that aberrant expression of a single glycosyltransferase can profoundly affect thymopoiesis, although the relative involvement of CD45-dependent and -independent mechanisms is yet to be determined.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Glycosylation changes in hFUT1 transgenic mice increase TCR signaling and apoptosis resulting in thymocyte maturation arrest.</str>
    <str name="id">18155296</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>In a previous article, we demonstrated the existence of fucosyl-containing O-glycans forms of nucleolin in bovine post-capillary venular endothelial cells (CVEC) and malignant cultured human A431 cells. The tool for this discovery was an antibody found to interact strongly and exclusively with nucleolin in total protein extracts. The antibody was originally raised against a mollusc glycoprotein and was demonstrated to be directed against its O-glycans, recently found to belong prevalently to the blood group H-antigen type with fucose linked in alpha1, 2 to galactose. Here, we show that si-RNA induced down-regulation of the expression of FUT1 and FUT2, the fucosyltransferases required for the biosynthesis of the terminal glycan motif Fucalpha-2-Galbeta-R, reduced expression of the fucosylated nucleolin glycoforms and their exposure at the cell surface in CVEC. Treatment of the cells with FUT1/2 siRNA also reduced their ability to bind and internalize endostatin and their adhesion efficiency and inhibited cell growth. Expression of FUT1, FUT2, and FUT6 was also analyzed in serum-stimulated versus serum-starved cells and in cells treated with FUT1 and FUT2 siRNA. A reduced expression of fucosylated nucleolin and inhibition of cell growth by suppressing FUT1/2 expression was also tested and shown to be exhibited in human A431 cells.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">RNA-mediated gene silencing of FUT1 and FUT2 influences expression and activities of bovine and human fucosylated nucleolin and inhibits cell adhesion and proliferation.</str>
    <str name="id">20506485</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The penultimate step in the biosynthesis of the human ABO blood group oligosaccharide antigens is catalyzed by alpha-(1,2)-fucosyltransferase(s) (GDP-L-fucose: beta-D-galactoside 2-alpha-L-fucosyltransferase, EC 2.4.1.69), whose expression is determined by the H and Secretor (SE) blood group loci (also known as FUT1 and FUT2, respectively). These enzymes construct Fuc alpha 1--&gt;2Gal beta-linkages, known as H determinants, which are essential precursors to the A and B antigens. Erythrocytes from individuals with the rare Bombay and para-Bombay blood group phenotypes are deficient in H determinants, and thus A and B determinants, as a consequence of apparent homozygosity for null alleles at the H locus. We report a molecular analysis of a human alpha-(1,2)-fucosyltransferase gene, thought to correspond to the H blood group locus, in a Bombay pedigree and a para-Bombay pedigree. We find inactivating point mutations in the coding regions of both alleles of this gene in each H-deficient individual. These results define the molecular basis for H blood group antigen deficiency in Bombay and para-Bombay phenotypes, provide compelling evidence that this gene represents the human H blood group locus, and strongly support a hypothesis that the H and SE loci represent distinct alpha-(1,2)-fucosyltransferase genes. Candidate sequences for the human SE locus are identified by low-stringency Southern blot hybridization analyses, using a probe derived from the H alpha-(1,2)-fucosyltransferase gene.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Molecular basis for H blood group deficiency in Bombay (Oh) and para-Bombay individuals.</str>
    <str name="id">7912436</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Lewis Y (LeY) antigen is highly expressed in a variety of human carcinomas of epithelial cell origin. Recent studies suggest functional blockade of LeY may provide a novel therapeutic approach for the treatment of cancers. However, suppressing LeY expression by genetic manipulation and its impact on neoplastic cell proliferation has not been investigated. We report here that different fucosyltransferases (FUTs) were expressed with the greatest expression of fucosyltransferase I or IV (FUT1/4), the two key enzymes for the synthesis of LeY in human epidermoid carcinoma A431 cells. Knocking down FUT1/4 expression by short interfering RNA technique dramatically reduced the expression of FUT1/4 and LeY and inhibited cell proliferation through decreasing epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) signaling pathway. Treatment of A431 cells that were inoculated into the nude mice with FUT1 siRNA or FUT4 siRNA greatly impeded tumor growth. Suppressing FUT1/4 expression also blocked EGF-induced tyrosine phosphorylation of EGFR and mitogen-activated protein kinases. In conclusion, suppressing the expression of FUT1/4 by RNAi technology reduces the synthesis of LeY and inhibits cancer growth. It may serve as a potential methodology for the treatment of cancers that express LeY glycoconjugates.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Suppression of FUT1/FUT4 expression by siRNA inhibits tumor growth.</str>
    <str name="id">18023290</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>We have previously used a gene-transfer scheme to isolate a human genomic DNA fragment that determines expression of a GDP-L-fucose:beta-D-galactoside 2-alpha-L-fucosyltransferase [alpha(1,2)FT; EC 2.4.1.69]. Although this fragment determined expression of an alpha(1,2)FT whose kinetic properties mirror those of the human H blood group alpha(1,2)FT, their precise nature remained undefined. We describe here the molecular cloning, sequence, and expression of a human cDNA corresponding to these human genomic sequences. When expressed in COS-1 cells, this cDNA directs expression of cell surface H structures and a cognate alpha(1,2)FT activity with properties analogous to the human H blood group alpha(1,2)FT. The cDNA sequence predicts a 365-amino acid polypeptide characteristic of a type II transmembrane glycoprotein with a domain structure analogous to that of other glycosyltransferases but without significant primary sequence similarity to these or other known proteins. To directly demonstrate that the cDNA encodes an alpha(1,2)FT, the COOH-terminal domain predicted to be Golgi-resident was expressed in COS-1 cells as a catalytically active, secreted, and soluble protein A fusion peptide. Southern blot analysis showed that this cDNA identifies DNA sequences syntenic to the human H locus on chromosome 19. These results strongly suggest that this cloned alpha(1,2)FT cDNA represents the product of the human H blood group locus.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Molecular cloning, sequence, and expression of a human GDP-L-fucose:beta-D-galactoside 2-alpha-L-fucosyltransferase cDNA that can form the H blood group antigen.</str>
    <str name="id">2118655</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The para-Bombay phenotype (also known as H-deficient secretor) is characterized by a lack of ABH antigens on red cells, but ABH substances are found in saliva. Molecular genetic analysis was performed for five Chinese individuals serologically typed as para-Bombay.</str>
      <str>ABO genotyping and mutational analysis of both FUT1 (or H) and FUT2 (or Se) loci were performed for these individuals using the polymerase chain reaction, single-strand conformation polymorphism analysis and direct DNA sequencing.</str>
      <str>The ABO genotypes of these para-Bombay individuals correlated with the types of ABH substances found in the saliva. Their FUT1 genotypes were h1h2 (three individuals), h2h2 (one individual) and h2h6 (one individual). Alleles h1 (547-552delAG) and h2 (880-882delTT) were known frameshift mutations, while h6 (522C &gt; A) was a missense mutation (Phe174Leu) not previously reported. These three mutations were rare sequence variations, each with an allele frequency of less than 0.005. Phe174 might be functionally important because this residue is conserved from mouse to human. Their FUT2 genotypes were Se357se357,385 for the h2h6 individual and Se357Se357) for the others. Both FUT2 alleles were known: one functional (Se357) and one weakly functional (se357,385). That they carried at least one copy of a functional FUT2 allele was consistent with their secretor status. As FUT1 and FUT2 are adjacent on 19q13.3, there are three possible haplotypes in these para-Bombay individuals: h1-Se357; h2-Se357; and h6-se357,385.</str>
      <str>A novel non-functional FUT1 allele (522C &gt; A, or Phe174Leu) was identified in a para-Bombay individual and on a se357,385 haplotype background.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Molecular genetic analysis of para-Bombay phenotypes in Chinese: a novel non-functional FUT1 allele is identified.</str>
    <str name="id">12366770</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Recent studies have suggested that at least three transcription-initiation sites were present in the human H-type alpha(1,2)fucosyltransferase gene (FUT1). In the present study, we have investigated these transcription start sites of FUT1 in undifferentiated leukemic cells (K562) that have erythroid characteristics, in erythroleukemia cells (HEL), and in bone marrow cells. K562 cells used exclusively exon 1 as the start site. While HEL cells used mainly exon 2 as the start site, the major start site for bone marrow cells was within exon 7. In addition, we investigated the transcription start site(s) in vascular endothelial cells (ECV304) as an example of mature cells and found that the start site was predominantly within exon 7. The promoter activities were found in the 5' flanking regions of these three start sites after transfection of constructs with luciferase reporter gene into K562 and HEL cells. These findings suggested that the transcription start sites of FUT1 changed during differentiation of the erythroid lineage and that the tissue-specific and stage-specific expressions of the FUT1 were regulated by three distinct promoters. We also found that the 5' flanking region of exon 2 (intron 1) consisted of repetitive sequences (chromosome 19-specific 37-bp minisatellite repeats, Alu sequence and long terminal repeat) and that the start site of exon 2 was within the long terminal repeat. Thus, these repetitive sequences may play a role in the expression of the FUT1.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Changing transcription start sites in H-type alpha(1,2)fucosyltransferase gene (FUT1) during differentiation of the human erythroid lineage.</str>
    <str name="id">9760178</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To transfect human alpha1, 2-fucosyltransferase (alpha1, 2-FT) gene to ovarian cancer cell line RMG-I and investigate the antigenic expression change of Lewis y and the other related oligosaccharides.</str>
      <str>The expression vector pcDNA3.1(-)-HFUT-H was constructed by polymerase chain reaction (PCR) to clone human alpha1, 2-FT gene coding region. The alpha1, 2-FT gene stable high-expression cell line RMG-I-H was established by transfecting pcDNA3.1(-)-HFUT-H to ovarian cell line RMG-I. The change of alpha1, 2-FT activity in the cell line before and after the tranfection was confirmed by the determination of enzymatic activity. The changes of cell lipid and glucolipid, especially the change of type II oligosaccharide, in the cell line before and after the transfection was determined by Thin-Layer Chromatography (TLC) and TLC immunostaining method, respectively.</str>
      <str>The H-1 antigen and Lewis y antigen were obviously increased in the cell line RMG-1-H, especially the latter one, which was 20 times higher than before, and the type I saccharide chain Lewis b was decreased significantly. The main lipid components on the cell membrane, cholesterol and phosphatides, showed no change in the cell lines before and after the transfection, and the neutral glycolipid also showed no obvious change.</str>
      <str>The transfection of alpha1, 2-FT gene can increase the activity of alpha1, 2-FT in the cell line RMG-I and mainly increase the expression of Lewis y antigen simultaneously. The construction of RMG-I Lewis y high expression cell line provides a cell model for further study on the relationship between Lewis y antigen and biological behaviors in the ovarian cancer.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">[Transfection of alpha1, 2-fucosyltransferase gene increases the antigenic expression of Lewis y in ovarian cancer cell line RMG-I].</str>
    <str name="id">18686606</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Five on the seven cloned human fucosyltransferase genes have been mapped to two clusters, one on 19q and the other on 19p. Comparative DNA sequence analysis showed the Généthon microsatellite D19S596 lies 2.2 kb downstream of the coding region of FUT1, indicating that the cluster comprising the closely linked FUT1 and FUT2 genes is located 4 cM distal to D19S412 (lod score 13.7) and 9 cM proximal to D19S571 (lod score 11.7). Polymorphic markers of FUT3, FUT5, and FUT6 were used for linkage analysis with 14 Généthon microsatellites in Indonesian families. These three loci constitute a cluster on 19p, located between the Généthon microsatellites D19S216 and D19S567, which are known to be only 1 cM distant from each other. Two cross-overs, one between FUT6 and FUT3 and the other between FUT3 and FUT5, suggest the gene order 19pter-D19S216-FUT6-FUT3-FUT5-D19S567++ +-cen. Comparison of genetic and physical maps suggests that the FUT6-FUT3-FUT5 cluster is located on 19p13.3 and the FUT1-FUT2 cluster on 19q13.3. FUT6, FUT3 and FUT5 genes share more than 85% homology and encode three similar, but distinct alpha(1,3) fucosyltransferases. FUT1 and FUT2 share about 70% homology and encode two distinct alpha(1,2)fucosyltransferases. No sequence homology was found between the genes of the two clusters. The members of each of these two clusters have probably emerged by duplication and divergent evolution of two unrelated ancestor genes.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Relative positions of two clusters of human alpha-L-fucosyltransferases in 19q (FUT1-FUT2) and 19p (FUT6-FUT3-FUT5) within the microsatellite genetic map of chromosome 19.</str>
    <str name="id">7656588</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The whole genome approach enables the characterization of all components of any given biological pathway. Moreover, it can help to uncover all the metabolic routes for any molecule. Here we have used the genome of Drosophila melanogaster to search for enzymes involved in the metabolism of fucosylated glycans. Our results suggest that in the fruit fly GDP-fucose, the donor for fucosyltransferase reactions, is formed exclusively via the de novo pathway from GDP-mannose through enzymatic reactions catalyzed by GDP-D-mannose 4,6-dehydratase (GMD) and GDP-4-keto-6-deoxy-D-mannose 3,5-epimerase/4-reductase (GMER, also known as FX in man). The Drosophila genome does not have orthologs for the salvage pathway enzymes, i.e. fucokinase and GDP-fucose pyrophosphorylase synthesizing GDP-fucose from fucose. In addition we identified two novel fucosyltransferases predicted to catalyze alpha1,3- and alpha1,6-specific linkages to the GlcNAc residues on glycans. No genes with the capacity to encode alpha1,2-specific fucosyltransferases were found. We also identified two novel genes coding for O-fucosyltransferases and a gene responsible for a fucosidase enzyme in the Drosophila genome. Finally, using the Drosophila CG4435 gene, we identified two novel human genes putatively coding for fucosyltransferases. This work can serve as a basis for further whole-genome approaches in mapping all possible glycosylation pathways and as a basic analysis leading to subsequent experimental studies to verify the predictions made in this work.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Composition of Drosophila melanogaster proteome involved in fucosylated glycan metabolism.</str>
    <str name="id">11698403</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>During the initiation of tumor associated angiogenesis endothelial cells migrate, adhere to extracellular matrix and form cell-cell contacts. Humoral factors of malignant cells conduct this process. We investigated whether cell surface expression of the carbohydrate blood group determinant Lewis(y) (CD174) and its precursor structure H2 (CD173) on endothelial cells is influenced by soluble factors of tumor cells. Using a bone marrow derived endothelial cell line we observed an enhanced expression of CD173/CD174 and transcription of FUT1, the key enzyme for their synthesis, after treatment with tumor necrosis factor-alpha (TNF-alpha) or conditioned supernatants of the leukemia cell line KG1a. CD173/CD174 are concentrated on pseudopodial extensions responsible for initial contacts between endothelial cells. Endothelial migration induced by TNF-alpha could be diminished by antibodies to CD174 as well as by siRNA induced downmodulation of FUT1 transcription. Endothelial FUT1-siRNA-transfectants displayed impaired in vitro angiogenesis when cultivated on extracellular matrix and in spheroid assays. In vivo upregulation of CD174 expression was observed immunocytologically in capillaries of tumor-infiltrated tissue. Together, our observations point to a tumor induced transcription of endothelial FUT1 and consequently an enhanced expression of CD174 which is involved in migration and early cell-cell contacts during tumor associated angiogenesis.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Involvement of alpha 1-2-fucosyltransferase I (FUT1) and surface-expressed Lewis(y) (CD174) in first endothelial cell-cell contacts during angiogenesis.</str>
    <str name="id">18205178</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To explore the effect of alpha1,2-fucosyltransferase (alpha1,2-FT) gene on the biological behavior of ovarian carcinoma cells, the expression vector pcDNA3.1 -HFUT-H which containing human alpha1,2-FT gene coding region was constructed and transfected into ovarian carcinoma cell line RMG-I. alpha1,2-FT gene expression, Lewis y antigen expression, alpha1,2-FT activity, rates of cell growth and tumorogenesis in nude mice were compared before and after RMG-I being transfected. The transfection of alpha1,2-FT gene significantly increased the expression of alpha1,2-FT gene and Lewis y antigen in RMG-I cells. After the transfection, RMG-I cells showed remarkable improvement of alpha1,2-FT activity, cell proliferation, the ability of colony formation in soft agar and tumorogenesis in nude mice. The growth rates of alpha1,2-FT gene transfected RMG-I cells were obviously increased, presenting that the proportion of the cells in G2-M and S phases was obviously increased from 2.05% to 7.32% and from 23.95% to 33.27% respectively, and that of the cells in G1 phase was obviously decreased from 74.14% to 59.46%, as compared with the control group. These findings indicate that alpha1,2-FT and Lewis y antigen have the ability to enhance the proliferation and elevate the survival rates of RMG-I cells, which can promote the genesis and development of ovarian carcinoma.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">[alpha1,2-fucosyltransferase gene transfection influences on biological behavior of ovarian carcinoma-derived RMG-I cells].</str>
    <str name="id">19137814</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>We previously reported that sialyl Lewis(y), synthesized by fucosyltransferases, is involved in angiogenesis. Fucosyltransferase 1 (fut1) is an α(1,2)-fucosyltransferase responsible for synthesis of the H blood group and Lewis(y) antigens. However, the angiogenic involvement of fut 1 in the pathogenesis of rheumatoid arthritis synovial tissue (RA ST) has not been clearly defined.</str>
      <str>Assay of α(1,2)-linked fucosylated proteins in RA was performed by enzyme-linked lectin assay. Fut1 expression was determined in RA ST samples by immunohistological staining. We performed angiogenic Matrigel assays using a co-culture system of human dermal microvascular endothelial cells (HMVECs) and fut1 small interfering RNA (siRNA) transfected RA synovial fibroblasts. To determine if fut1 played a role in leukocyte retention and cell proliferation in the RA synovium, myeloid THP-1 cell adhesion assays and fut1 siRNA transfected RA synovial fibroblast proliferation assays were performed.</str>
      <str>Total α(1,2)-linked fucosylated proteins in RA ST were significantly higher compared to normal (NL) ST. Fut1 expression on RA ST lining cells positively correlated with ST inflammation. HMVECs from a co-culture system with fut1 siRNA transfected RA synovial fibroblasts exhibited decreased endothelial cell tube formation compared to control siRNA transfected RA synovial fibroblasts. Fut1 siRNA also inhibited myeloid THP-1 adhesion to RA synovial fibroblasts and RA synovial fibroblast proliferation.</str>
      <str>These data show that α(1,2)-linked fucosylated proteins are upregulated in RA ST compared to NL ST. We also show that fut1 in RA synovial fibroblasts is important in angiogenesis, leukocyte-synovial fibroblast adhesion, and synovial fibroblast proliferation, all key processes in the pathogenesis of RA.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Fucosyltransferase 1 mediates angiogenesis, cell adhesion and rheumatoid arthritis synovial tissue fibroblast proliferation.</str>
    <str name="id">24467809</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The strong observational association between total homocysteine (tHcy) concentrations and risk of coronary artery disease (CAD) and the null associations in the homocysteine-lowering trials have prompted the need to identify genetic variants associated with homocysteine concentrations and risk of CAD.</str>
      <str>We tested whether common genetic polymorphisms associated with variation in tHcy are also associated with CAD.</str>
      <str>We conducted a meta-analysis of genome-wide association studies (GWAS) on tHcy concentrations in 44,147 individuals of European descent. Polymorphisms associated with tHcy (P &lt; 10(⁻⁸) were tested for association with CAD in 31,400 cases and 92,927 controls.</str>
      <str>Common variants at 13 loci, explaining 5.9% of the variation in tHcy, were associated with tHcy concentrations, including 6 novel loci in or near MMACHC (2.1 × 10⁻⁹), SLC17A3 (1.0 × 10⁻⁸), GTPB10 (1.7 × 10⁻⁸), CUBN (7.5 × 10⁻¹⁰), HNF1A (1.2 × 10⁻¹²)), and FUT2 (6.6 × 10⁻⁹), and variants previously reported at or near the MTHFR, MTR, CPS1, MUT, NOX4, DPEP1, and CBS genes. Individuals within the highest 10% of the genotype risk score (GRS) had 3-μmol/L higher mean tHcy concentrations than did those within the lowest 10% of the GRS (P = 1 × 10⁻³⁶). The GRS was not associated with risk of CAD (OR: 1.01; 95% CI: 0.98, 1.04; P = 0.49).</str>
      <str>We identified several novel loci that influence plasma tHcy concentrations. Overall, common genetic variants that influence plasma tHcy concentrations are not associated with risk of CAD in white populations, which further refutes the causal relevance of moderately elevated tHcy concentrations and tHcy-related pathways for CAD.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Common genetic loci influencing plasma homocysteine concentrations and their effect on risk of coronary artery disease.</str>
    <str name="id">23824729</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Angiogenesis contributes to the pathogenesis of rheumatoid arthritis. Fucosyltransferases (Futs) are involved in angiogenesis and tumour growth. Here, we examined the role of Fut1 in angiogenesis and K/BxN serum transfer arthritis.</str>
      <str>We examined Fut1 expression in human dermal microvascular endothelial cells (HMVECs) by quantitative PCR. We performed a number of angiogenesis assays to determine the role of Fut1 using HMVECs, Fut1 null (Fut1(-/-)), and wild type (wt) endothelial cells (ECs) and mice. K/BxN serum transfer arthritis was performed to determine the contribution of Fut1-mediated angiogenesis in Fut1(-/-) and wt mice. A static adhesion assay was implemented with RAW264.7 (mouse macrophage cell line) and mouse ECs. Quantitative PCR, immunofluorescence and flow cytometry were performed with Fut1(-/-) and wt ECs for adhesion molecule expression.</str>
      <str>Tumour necrosis factor-α induced Fut1 mRNA and protein expression in HMVECs. HMVECs transfected with Fut1 antisense oligodeoxynucleotide and Fut1(-/-) ECs formed significantly fewer tubes on Matrigel. Fut1(-/-) mice had reduced angiogenesis in Matrigel plug and sponge granuloma angiogenesis assays compared with wt mice. Fut1(-/-) mice were resistant to K/BxN serum transfer arthritis and had decreased angiogenesis and leucocyte ingress into inflamed joints. Adhesion of RAW264.7 cells to wt mouse ECs was significantly reduced when Fut1 was lacking. Fut1(-/-) ECs had decreased intercellular adhesion molecule-1 (ICAM-1) expression at mRNA and protein levels compared with wt ECs. ICAM-1 was also decreased in Fut1(-/-) arthritic ankle cryosections compared with wt ankles.</str>
      <str>Fut1 plays an important role in regulating angiogenesis and ICAM-1 expression in inflammatory arthritis.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">A key role for Fut1-regulated angiogenesis and ICAM-1 expression in K/BxN arthritis.</str>
    <str name="id">24665114</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The reason why delayed RBC engraftment and pure red cell aplasia (PRCA) develop only in some but not all recipients of major ABO-incompatible hematopoietic stem cell transplantation (HSCT) remains elusive and the underlying mechanisms are not fully understood. Understanding how incompatible erythroid blood group antibodies (Abs) interact with ABH antigens (Ags) of grafts, and investigating how to induce artificially accommodation of grafts are of obvious importance in transplantation immunology. The effects of anti-H on proliferation, apoptosis, and α-(1,2)-fucosyltransferase gene (FUT1) expression in erythroid differentiated K562 cells were analyzed by the MTT assay, Annexin V/PI staining, and quantitative RT-PCR method. The growth of erythroid differentiated K562 cells was significantly suppressed when anti-H dilution was ≤ 1:8 (P&lt;0.001, as compared with 1:16). Under the complement-free culture conditions, the apoptotic ratio of erythroid differentiated K562 cells was significantly increased when anti-H dilution was ≤ 1:16 (P&lt;0.05, as compared with 1:32). The apoptosis was not only closely associated with anti-H dilution (F=138.991, P&lt;0.001), but also correlated with treated time (F=583.249, P&lt;0.001), which indicated typical dose- and time-dependent effects. Under the complement-free culture conditions, the FUT1 mRNA expression level was also suppressed when anti-H dilution was ≤ 1:16 (P&lt;0.05, as compared with 1:32), which also manifested in typical dose-dependent (F=130.356, P&lt;0.001) and time-dependent (F=1432.00, P&lt;0.001) effects. The results confirm that anti-H can trigger apoptosis and down-regulate FUT1 expression in erythroid differentiated K562 cells without complement mediation. The findings suggest that anti-H could accommodate grafts through triggering apoptosis and down-regulating Fut1 expression to reduce ABH antigens.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Anti-H can trigger apoptosis and down-regulate FUT1 expression in erythroid differentiated K562 cells without complement mediation.</str>
    <str name="id">23063462</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>This is a study on the allele composing of ABO, FUT1 and FUT2 gene loci of 10 para-Bombay individuals in China.</str>
      <str>Ten samples coming from different districts of China were suspected of para-Bombay phenotype by primary serology tests. Routine and absorb-elution tests were conducted to identify their ABO type, and duplex polymerase chain reaction-restriction fragment length polymorphism (PCR-RFLP) was applied to getting their ABO genotype. Most of them were submitted to a test of their Lewis type as well. Then through direct DNA sequencing with PCR products of FUT1 and FUT2 genes, the genotypes of their H and SE gene loci were analyzed.</str>
      <str>It can be confirmed that the 10 samples are para-Bombay. All of their ABO genotypes are consistent with the serological absorb-elution results and the substances detected results in saliva. Seven out of 10 have recessive homozygous gene at their H locus. Each phenotype of h1h1 (nt547-552Deltaag), h2h2 (nt880-882Deltatt) and h4h4 (nt35 t--&gt;c) are ascertained in 2 individuals; moreover, h3h3 (nt 658 c--&gt;t) is identified in one individual. The rest are hh heterozygous individuals: one is h3/h(new-1); the other is h2/h(new-2); the last one is h1/h2. The h(new-1) (nt586 c--&gt;t) allele has a point mutation at nt 586 C to T, which leads a nonsense mutation Gln(CAG) to stop (TAG).The second h (new-2) (nt328 g--&gt;a) has an nt328 G to A missense mutation,which leads Ala (GCC),was replaced by Thr (ACC) at 110 amino acid position. All the 10 samples have Se (nt357 c--&gt;t) synonymous mutation. One Bm(h) (B/O) individual with h4h4 phenotype has a Se(w)(nt357 c--&gt;t; nt385 a--&gt;t) allele, whose Lewis type is Le(a+b+). Moreover, the authors detected a (nt716 g--&gt;a) mutation in two samples' Se gene.</str>
      <str>Four kinds of known h alleles (h1-h4), 2 kinds of novel non-functional FUT1 alleles, a Se(w) allele, and a novel SeG716A polymorphism in Chinese para-Bombay individuals were detected. At the same time, the authors noticed that all the 10 samples have the nt357 c--&gt;t mutation in their FUT2 gene.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">[Analysis on FUT1 and FUT2 gene of 10 para-Bombay individuals in China].</str>
    <str name="id">15476160</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Alpha(1,2)-fucosyltransferase catalyzes the transfer of fucose to the C-2 position of galactose on type II precursor substrate Gal beta1-4GlcNAc beta1-R. It plays an important biological role in the formation of H antigen, a precursor oligosaccharide for both A and B antigens on red blood cells. Aberration of alpha(1,2)-fucosyltransferase activity by gene mutations results in decreased synthesis of H antigen, leading to the para-Bombay phenotype. In this study, we collected about 250,000 blood samples in Taiwan during 5 yr and identified the subjects with para-Bombay phenotype. Then we analyzed the sequence of the alpha(1,2)-fucosyltransferase gene by direct sequencing and gene cloning methods, using the blood samples of 30 para-Bombay individuals and 30 control subjects who were randomly selected. The goals of this study were to search for new h alleles, to determine the h allele frequencies, and to test whether the sporadic theory is applicable in Taiwan. Six different h alleles (ha, 547-548 AG-del; hb, 880-881 TT-del; hc, R220C; hd, R220H; he, F174L; and hf, N327T) were observed. Two h alleles, he and hf, were newly discovered in Taiwan. The he allele has a nucleotide 522C&gt;A point mutation, predicting the amino acid 174 substitution of Phe to Leu; the hf allele has missense mutation of nucleotide 980A&gt;C, predicting the amino acid 327 substitution of Asn to Thr. Frequencies of the 6 alleles are ha 46.67%, hb 38.33%, hc 5.00%, hd 1.67%, he 3.33%, and hf 5.00%, respectively. These findings in the Taiwanese population confirm previous observations in other populations that the Bombay and para-Bombay phenotypes are due to diverse, sporadic, nonfunctional alleles, predominantly ha and hb, leading to H deficiency of red blood cells. In contrast to previous reports of non-prevalent associations of h alleles with para-Bombay phenotype, our results suggest a regional allele preference associated with para-Bombay individuals in Taiwan.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Two prevalent h alleles in para-Bombay haplotypes among 250,000 Taiwanese.</str>
    <str name="id">15487706</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To establish the eukaryotic cell expression system for the alpha-1,2 fucosyltransferase gene FUT1 293C to T and 658C to T mutations and explore the mechanism of FUT1 mutations resulting in the reduced expression of H antigen.</str>
      <str>Genomic DNAs were extracted from individuals with para-Bombay phenotype and full coding region of FUT1 was amplified. The amplification fragments were ligated with pcDNA3.1 plasmid to construct the recombinant expression vectors. The recombinant plasmids were transfected into the COS-7 cells using lipofectamine transfection reagent and stable expression screening was performed. FUT1 mRNA expression was determined by real-time quantitative PCR. The activity of enzyme was measured by high performance liquid chromatography. Expressed protein was identified by SDS-PAGE and Western blotting.</str>
      <str>pcDNA3.1-FUT1 wildtype, pcDNA3.1-FUT1 293C to T and pcDNA3.1-FUT1 658C to T recombinant vectors were constructed, respectively. COS-7 cells with stable expression of FUT1 were obtained through recombinant plasmid transfection and screening with G418. The FUT1 mRNA level of transfected cells with 293C to T and 658C to T recombinant vectors reached 97.10% and 104.74% of the wildtype FUT1 transfected cell. A specific protein band with about 46 000 was confirmed in the transfected cell lysates by SDS-PAGE electrophoresis and Western blotting with 6×His Tag antibody. The wildtype FUT1 transfected cell lysates can catalyze the enzymatic reaction, while the enzyme activity of cell lysates from 293C to T and 658C to T were abolished.</str>
      <str>The results suggested that the 293C to T and 658C to T mutations of FUT1 gene did not affect the RNA and protein expression levels, but the enzyme activity of cells with FUT1 mutations was significantly decreased which resulted in the reduced expressin of H antigen.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">[Study on the expression stability of mutant alpha-1,2 fucosyltransferase gene 293C to T and 658C to T in eukaryotic cells].</str>
    <str name="id">21983725</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Serum carcinoembryonic antigen (sCEA) level might be an indicator of disease. Indeed, an elevated sCEA level is a prognostic factor in colorectal cancer (CRC) patients. However, the genetic determinants of sCEA level in healthy and CRC population remains unclear. Thus we investigated the genetic markers associated with elevated serum sCEA level in these two populations and its clinical implications.</str>
      <str>Genome-wide association study (GWAS) was conducted in a cohort study with 4,346 healthy male adults using the Illumina Omni 1 M chip. Candidate SNPs associated with elevated sCEA levels were validated in 194 CRC patients on ABI Taqman platform. Eight candidate SNPs were validated in CRC patients. The rs1047781 (chr19- FUT2) (A/T) was associated with elevated sCEA levels, and rs8176746 (chr9- ABO) was associated with the regional lymph metastasis in the CRC patients. The preoperative sCEA level was a risk factor for tumor recurrence in 5 years after operation (OR = 1.427, 95% CI: 1.005∼1.843, P = 0.006). It was also one of the risk factors for regional lymph node metastasis (OR = 2.266, 95% CI: 1.196∼4.293, P = 0.012). The sCEA level in rs1047781-T carriers was higher than that in the A carriers in CRC patients without lymph node metastasis (P = 0.006). The regional lymph node metastasis in patients with homozygote AA of rs8176746 was more common than that in the heterozygote AG carriers (P = 0.022). In addition, rs1047781-AT and TT CRC patients exhibited a worse disease-free survival than AA genotype carriers (P = 0.023).</str>
      <str>We found candidate SNPs associated with elevated sCEA levels in both healthy males and CRC population. Rs1047781 (chr19- FUT2) may be the susceptible locus for recurrence of CRC in a population from Southern China.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Genetic variations affecting serum carcinoembryonic antigen levels and status of regional lymph nodes in patients with sporadic colorectal cancer from Southern China.</str>
    <str name="id">24941225</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>There is increasing evidence that the microcirculation plays an important role in the pathogenesis of cardiovascular diseases. Changes in retinal vascular caliber reflect early microvascular disease and predict incident cardiovascular events. We performed a genome-wide association study to identify genetic variants associated with retinal vascular caliber. We analyzed data from four population-based discovery cohorts with 15,358 unrelated Caucasian individuals, who are members of the Cohort for Heart and Aging Research in Genomic Epidemiology (CHARGE) consortium, and replicated findings in four independent Caucasian cohorts (n  =  6,652). All participants had retinal photography and retinal arteriolar and venular caliber measured from computer software. In the discovery cohorts, 179 single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNP) spread across five loci were significantly associated (p&lt;5.0×10(-8)) with retinal venular caliber, but none showed association with arteriolar caliber. Collectively, these five loci explain 1.0%-3.2% of the variation in retinal venular caliber. Four out of these five loci were confirmed in independent replication samples. In the combined analyses, the top SNPs at each locus were: rs2287921 (19q13; p  =  1.61×10(-25), within the RASIP1 locus), rs225717 (6q24; p = 1.25×10(-16), adjacent to the VTA1 and NMBR loci), rs10774625 (12q24; p  =  2.15×10(-13), in the region of ATXN2,SH2B3 and PTPN11 loci), and rs17421627 (5q14; p = 7.32×10(-16), adjacent to the MEF2C locus). In two independent samples, locus 12q24 was also associated with coronary heart disease and hypertension. Our population-based genome-wide association study demonstrates four novel loci associated with retinal venular caliber, an endophenotype of the microcirculation associated with clinical cardiovascular disease. These data provide further insights into the contribution and biological mechanisms of microcirculatory changes that underlie cardiovascular disease.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Four novel Loci (19q13, 6q24, 12q24, and 5q14) influence the microcirculation in vivo.</str>
    <str name="id">21060863</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The H genes, encoding an alpha1,2fucosyltransferase, which defines blood groups with the H structure, of four Bombay and 13 para-Bombay Japanese individuals were analyzed for mutations. Four Bombay individuals were homologous for the same null H allele, which is inactivated by a single nonsense mutation at position 695 from G to A (G695A), resulting in termination of H gene translation. The allele inactivated by the G695A was designated h1. The other 13 para-Bombay individuals possessed a trace amount of H antigens on erythrocytes regardless of their secretor status. Sequence analysis of their H genes showed four additional inactivated H gene alleles, h2, h3, h4, and h5. The h2 allele possesed a single base deletion at position 990 G (990-del). The h3 and h4 alleles possessed a single missense mutation, T721C, which changes Tyr 241 to His, and G442T, which changes Asp148 to Tyr, respectively. The h5 allele possessed two missense mutations, T460C (Tyr154to His) and G1042A (Glu348to Lys). The h2, h3, h4, and h5 enzymes directed by these alleles were not fully inactivated by the deletion and the missense mutations expressing some residual enzyme activity resulting in synthesis of H antigen on erythrocytes. Thirteen para-Bombay individuals whose erythrocytes retained a trace amount of H antigen were determined to be heterozygous or homozygous for at least one of h2, h3, h4, or h5 alleles. This clarified that the levels (null to trace amount) of H antigen expression on erythrocytes of Bombay and para-Bombay individuals are determined solely by H enzyme activity. These mutations found in the Japanese H alleles differ from a nonsense mutation found in the Indonesian population. To determine the roles of the H, Se, and Le genes in the expression of H antigen in secretions and Lewis blood group antigen on erythrocytes, the Lewis and secretor genes were also examined in these Bombay and para-Bombay individuals. The Lewis blood group phenotype, Le(alpha- b+), was determined by the combinatorial activity of two fucosyltransferases, the Lewis enzyme and the secretor enzyme, and the secretor status was solely determined by the secretor enzyme activity, not by H enzyme activity. Bombay individuals were confirmed to be homozygous for the inactivated H and Se genes. As expected from the very low frequency of Bombay and para-Bombay individuals in the population, ie, approximately one in two or 300,000, the H gene mutations were found to be very variable, unlike the cases of the point mutations in the other glycosyltransferase genes; the ABO genes, the Lewis gene, and the secretor gene.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Wide variety of point mutations in the H gene of Bombay and para-Bombay individuals that inactivate H enzyme.</str>
    <str name="id">9226185</str></doc>
</result>
</response>
