<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<response>

<lst name="responseHeader">
  <int name="status">0</int>
  <int name="QTime">0</int>
  <lst name="params">
    <str name="q">*:*
1763885
9299444
17459061
16331565
9745152
24527852
19572973
17922418
23533340
12652076
9054453
9122901
7912436
2118655
12366770
24467809
15476160
15487706
21983725
9226185</str>
    <str name="indent">true</str>
    <str name="fl">id, medline_abstract_text, medline_article_title</str>
    <str name="rows">100</str>
    <str name="wt">xml</str>
  </lst>
</lst>
<result name="response" numFound="24797215" start="0">
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Families segregating for deficiency of the H alpha-2-L-fucosyltransferase, FUT1, have been investigated for linkage between FUT1 and other markers on chromosome 19. The results provide evidence for close linkage between FUT1 and FUT2 and for looser linkage between FUT1 and APOC2 and between FUT1 and D19S7. Pairwise linkage data are also reported between other markers investigated.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The human chromosome 19 linkage group FUT1 (H), FUT2 (SE), LE, LU, PEPD, C3, APOC2, D19S7 and D19S9.</str>
    <str name="id">1763885</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The Bombay phenotype fails to express the ABH antigens of ABO blood group system on red blood cells and in secretions because of a lack in activities of the H gene (FUT1)- and Secretor gene (FUT2)-encoded alpha (1,2)fucosyltransferases. In this study, we have examined the FUT1 and the FUT2 from three unrelated Indian individuals with the Bombay phenotype. These three individuals were found to be homozygous for a T725G mutation in the coding region of the FUT1, which inactivated the enzyme activity. In addition, we did not detect any hybridized band corresponding to the FUT2 by Southern blot analysis using the catalytic domain of the FUT2 as a probe, indicating that the three individuals were homozygous for a gene deletion in the FUT2. These results suggest that the T725G mutation of FUT1 and the gene deletion of FUT2 are responsible for the classical Indian Bombay phenotype.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Missense mutation of FUT1 and deletion of FUT2 are responsible for Indian Bombay phenotype of ABO blood group system.</str>
    <str name="id">9299444</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Lewis antigens are terminal fucosylated oligosaccharides synthesized by the sequential action of several glycosyltransferases. The fucosyltransferases are the enzymes responsible for the addition of terminal fucose to precursor oligosaccharides attached to proteins or lipids. These oligosaccharides, defined as cell surface markers, have been implicated in different types of intercellular interactions and in adhesion and invasion processes. Transfection of HT-29/M3 colon cancer cells with the full length of human fucosyltransferase (FUT1), induces the synthesis of H type 2 and Lewis y antigens, associated with a decrease of sialyl-Lewis x. The capacity to develop primary tumors when cells were injected intrasplenically was similar in parental and FUT1-transfected cells, but the capacity to colonize the liver after spleen removal was significantly reduced in M3/FUT1 transfected cells. These results indicate that the expression of FUT1 induces changes in the metastatic capacity of HT-29/M3 colon cancer cells, as a consequence of the altered expression pattern of type 2 Lewis antigens. Also, an association between MUC5AC expression and the degree of gland differentiation in both primary splenic tumors and hepatic metastases was detected.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Changes in the invasive and metastatic capacities of HT-29/M3 cells induced by the expression of fucosyltransferase 1.</str>
    <str name="id">17459061</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To investigate the h4 allele (C35T) frequency of alpha-1,2-fucosyltransferase gene in Chinese population.</str>
      <str>The polymerase chain reaction-restriction fragment length polymorphism (PCR-RFLP) method for identifying C35T variant was established by using PCR to amplify a 125 bp FUT1 gene fragment, including C35T variant sequence, and the PCR product was digested by Hae III restriction enzyme. One hundred and fifty-eight random samples from Chinese blood donor were screened by PCR-RFLP.</str>
      <str>Among 158 Chinese individuals with normal ABO and H blood group phenotypes, 8 and 83 were homozygous with 35T/T and 35C/C, respectively, while 67 were heterozygous with 35C/T. The allele frequencies were compatible with Hardy-Weinberg equilibrium.</str>
      <str>The C35T substitution of FUT1 gene is not a mutation which gives rise to a non-functional h allele responsible for para-Bombay phenotype but a single nucleotide polymorphism in Chinese population.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">[Study on the frequency of alpha-1,2-fucosyltransferase gene h4 allele (C35T) in Chinese population].</str>
    <str name="id">16331565</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Definition of the molecular basis of the Reunion and the Bombay red cell and salivary H-deficient phenotypes.</str>
      <str>Sequence and expression of FUT1 and FUT2 genes from H-deficient individuals. Family segregation analysis of the mutations responsible for the fucosyltransferase defects of H, secretor and Lewis systems.</str>
      <str>The Indian red cell H null Bombay phenotype depends on a new mutation of the FUT1 gene. T725--&gt;G changing Leu242--&gt;Arg. Their salivary nonsecretor phenotype is secondary to a complete deletion of the FUT2 gene. The red cell H weak Reunion phenotype depends on another new mutation of FUT1, C349--&gt;T which induces a change of His117--&gt;Tyr. Their salivary nonsecretor phenotype is due to the known Caucasian inactivating mutation G428--&gt;A.</str>
      <str>Single prevalent FUT1 and FUT2 point mutations and a deletion are responsible for the Indian Bombay H null and the Reunion H weak phenotypes found on Reunion island. This is in contrast with other H-deficient phenotypes where sporadic nonprevalent inactivating mutations are the rule.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Point mutations and deletion responsible for the Bombay H null and the Reunion H weak blood groups.</str>
    <str name="id">9745152</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The α(1,2)-fucosyltransferase gene 1 (FUT1) and 2 (FUT2), respectively, regulate H antigen synthesis in red blood cells and body fluids. Genetic polymorphisms of FUT1 and FUT2 are ethnically and geographically specific.</str>
      <str>Healthy unrelated Tibetan blood donors (n = 200) from the Tibet Autonomous Region of China were recruited for this study. The entire FUT1 and FUT2 coding regions were amplified and sequenced. The haplotypes including novel single-nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) were determined by clone sequencing.</str>
      <str>In Tibetans, the major FUT1 allele was wild-type allele with a frequency of 97.75%. One novel FUT1 allele was defined by a novel synonymous mutation (846T&gt;G). The two most common FUT2 alleles were functional allele Se(357) with a frequency of 32.75% and nonfunctional allele se(357,385) with a frequency of 55%. Two new FUT2 alleles were found at low frequency. They were characterized by two novel SNPs on the basis of se(357,385) : 617 T&gt;G (V206G) and 841 G&gt;A (G281R).</str>
      <str>Three new alleles in FUT1 and FUT2 genes were identified in the study. The allelic polymorphisms of FUT1 and FUT2 in Tibetans show a population-specific manner.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Sequence analysis of the human fucosyltransferase 1 and 2 genes in Tibetan blood donors: identification of three novel alleles.</str>
    <str name="id">24527852</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Genes for fucosyltransferases 1 (FUT1:H), 2 (FUT2:Secretor), and 3 (FUT3:Lewis) encode enzymes crucial for ABH and Lewis blood group antigen synthesis. They are highly polymorphic and ethnically and geographically specific.</str>
      <str>Genetic variations and allele frequencies of FUT1, FUT2, and FUT3 encoding regions and flanking sequences were analyzed in 100 Styrian blood donors by systematic sequencing. Haplotypes were verified with sequence-specific primers. To identify discrepancies, serologically determined ABO and Lewis blood groups were correlated to respective genotypes.</str>
      <str>Two novel FUT1 alleles were defined by 9C&gt;T (silent) and 991C&gt;A (P331T) mutations, the latter located in the catalytic domain of the enzyme. Five new alleles of FUT2 were found: three were characterized by new variants and two resulted from new combinations of known polymorphisms. The new 412G&gt;A (G138S) mutation also is located in the catalytic domain. A new nonsecretor allele, based on the presence of 428G&gt;A (nonsense), was found. Another FUT2 allele may have resulted from an intragenic crossover event. FUT3 analysis revealed seven novel alleles, partly based on the new mutations 41G&gt;A (R14H), 1060C&gt;G (R354G), 735G&gt;C (silent), and 882C&gt;T (silent). While 41G&gt;A is placed in the cytoplasmic domain and functional, 1060C&gt;G is placed in the catalytic domain.</str>
      <str>Multiple common and sporadic sequence variations including 14 new alleles at FUT1, FUT2, and FUT3 loci were identified. Four novel mutations result in amino acid substitution in the protein. Three of them are predicted to have adverse effects on the enzyme activity. A novel nonsecretor allele was found.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Identification of 14 new alleles at the fucosyltransferase 1, 2, and 3 loci in Styrian blood donors, Austria.</str>
    <str name="id">19572973</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Molecular genetic analysis of FUT1 and FUT2 gene was performed for seven Chinese Han individuals serologically typed as para-Bombay.</str>
      <str>Seven DNA samples were studied by polymerase chain reaction and then by direct sequencing. Molecular cloning sequencing was done for an individual with a novel FUT1 allele. Family segregation analysis of the novel FUT1 allele was done to explore whether the allele was responsible for the fucosyltransferase defects of H.</str>
      <str>The FUT1 genotypes of seven para-Bombay individuals were h1h1 (four individuals), h2h2 (two individuals), h328hnew (one individual), alleles h1 lost one of the three AG repeats located at the nucleotides 547-552 of the FUT1 gene, h2 lost two of the three T repeats located at the nucleotides 880-882, h328 (nt328G&gt;A) was a missense mutation, all of them were known mutations, while allele hnew deleted GGTATTCCGCATCACCCTGCCCGTGCTGGCCCC at nt360-400, total 33 bases, and the frame-shift mutation was not previously reported. The segregation of the hnew allele in his family showed that his father genotype was Hh328, and his mother was Hhnew, while two brother were h328hnew. The FUT2 genotypes of seven para-Bombay individuals were Se357 Se357 (three individuals), Se357 Se357,385 (three individuals), Se357,716Se357,716(one individual), the functional Se357(nt357C&gt;T), Se716(nt716G&gt;A) and the weakly functional Se385(nt385A&gt;T) were known. The seven para-Bombay individuals carried at least one copy of a functional FUT2 allele was consistent with their secretor status.</str>
      <str>A novel FUT1 allele was identified in a para-Bombay Chinese individual, which was responsible for the inactivation of the FUT1-encoded enzyme activity.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">[Molecular genetic analysis of FUT1 and FUT2 gene in para-Bombay Chinese: a novel FUT1 allele is identified].</str>
    <str name="id">17922418</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The α 1,2-fucosyltransferase I (FUT1) enzyme is important for the biosynthesis of H antigens, Lewis B, and Lewis Y. In this study, we clarified the transcriptional regulation of FUT1 in the DLD-1 colon cancer cell line, which has high expression of Lewis B and Lewis Y antigens, expresses the FUT1 gene, and shows α 1,2-fucosyltransferase (FUT) activity. 5'-rapid amplification of cDNA ends revealed a FUT1 transcriptional start site -10 nucleotides upstream of the site registered at NM_000148 in the DataBase of Human Transcription Start Sites (DBTSS). Using the dual luciferase assay, FUT1 gene expression was shown to be regulated at the region -91 to -81 nt to the transcriptional start site, which contains the Elk-1 binding site. Site-directed mutagenesis of this region revealed the Elk-1 binding site to be essential for FUT1 transcription. Furthermore, transfection of the dominant negative Elk-1 gene, and the chromatin immunoprecipitation (CHIp) assay, supported Elk-1-dependent transcriptional regulation of FUT1 gene expression in DLD-1 cells. These results suggest that a defined region in the 5'-flanking region of FUT1 is critical for FUT1 transcription and that constitutive gene expression of FUT1 is regulated by Elk-1 in DLD-1 cells.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Transcriptional regulation of fucosyltransferase 1 gene expression in colon cancer cells.</str>
    <str name="id">23533340</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Recently, we have reported that in normal gastric epithelium, the expression of gastric apomucins MUC5AC and MUC6 is associated with the specific expression of type 1 and type 2 Lewis antigens, and FUT2 and FUT1 fucosyltransferases, respectively. Until now, there are no data demonstrating the direct implication of specific glycosyltransferases in the specific patterns of apomucin glycosylation. HT29/M3 colon cancer cell line express MUC1, MUC5AC, type 1 Lewis antigens and FUT2 but not type 2 structures and FUT1, as it occurs in the epithelial cells of the gastric superficial epithelium. These cells were transfected with the cDNA of human FUT1, the alpha-1,2-fucosyltransferase responsible for the synthesis of type 2 Lewis antigens, to assess the implication of FUT1 in the glycosylation of MUC1 and MUC5AC. The M3-FUT1 clones obtained express high levels of type 2 Lewis antigens: H type 2 and Ley antigens. Immunoprecipitation of MUC1 and MUC5AC apomucins gives the direct evidence that FUT1 catalyses the addition of alpha-1,2-fucose to these apomucins, supporting the hypothesis that the pattern of apomucin glycosylation is not only instructed by the mucin primary sequence but also by the set of glycosyltransferases expressed in each specific cell type.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The expression of human FUT1 in HT-29/M3 colon cancer cells instructs the glycosylation of MUC1 and MUC5AC apomucins.</str>
    <str name="id">12652076</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The expression of the ABO antigens on erythrocyte membranes is regulated by H gene (FUT1)-encoded alpha(1,2)fucosyltransferase activity. We have examined the expression of the FUT1 in several tumor cell lines, including erythroid lineage and normal bone marrow cells, by Northern blot and/or reverse transcription-polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) analyses. RT-PCR indicated that bone marrow cells, erythroleukemic cells (HEL), and highly undifferentiated leukemic cells (K562) that have erythroid characteristics expressed the FUT1 mRNA while four leukemic cell lines did not. The FUT1 mRNA was also demonstrated in gastric, colonic, and ovarian (MCAS) cancer cell lines by RT-PCR. Northern blot analysis indicated that a 4. 0-kilobase FUT1 transcript was expressed in some of these tumor cell lines. Rapid amplification of 5' cDNA end (RACE) analysis suggested that the FUT1 transcript had several forms generated by two distinct transcription start sites and alternative splicing. The results of RT-PCR using specific primers for each starting exon suggested that two transcription initiation sites (exon 1A and exon 2A) of the FUT1 were identified in gastric cancer cells and in ovarian cancer cells. Only exon 1A was identified as a transcription start site in another gastric cancer cell line, two colonic cancer cell lines, and in K562 cells, whereas only exon 2A was identified in HEL cells and in bone marrow cells. These two transcription start sites were located 1.8 kilobases apart. Therefore, two distinct promoters appeared to be present in the FUT1. The distinct promoters of the FUT1 and alternative splicing of the FUT1 mRNA may be associated with time- and tissue-specific expression of the FUT1.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Structure and expression of H-type GDP-L-fucose:beta-D-galactoside 2-alpha-L-fucosyltransferase gene (FUT1). Two transcription start sites and alternative splicing generate several forms of FUT1 mRNA.</str>
    <str name="id">9054453</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Current polymerase chain reaction-based strategies for phenotype prediction often fail when sporadic nonfunctional alleles are encountered. The population frequency of such mutations was not known for any gene under low selection pressure and may be best examined in blood groups systems lacking prevalent nonfunctional alleles. The frequency of the very rare Bombay blood group (Oh, genotype hh sese) was recently determined in a systematic survey of more than 600,000 white individuals.</str>
      <str>With this survey used in conjunction with additional blood samples, the population frequency of nonfunctional alleles of the gene encoding the alpha (1,2)fucosyltransferase (H or FUT1) was determined.</str>
      <str>Seven different h alleles were found in five unrelated individuals, three of whom were homozygous for unique alleles. There was no prevalent h allele. Five missense and one frameshift mutations were observed, that were the presumptive causes of the null phenotype; the coding sequence of one h allele was identical to the H sequence. The average inbreeding factor alpha was 0.00116. The frequency of nonfunctional alleles at the H gene locus was calculated as 1 in 347 in a large white population (95% CI: 1:185-1:824).</str>
      <str>The Bombay blood group phenotype in white is due to diverse, sporadic, nonfunctional alleles without any prevalent allele. Assuming similar rates of nonfunctional alleles in glycosyltransferase genes like ABO, current genotyping strategies may fail as often as once in about 300 individuals of blood group O. Sporadic neutral alleles may also pose a serious obstacle for population-wide screening of many disease-associated genes.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Polymorphism of the h allele and the population frequency of sporadic nonfunctional alleles.</str>
    <str name="id">9122901</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The penultimate step in the biosynthesis of the human ABO blood group oligosaccharide antigens is catalyzed by alpha-(1,2)-fucosyltransferase(s) (GDP-L-fucose: beta-D-galactoside 2-alpha-L-fucosyltransferase, EC 2.4.1.69), whose expression is determined by the H and Secretor (SE) blood group loci (also known as FUT1 and FUT2, respectively). These enzymes construct Fuc alpha 1--&gt;2Gal beta-linkages, known as H determinants, which are essential precursors to the A and B antigens. Erythrocytes from individuals with the rare Bombay and para-Bombay blood group phenotypes are deficient in H determinants, and thus A and B determinants, as a consequence of apparent homozygosity for null alleles at the H locus. We report a molecular analysis of a human alpha-(1,2)-fucosyltransferase gene, thought to correspond to the H blood group locus, in a Bombay pedigree and a para-Bombay pedigree. We find inactivating point mutations in the coding regions of both alleles of this gene in each H-deficient individual. These results define the molecular basis for H blood group antigen deficiency in Bombay and para-Bombay phenotypes, provide compelling evidence that this gene represents the human H blood group locus, and strongly support a hypothesis that the H and SE loci represent distinct alpha-(1,2)-fucosyltransferase genes. Candidate sequences for the human SE locus are identified by low-stringency Southern blot hybridization analyses, using a probe derived from the H alpha-(1,2)-fucosyltransferase gene.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Molecular basis for H blood group deficiency in Bombay (Oh) and para-Bombay individuals.</str>
    <str name="id">7912436</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>We have previously used a gene-transfer scheme to isolate a human genomic DNA fragment that determines expression of a GDP-L-fucose:beta-D-galactoside 2-alpha-L-fucosyltransferase [alpha(1,2)FT; EC 2.4.1.69]. Although this fragment determined expression of an alpha(1,2)FT whose kinetic properties mirror those of the human H blood group alpha(1,2)FT, their precise nature remained undefined. We describe here the molecular cloning, sequence, and expression of a human cDNA corresponding to these human genomic sequences. When expressed in COS-1 cells, this cDNA directs expression of cell surface H structures and a cognate alpha(1,2)FT activity with properties analogous to the human H blood group alpha(1,2)FT. The cDNA sequence predicts a 365-amino acid polypeptide characteristic of a type II transmembrane glycoprotein with a domain structure analogous to that of other glycosyltransferases but without significant primary sequence similarity to these or other known proteins. To directly demonstrate that the cDNA encodes an alpha(1,2)FT, the COOH-terminal domain predicted to be Golgi-resident was expressed in COS-1 cells as a catalytically active, secreted, and soluble protein A fusion peptide. Southern blot analysis showed that this cDNA identifies DNA sequences syntenic to the human H locus on chromosome 19. These results strongly suggest that this cloned alpha(1,2)FT cDNA represents the product of the human H blood group locus.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Molecular cloning, sequence, and expression of a human GDP-L-fucose:beta-D-galactoside 2-alpha-L-fucosyltransferase cDNA that can form the H blood group antigen.</str>
    <str name="id">2118655</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The para-Bombay phenotype (also known as H-deficient secretor) is characterized by a lack of ABH antigens on red cells, but ABH substances are found in saliva. Molecular genetic analysis was performed for five Chinese individuals serologically typed as para-Bombay.</str>
      <str>ABO genotyping and mutational analysis of both FUT1 (or H) and FUT2 (or Se) loci were performed for these individuals using the polymerase chain reaction, single-strand conformation polymorphism analysis and direct DNA sequencing.</str>
      <str>The ABO genotypes of these para-Bombay individuals correlated with the types of ABH substances found in the saliva. Their FUT1 genotypes were h1h2 (three individuals), h2h2 (one individual) and h2h6 (one individual). Alleles h1 (547-552delAG) and h2 (880-882delTT) were known frameshift mutations, while h6 (522C &gt; A) was a missense mutation (Phe174Leu) not previously reported. These three mutations were rare sequence variations, each with an allele frequency of less than 0.005. Phe174 might be functionally important because this residue is conserved from mouse to human. Their FUT2 genotypes were Se357se357,385 for the h2h6 individual and Se357Se357) for the others. Both FUT2 alleles were known: one functional (Se357) and one weakly functional (se357,385). That they carried at least one copy of a functional FUT2 allele was consistent with their secretor status. As FUT1 and FUT2 are adjacent on 19q13.3, there are three possible haplotypes in these para-Bombay individuals: h1-Se357; h2-Se357; and h6-se357,385.</str>
      <str>A novel non-functional FUT1 allele (522C &gt; A, or Phe174Leu) was identified in a para-Bombay individual and on a se357,385 haplotype background.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Molecular genetic analysis of para-Bombay phenotypes in Chinese: a novel non-functional FUT1 allele is identified.</str>
    <str name="id">12366770</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>We previously reported that sialyl Lewis(y), synthesized by fucosyltransferases, is involved in angiogenesis. Fucosyltransferase 1 (fut1) is an α(1,2)-fucosyltransferase responsible for synthesis of the H blood group and Lewis(y) antigens. However, the angiogenic involvement of fut 1 in the pathogenesis of rheumatoid arthritis synovial tissue (RA ST) has not been clearly defined.</str>
      <str>Assay of α(1,2)-linked fucosylated proteins in RA was performed by enzyme-linked lectin assay. Fut1 expression was determined in RA ST samples by immunohistological staining. We performed angiogenic Matrigel assays using a co-culture system of human dermal microvascular endothelial cells (HMVECs) and fut1 small interfering RNA (siRNA) transfected RA synovial fibroblasts. To determine if fut1 played a role in leukocyte retention and cell proliferation in the RA synovium, myeloid THP-1 cell adhesion assays and fut1 siRNA transfected RA synovial fibroblast proliferation assays were performed.</str>
      <str>Total α(1,2)-linked fucosylated proteins in RA ST were significantly higher compared to normal (NL) ST. Fut1 expression on RA ST lining cells positively correlated with ST inflammation. HMVECs from a co-culture system with fut1 siRNA transfected RA synovial fibroblasts exhibited decreased endothelial cell tube formation compared to control siRNA transfected RA synovial fibroblasts. Fut1 siRNA also inhibited myeloid THP-1 adhesion to RA synovial fibroblasts and RA synovial fibroblast proliferation.</str>
      <str>These data show that α(1,2)-linked fucosylated proteins are upregulated in RA ST compared to NL ST. We also show that fut1 in RA synovial fibroblasts is important in angiogenesis, leukocyte-synovial fibroblast adhesion, and synovial fibroblast proliferation, all key processes in the pathogenesis of RA.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Fucosyltransferase 1 mediates angiogenesis, cell adhesion and rheumatoid arthritis synovial tissue fibroblast proliferation.</str>
    <str name="id">24467809</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>This is a study on the allele composing of ABO, FUT1 and FUT2 gene loci of 10 para-Bombay individuals in China.</str>
      <str>Ten samples coming from different districts of China were suspected of para-Bombay phenotype by primary serology tests. Routine and absorb-elution tests were conducted to identify their ABO type, and duplex polymerase chain reaction-restriction fragment length polymorphism (PCR-RFLP) was applied to getting their ABO genotype. Most of them were submitted to a test of their Lewis type as well. Then through direct DNA sequencing with PCR products of FUT1 and FUT2 genes, the genotypes of their H and SE gene loci were analyzed.</str>
      <str>It can be confirmed that the 10 samples are para-Bombay. All of their ABO genotypes are consistent with the serological absorb-elution results and the substances detected results in saliva. Seven out of 10 have recessive homozygous gene at their H locus. Each phenotype of h1h1 (nt547-552Deltaag), h2h2 (nt880-882Deltatt) and h4h4 (nt35 t--&gt;c) are ascertained in 2 individuals; moreover, h3h3 (nt 658 c--&gt;t) is identified in one individual. The rest are hh heterozygous individuals: one is h3/h(new-1); the other is h2/h(new-2); the last one is h1/h2. The h(new-1) (nt586 c--&gt;t) allele has a point mutation at nt 586 C to T, which leads a nonsense mutation Gln(CAG) to stop (TAG).The second h (new-2) (nt328 g--&gt;a) has an nt328 G to A missense mutation,which leads Ala (GCC),was replaced by Thr (ACC) at 110 amino acid position. All the 10 samples have Se (nt357 c--&gt;t) synonymous mutation. One Bm(h) (B/O) individual with h4h4 phenotype has a Se(w)(nt357 c--&gt;t; nt385 a--&gt;t) allele, whose Lewis type is Le(a+b+). Moreover, the authors detected a (nt716 g--&gt;a) mutation in two samples' Se gene.</str>
      <str>Four kinds of known h alleles (h1-h4), 2 kinds of novel non-functional FUT1 alleles, a Se(w) allele, and a novel SeG716A polymorphism in Chinese para-Bombay individuals were detected. At the same time, the authors noticed that all the 10 samples have the nt357 c--&gt;t mutation in their FUT2 gene.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">[Analysis on FUT1 and FUT2 gene of 10 para-Bombay individuals in China].</str>
    <str name="id">15476160</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Alpha(1,2)-fucosyltransferase catalyzes the transfer of fucose to the C-2 position of galactose on type II precursor substrate Gal beta1-4GlcNAc beta1-R. It plays an important biological role in the formation of H antigen, a precursor oligosaccharide for both A and B antigens on red blood cells. Aberration of alpha(1,2)-fucosyltransferase activity by gene mutations results in decreased synthesis of H antigen, leading to the para-Bombay phenotype. In this study, we collected about 250,000 blood samples in Taiwan during 5 yr and identified the subjects with para-Bombay phenotype. Then we analyzed the sequence of the alpha(1,2)-fucosyltransferase gene by direct sequencing and gene cloning methods, using the blood samples of 30 para-Bombay individuals and 30 control subjects who were randomly selected. The goals of this study were to search for new h alleles, to determine the h allele frequencies, and to test whether the sporadic theory is applicable in Taiwan. Six different h alleles (ha, 547-548 AG-del; hb, 880-881 TT-del; hc, R220C; hd, R220H; he, F174L; and hf, N327T) were observed. Two h alleles, he and hf, were newly discovered in Taiwan. The he allele has a nucleotide 522C&gt;A point mutation, predicting the amino acid 174 substitution of Phe to Leu; the hf allele has missense mutation of nucleotide 980A&gt;C, predicting the amino acid 327 substitution of Asn to Thr. Frequencies of the 6 alleles are ha 46.67%, hb 38.33%, hc 5.00%, hd 1.67%, he 3.33%, and hf 5.00%, respectively. These findings in the Taiwanese population confirm previous observations in other populations that the Bombay and para-Bombay phenotypes are due to diverse, sporadic, nonfunctional alleles, predominantly ha and hb, leading to H deficiency of red blood cells. In contrast to previous reports of non-prevalent associations of h alleles with para-Bombay phenotype, our results suggest a regional allele preference associated with para-Bombay individuals in Taiwan.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Two prevalent h alleles in para-Bombay haplotypes among 250,000 Taiwanese.</str>
    <str name="id">15487706</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To establish the eukaryotic cell expression system for the alpha-1,2 fucosyltransferase gene FUT1 293C to T and 658C to T mutations and explore the mechanism of FUT1 mutations resulting in the reduced expression of H antigen.</str>
      <str>Genomic DNAs were extracted from individuals with para-Bombay phenotype and full coding region of FUT1 was amplified. The amplification fragments were ligated with pcDNA3.1 plasmid to construct the recombinant expression vectors. The recombinant plasmids were transfected into the COS-7 cells using lipofectamine transfection reagent and stable expression screening was performed. FUT1 mRNA expression was determined by real-time quantitative PCR. The activity of enzyme was measured by high performance liquid chromatography. Expressed protein was identified by SDS-PAGE and Western blotting.</str>
      <str>pcDNA3.1-FUT1 wildtype, pcDNA3.1-FUT1 293C to T and pcDNA3.1-FUT1 658C to T recombinant vectors were constructed, respectively. COS-7 cells with stable expression of FUT1 were obtained through recombinant plasmid transfection and screening with G418. The FUT1 mRNA level of transfected cells with 293C to T and 658C to T recombinant vectors reached 97.10% and 104.74% of the wildtype FUT1 transfected cell. A specific protein band with about 46 000 was confirmed in the transfected cell lysates by SDS-PAGE electrophoresis and Western blotting with 6×His Tag antibody. The wildtype FUT1 transfected cell lysates can catalyze the enzymatic reaction, while the enzyme activity of cell lysates from 293C to T and 658C to T were abolished.</str>
      <str>The results suggested that the 293C to T and 658C to T mutations of FUT1 gene did not affect the RNA and protein expression levels, but the enzyme activity of cells with FUT1 mutations was significantly decreased which resulted in the reduced expressin of H antigen.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">[Study on the expression stability of mutant alpha-1,2 fucosyltransferase gene 293C to T and 658C to T in eukaryotic cells].</str>
    <str name="id">21983725</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The H genes, encoding an alpha1,2fucosyltransferase, which defines blood groups with the H structure, of four Bombay and 13 para-Bombay Japanese individuals were analyzed for mutations. Four Bombay individuals were homologous for the same null H allele, which is inactivated by a single nonsense mutation at position 695 from G to A (G695A), resulting in termination of H gene translation. The allele inactivated by the G695A was designated h1. The other 13 para-Bombay individuals possessed a trace amount of H antigens on erythrocytes regardless of their secretor status. Sequence analysis of their H genes showed four additional inactivated H gene alleles, h2, h3, h4, and h5. The h2 allele possesed a single base deletion at position 990 G (990-del). The h3 and h4 alleles possessed a single missense mutation, T721C, which changes Tyr 241 to His, and G442T, which changes Asp148 to Tyr, respectively. The h5 allele possessed two missense mutations, T460C (Tyr154to His) and G1042A (Glu348to Lys). The h2, h3, h4, and h5 enzymes directed by these alleles were not fully inactivated by the deletion and the missense mutations expressing some residual enzyme activity resulting in synthesis of H antigen on erythrocytes. Thirteen para-Bombay individuals whose erythrocytes retained a trace amount of H antigen were determined to be heterozygous or homozygous for at least one of h2, h3, h4, or h5 alleles. This clarified that the levels (null to trace amount) of H antigen expression on erythrocytes of Bombay and para-Bombay individuals are determined solely by H enzyme activity. These mutations found in the Japanese H alleles differ from a nonsense mutation found in the Indonesian population. To determine the roles of the H, Se, and Le genes in the expression of H antigen in secretions and Lewis blood group antigen on erythrocytes, the Lewis and secretor genes were also examined in these Bombay and para-Bombay individuals. The Lewis blood group phenotype, Le(alpha- b+), was determined by the combinatorial activity of two fucosyltransferases, the Lewis enzyme and the secretor enzyme, and the secretor status was solely determined by the secretor enzyme activity, not by H enzyme activity. Bombay individuals were confirmed to be homozygous for the inactivated H and Se genes. As expected from the very low frequency of Bombay and para-Bombay individuals in the population, ie, approximately one in two or 300,000, the H gene mutations were found to be very variable, unlike the cases of the point mutations in the other glycosyltransferase genes; the ABO genes, the Lewis gene, and the secretor gene.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Wide variety of point mutations in the H gene of Bombay and para-Bombay individuals that inactivate H enzyme.</str>
    <str name="id">9226185</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Minimizing attrition is a key objective in longitudinal research, with possible consequences being additional bias and reduced generalizability. Identifying determinants of attrition is essential in determining attrition prevention strategies. The objective of this study was to investigate a number of these determinants, with an emphasis on contactability.</str>
      <str>Data were taken from the Passports project, a randomized controlled trial of an intervention to provide postrelease support to ex-prisoners in Queensland, Australia. Measures of contactability included intervention intensity, baseline collaterals, and follow-up telephone calls, with attrition at follow-up being the outcome event. Multivariable modeling was used to assess the independent effects of these measures on attrition.</str>
      <str>Attrition was found to be more likely among those who were not contacted between the release and follow-up (adjusted odds ratio [AOR]: 2.93; 95% confidence interval [CI]: 1.87, 4.60), did not provide collaterals (AOR: 2.58; 95% CI: 1.68, 3.97), and received more than four telephone calls (AOR: 2.42; 95% CI: 1.61, 3.63). Evidence of dose-response relationships between attrition and the measures of collaterals and telephone calls was also seen to exist.</str>
      <str>These findings have implications for sample size maintenance, especially those involving hard-to-reach populations. Subject to cost constraints and possible diminishing returns, researchers should endeavor to implement a study protocol that facilitates continued contact during follow-up.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Attrition in a longitudinal study with hard-to-reach participants was reduced by ongoing contact.</str>
    <str name="id">23384589</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To examine and compare the sensibility attributes (face/content validity and feasibility) of five at-work productivity measures from the perspective of patients with osteoarthritis (OA) or rheumatoid arthritis (RA).</str>
      <str>Workers with OA or RA (n = 250) completed a survey that includes five at-work productivity (presenteeism) measures and questions asking about their comprehensiveness, understandability, length, and suitability of response options. A final question asked respondents which single measure was considered "best" overall. Measures compared included the Workplace Activity Limitations Scale (WALS), Stanford Presenteeism Scale, Endicott Work Productivity Scale, Work Instability Scale for Rheumatoid Arthritis (RA-WIS), and Work Limitations Questionnaire (WLQ-25). Sensibility performance was assessed quantitatively (% respondent endorsement) and qualitatively via written feedback.</str>
      <str>The WLQ-25 was considered most comprehensive (endorsed by 92.8%), the WALS performed best in terms of understandability (97.6%) and suitability of response options (97.9%), and the RA-WIS was favored in terms of length (91.6%). Consistent sensibility performance between OA and RA was found. The WALS (32.6%) and WLQ-25 (30.0%) were moderately preferred in the final overall appraisal.</str>
      <str>Sensibility criteria were generally met by all five at-work productivity measures. Variable endorsement levels across specific sensibility attributes were also revealed across the measures compared.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Sensibility of five at-work productivity measures was endorsed by patients with osteoarthritis or rheumatoid arthritis.</str>
    <str name="id">23466017</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Evaluating the performance of a new diagnostic test presents a challenge if the conventional "gold" standard is invasive, hazardous, or expensive, especially if that test has been supplanted in usual clinical practice by a "silver" standard test that is more acceptable and perhaps only slightly suboptimal. In such a case, a systematic literature review will typically uncover a mix of study types, some using the gold and some the silver.</str>
      <str>We sought to develop and compare statistical methods to account for this kind of heterogeneity in performing a meta-analysis.</str>
      <str>We compared the performance of estimation methods based on generalized mixed models which incorporate heterogeneity, especially choice of reference test, and random between-study variation in sensitivity and specificity with more conventional methods which neglect the differences in reference tests. Computer simulations were conducted to assess bias and root mean square error of point estimates and coverage of interval estimates.</str>
      <str>Methods ignoring the difference in reference tests severely underestimated sensitivity and specificity under the assumption of conditional independence. Bias was substantial even for references with small departure from the standard and persisted with increasing sample size. Coverage of interval estimates was far from nominal level.</str>
      <str>In the presence of varying reference tests, avoidance of bias and invalid confidence intervals for diagnostic performance requires applying a model that accounts for differences in reference test and heterogeneity among studies.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Statistical methods for the meta-analysis of diagnostic tests must take into account the use of surrogate standards.</str>
    <str name="id">23466018</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>This study aimed to develop and pilot an equity lens that could help researchers in developing a more equity-oriented approach toward priority setting and agenda setting in systematic reviews.</str>
      <str>We developed an equity lens to guide the development and evaluation of a prioritization process and evaluate its outcomes based on the information derived from a discussion workshop and a comparison with the existing literature on the topic. We piloted the process section of the equity lens across the 13 structured priority-setting approaches in the Cochrane Collaboration.</str>
      <str>We devised an equity lens with two checklists: one to guide the process of priority setting (nine questions) and the other to evaluate the outcomes of priority setting (eight questions). Of the nine questions, seven questions were partially addressed by at least one of the prioritization projects. Two questions were not considered in any of them. The prioritization projects did not report sufficient outcome data, thus we could not explore the eight question on evaluating outcomes.</str>
      <str>Currently, there are few strategies in the Cochrane Collaboration that explicitly address the research priorities of individuals from different sociodemographic groups. The equity lens for priority setting and agenda setting can help project teams to develop a more equity-oriented approach to set a research agenda and/or prioritize research topics. However, further studies are needed to evaluate its impact on the prioritization process.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">An equity lens can ensure an equity-oriented approach to agenda setting and priority setting of Cochrane Reviews.</str>
    <str name="id">23477991</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Methods for setting priorities in systematic reviews.</str>
    <str name="id">23548134</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To examine the responsiveness of generic and condition-specific instruments based on the anchor of self-reported level of global change in patients with colorectal cancer (CRC).</str>
      <str>Three hundred thirty-three patients with CRC were surveyed at two assessments at baseline and follow-up at 6 months from September 2009 to July 2010 using the Short Form-12 Health Survey version 2 (SF-12v2) and Functional Assessment of Cancer Therapy-Colorectal (FACT-C) measures. The responsiveness of the two measures was evaluated using standardized effect size, standardized response mean, responsiveness statistic, and receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve analysis.</str>
      <str>In worsened group, internal responsiveness of detecting negative changes was satisfactory for most subscales of FACT-C and SF-12v2. The FACT-C subscales were significantly more responsive to positive changes detection than the SF-12v2 subscales in improved group. Physical well-being subscale, Trial Outcome Index (TOI), and total score of FACT-C were more externally responsive to ROC curve analysis. The FACT-C measure was generally more responsive to changes in health status compared with SF-12v2 measure.</str>
      <str>TOI and total score of FACT-C were the most responsive among subscales of condition-specific measure, which were more responsive than all generic subscales with the exception of social domain. Complementary use of condition-specific and generic instruments to evaluate the health-related quality of life of CRC patients is encouraged.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Condition-specific measure was more responsive than generic measure in colorectal cancer: all but social domains.</str>
    <str name="id">23548135</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>An increased risk of metabolic syndrome (MS) has been observed among women with previous gestational diabetes mellitus (pGDM). Increased inflammatory markers such as C-reactive protein (CRP) and interleukin 6 (IL-6) usually accompany. We performed this survey to examine the relationship between pGDM and MS, CRP and IL-6.</str>
      <str>77 women with pGDM and 67 randomly sampled women free from GDM participated in this study, 2-3 years after index pregnancy. Laboratory and anthropometric measurements were performed. MS was defined according to ATP III criteria. Statistical analyses were conducted using SPSS 18.</str>
      <str>CRP were different between groups with and without pGDM [2.69 (2.86 mg/dl and 1.56 (1.39) mg/dl, respectively; p &lt; 0.01]. The presence of each MS component by itself was associated with significantly higher CRP Levels, except for fasting blood glucose. In linear regression models, CRP and IL-6 were significantly associated with BMI (β =0. 25, 0.23; p &lt; 0.01), waist circumference (β=0. 27, 0.05; p &lt; 0.01) and HOMA-IR (β=0. 39, 0.39; p &lt; 0.01). After adjustment for age and BMI the occurrence of pGDM in the group with both high CRP and MS was significantly associated with CRP level (OR= 5.11; CI=1.59-16.43; p &lt; 0.01).</str>
      <str>Since CRP and Il-6 were higher in women with both pGDM and MS it appears that the presence of pGDM with MS components have a synergistic effect on the elevation of serum levels of inflammatory markers which can be partly as a result of visceral obesity. Further long-term studies are necessary to confirm the relationship between CRP, IL-6 and MS in women with pGDM.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Association of metabolic syndrome with inflammatory mediators in women with previous gestational diabetes mellitus.</str>
    <str name="id">23497664</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The foot and ankle are frequently affected in patients with rheumatoid arthritis (RA). One of the negative consequences of RA on the physical function of patients is a decrease in muscle strength. However, little is known about foot and muscle strength in this population. The aim of the study was to evaluate significant differences in foot and ankle muscle strength between patients with established RA against age and sex-matched controls using hand-held dynamometry.</str>
      <str>The maximal muscle strength of ankle plantarflexion, dorsiflexion, eversion and inversion was assessed in 14 patients with RA, mean (SD) disease duration of 22 (14.1) years, and 20 age and sex-matched control participants using hand-held dynamometry.</str>
      <str>Significant differences were observed in muscle strength between the two groups in plantarflexion (p = 0.00), eversion (p = 0.04) and inversion (p = 0.01). No significant difference was found in dorsiflexion (p &gt; 0.05). The patients with RA displayed a significantly lower plantarflexion-dorsiflexion ratio than the control participants (p = 0.03).</str>
      <str>The results from this study showed that the RA patients displayed a significant decrease in ankle dorsiflexion, eversion and inversion when compared to the non-RA control group suggesting that foot and ankle muscle strength may be affected by the pathological processes in RA. This study is a preliminary step for the measurement of muscle impairments within the RA population.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Assessment of foot and ankle muscle strength using hand held dynamometry in patients with established rheumatoid arthritis.</str>
    <str name="id">23522448</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The aging tsunami: time for a new metaphor?</str>
    <str name="id">23548140</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Using person-environment-fit theory as a theoretical framework, this qualitative case study examined, through in-depth interviews and thematic analysis, the lived experience of an older gay man who has lived solely in rural communities. An overarching theme of life satisfaction clearly emerged, along with themes regarding supportive social networks and disclosure management of his sexual orientation. The findings suggest that although it is important to understand the challenges faced by the lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender community in rural environments, it is equally important to shed light on the ways in which older adults age well within these communities.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Aging well and gay in rural America: a case study.</str>
    <str name="id">23548141</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>In the final phase of a 3-phase project, the Assessment of Readiness for Mobility Transition (ARMT) was clinically validated, emphasizing assessment/intervention. ARMT and coping, health/vision status, and social support measures were administered to 133 community-dwelling older adults. Concurrent validity is supported. Higher readiness to cope with mobility transition and self-confidence related to fall risk, higher self-rated health/vision, and fewer maladaptive behaviors, but not social support/adaptive coping, suggesting that those at risk can benefit from person-centered intervention to mobilize strengths for transportation/mobility planning. Older drivers may harbor unrealistic expectations regarding nonfamily mobility support. Implications for practice, education, research, and policy are presented.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Addressing individual differences in mobility transition counseling with older adults.</str>
    <str name="id">23548142</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>As they age, gay and bisexual men are embedded in multiple environments and communities. This article reanalyzes data collected as part of a larger qualitative study of crystal methamphetamine use in New York City. Focusing on the migration narratives of 30 racially/ethnically diverse men, age 40 years old and older, recruited from multiple venues several key areas emerged: ostracization, lack of affirmation as well as movement activities. Interactively they transformed social practices and increased spaces to explore sexuality, build community engagements and exchange resources. This study suggests that assessment of gay men (and other marginalized groups) may be enhanced through application of migration narratives.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Migration narratives: expanding methods to examine the interaction of person and environment among aging gay men.</str>
    <str name="id">23548143</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>One of the main reasons for reforming long-term care systems is a deficient existing service infrastructure for the elderly. This article provides an overview of why and how the Korean government expanded long-term care infrastructure through the introduction of a new compulsory insurance system, with a particular focus on the market-friendly policies used to expand the infrastructure. Then, the positive results of the expansion of the long-term care infrastructure and the challenges that have emerged are examined. Finally, it is argued that the Korean government should actively implement a range of practical policies and interventions within the new system.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The development of Korea's new long-term care service infrastructure and its results: focusing on the market-friendly policy used for expansion of the numbers of service providers and personal care workers.</str>
    <str name="id">23548145</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>p53 is a powerful tumor suppressor and is an attractive cancer therapeutic target. A breakthrough in cancer research came from the discovery of the drugs which are capable of reactivating p53 function. Most anti-cancer agents, from traditional chemo- and radiation therapies to more recently developed non-peptide small molecules exert their effects by enhancing the anti-proliferative activities of p53. Small molecules such as nutlin, RITA, and PRIMA-1 that can activate p53 have shown their anti-tumor effects in different types of hematological malignancies. Importantly, nutlin and PRIMA-1 have successfully reached the stage of phase I/II clinical trials in at least one type of hematological cancer. Thus, the pharmacological activation of p53 by these small molecules has a major clinical impact on prognostic use and targeted drug design. In the current review, we present the recent achievements in p53 research using small molecules in hematological malignancies. Anticancer activity of different classes of compounds targeting the p53 signaling pathway and their mechanism of action are discussed. In addition, we discuss how p53 tumor suppressor protein holds promise as a drug target for recent and future novel therapies in these diseases.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Targeting p53 by small molecules in hematological malignancies.</str>
    <str name="id">23531342</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Steady progress is being made in endoscopic biliary intervention, especially endoscopic ultrasonography (EUS)-guided procedures. The EUS-guided rendezvous technique (EUS-RV) is a salvage method for failed selective biliary cannulation. The overall success rate of EUS-RV in 247 cases from seven published articles was 74 % and the incidence of complications was 11 %. The main cause of failed rendezvous cannulation was difficulty passing a biliary stricture or papilla due to poor guidewire (GW) manipulation. A recent large study found a 98.3 % success rate and superiority to precutting. This report suggested using a hydrophilic guidewire. Major complications were bleeding (0.8 %), bile leakage (1.2 %), peritonitis (0.4 %), pneumoperitoneum (0.2 %), and pancreatitis (1.6 %). The approach routes for EUS-RV were transgastric, transduodenal short position, and transduodenal long position. The appropriate route for each patient should be used. GW selection for EUS-RV is critical, and a hydrophilic GW might be the most useful. The catheter can be inserted through the papilla alongside or over the wire. Alongside cannulation is convenient, but difficult. The problem with the over-the-wire technique is withdrawal of the GW in the accessory channel. EUS-RV is effective and safe, but is not established. The efficacy should be confirmed in a prospective comparative trial, and the necessary specialist equipment should be developed.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The endoscopic ultrasonography-guided rendezvous technique for biliary cannulation: a technical review.</str>
    <str name="id">23179560</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>This study was performed to evaluate the outcomes of laparoscopic distal pancreatectomy (LDP) and laparoscopic pancreatoduodenectomy (LPD) compared with the open method using meta-analysis.</str>
      <str>A literature search was performed to identify comparative studies of laparoscopic versus open pancreatectomy. Perioperative outcomes were evaluated by meta-analysis using a fixed effect model and random effects model.</str>
      <str>Twenty-four studies of LDP and three studies of LPD matched the selection criteria, including 2,904 patients of DP and 109 patients of PD. Compared with ODP, LDP showed statistically significant differences with respect to less blood loss, lower transfusion rates, lower wound infection rates, lower morbidity rates, and shorter hospital stays. LPD showed significantly longer operative times compared with OPD. There was no significant difference in oncological outcomes between laparoscopic pancreatectomy and the open technique.</str>
      <str>This meta-analysis included the largest number of patients and number of articles comparing LDP and ODP, and LDP showed significantly better perioperative outcomes. This meta-analysis suggests that LDP is a reasonable operative method for benign tumors and some ductal carcinomas in the pancreas.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Laparoscopic distal pancreatectomy and pancreatoduodenectomy: is it worthwhile? A meta-analysis of laparoscopic pancreatectomy.</str>
    <str name="id">23224732</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Local ablation therapy (LAT) is a widely used treatment for hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) because it is less invasive than hepatic resection. The precise molecular mechanism underlying local HCC recurrence after LAT is largely unknown. The CD44 standard isoform (CD44s) is involved in epithelial-mesenchymal transition (EMT) in HCC. We investigate the significance of CD44s expression and EMT expression profile in local HCC recurrence after LAT.</str>
      <str>We studied the expression levels of CD44s, EMT expression profile (E-cadherin(low)/vimentin(high) expression) and their association with clinicopathological factors in 30 HCC samples from patients with locally recurrent HCCs after LAT following hepatic resection. The alterations of CD44s expression was compared with those in initial HCCs from 150 patients without prior any anticancer treatment including LAT.</str>
      <str>A high CD44s expression was significantly associated with the EMT expression profile (P = 0.002), and it was also detected with a higher frequency in the locally recurrent HCCs after LAT compared to initial HCCs (P &lt; 0.001). In addition, high CD44s expression was associated with the intrahepatic dissemination of HCC after LAT (P = 0.006).</str>
      <str>These results suggest that high CD44s expression is associated with the aggressive recurrence pattern via EMT after LAT for HCC.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">High CD44s expression is associated with the EMT expression profile and intrahepatic dissemination of hepatocellular carcinoma after local ablation therapy.</str>
    <str name="id">23238743</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Solid serous cystic neoplasm of the pancreas with invasive growth.</str>
    <str name="id">23269459</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Because the biopsy specimen of extrahepatic bile duct carcinoma (EHBDC) is small and shows reactive changes, the histological distinction between malignant and benign tissue can be difficult. Recent studies reported that S100P and insulin-like growth factor II mRNA-binding protein 3 (IMP3) were not only diagnostic molecules but also prognostic biomarkers in several organs. The objective of this study is to clarify the diagnostic and prognostic value of immunohistochemical expression of S100P and IMP3 in transpapillary biliary forceps biopsy (TBFB) samples.</str>
      <str>The TBFB samples were collected from 80 patients (EHBDC, 68 patients; benign, 12 patients), retrospectively.</str>
      <str>When using cytoplasmic-positive staining for IMP3 as a marker of malignancy, the sensitivity and specificity reached 79.4 and 91.7 %, respectively. The sensitivity, specificity and accuracy achieved 89.7, 91.7 and 90.0 %, respectively, when using positive staining for IMP3 and/or positive histology as a maker of malignancy. While univariate (P = 0.033) and multivariate (P = 0.039) analysis revealed that S100P-positive EHBDC patients showed significantly shorter survival.</str>
      <str>The results of this study suggest that immunohistochemical staining for IMP3 is useful in the diagnosis of EHBDC and that of S100P is useful as a prognostic marker for EHBDC.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Diagnostic and prognostic value of immunohistochemical expression of S100P and IMP3 in transpapillary biliary forceps biopsy samples of extrahepatic bile duct carcinoma.</str>
    <str name="id">23269460</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>We have reported the utility of an image display system using augmented reality (AR) technology in hepatobiliary surgery under laparotomy. Among several procedures, we herein report a system using a novel short rigid scope and stereo-scope, both designed specifically for open abdominal navigation surgery, and their clinical application for hepatobiliary and pancreatic surgery.</str>
      <str>The 3D reconstructed images were obtained from preoperative computed tomography data. In our specialized operating room, after paired-point matching registration, the reconstructed images are overlaid onto the operative field images captured by the short rigid scopes. The scopes, which are compact and sterilizable, can be used in the operative field. The stereo-scope provides depth information. Eight patients underwent operations using this system, including hepatectomy in two, distal pancreatectomy in three, and pancreaticoduodenectomy in three patients. The stereo-scope was used in five patients.</str>
      <str>All eight operations were performed safely using the novel short rigid scopes, and stereo images were acquired in all five patients for whom the stereo-scope was used. The scopes were user friendly, and the intraoperative time requirement for our system was reduced compared with the conventional method.</str>
      <str>The novel short rigid scope and stereo-scope seem to be suitable for clinical use in open abdominal navigation surgery. In hepatobiliary and pancreatic surgery, our novel system may improve the safety, accuracy and efficiency of operations.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Short rigid scope and stereo-scope designed specifically for open abdominal navigation surgery: clinical application for hepatobiliary and pancreatic surgery.</str>
    <str name="id">23269461</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Even during laparoscopic hepatectomy, a technique is often required to expose the major vessels, for example, in anatomical hepatectomy. We have standardized and performed such laparoscopic hepatectomy as successfully as open hepatectomy.</str>
      <str>We divide the liver parenchyma without pre-coagulation, exposing the major vessels using CUSA. To control the bleeding, we keep the central venous pressure low and often perform Pringle's maneuver. Over 49 months, we performed totally laparoscopic hepatectomies in 41 patients with the technique of exposing the major vessels. These included major hepatectomy in 7, sectorectomy in 17, segmentectomy in 14, and others in 3.</str>
      <str>The median operative time was 361 (range 176-605) minutes, with median blood loss of 216 (range 0-1600) g. The conversion rate was 4.9 %. Postoperative morbidity rate was 9.8 % (prolonged ascites in 1, port site infection in 1, peroneal palsy in 2). Mortality was zero. The median length of hospital stay after surgery was 8 (range 5-28) days. No local recurrence was found at the time of writing.</str>
      <str>By using our standardized procedure exposing the major vessels, we could raise the quality of laparoscopic hepatectomy toward the level of open hepatectomy significantly.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Totally laparoscopic hepatectomy exposing the major vessels.</str>
    <str name="id">23269462</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Intestinal ischemia/reperfusion (IR) injury is a serious and triggering event in the development of remote organ dysfunction, from which the lung is the main target. This condition is characterized by intense neutrophil recruitment, increased microvascular permeability. Intestinal IR is also responsible for induction of adult respiratory distress syndrome, the most serious and life-threatening form of acute lung injury. The purpose of this study was to investigate the effect of annexin-A1 protein as an endogenous regulator of the organ remote injury induced by intestinal ischemia/reperfusion. Male C57bl/6 mice were subjected to intestinal ischemia, induced by 45 min occlusion of the superior mesenteric artery, followed by reperfusion.</str>
      <str>The intestinal ischemia/reperfusion evoked a high intensity lung inflammation as indicated by the number of neutrophils as compared to control group. Treatment with annexin-A1 peptidomimetic Ac2-26, reduced the number of neutrophils in the lung tissue and increased its number in the blood vessels, which suggests a regulatory effect of the peptide Ac2-26 in the neutrophil migration. Moreover, the peptide Ac2-26 treatment was associated with higher levels of plasma IL-10.</str>
      <str>Our data suggest that the annexin-A1 peptidomimetic Ac2-26 treatment has a regulatory and protective effect in the intestinal ischemia/reperfusion by attenuation of the leukocyte migration to the lung and induction of the anti-inflammatory cytokine IL-10 release into the plasma. The anti-inflammatory action of annexin-A1 and its peptidomimetic described here may serve as a basis for future therapeutic approach in mitigating inflammatory processes due to intestinal ischemia/reperfusion.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Annexin-A1 peptide down-regulates the leukocyte recruitment and up-regulates interleukin-10 release into lung after intestinal ischemia-reperfusion in mice.</str>
    <str name="id">23497133</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>There is increasing evidence that the immune system is regulated by circadian rhythms. A wide range of immune parameters, such as the number of red blood cells and peripheral blood mononuclear cells as well as the level of critical immune mediators, such as cytokines, undergo daily fluctuations. Current experimental data indicate that circadian information reaches immune tissues mainly through diurnal patterns of autonomic and endocrine rhythms. In addition, immune factors such as cytokines can also influence the phase of the circadian clock, providing bidirectional flow of circadian information between the neuroendocrine and immune systems. This network of neuroendocrine-immune interactions consists of complexly integrated molecular feedback and feedforward loops that function in synchrony in order to optimize immune response. Chronic stress can disrupt this intrinsic orchestration, as several endocrine signals of chronically stressed patients present blunted rhythmic characteristics. Reprogramming of biological rhythms has recently gained much attention as a potent method to leverage homeostatic circadian controls to ultimately improve clinical outcomes. Elucidation of the intrinsic properties of such complex systems and optimization of intervention strategies require not only an accurate identification of the signaling pathways that mediate host responses, but also a system-level description and evaluation.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Systems biology of circadian-immune interactions.</str>
    <str name="id">23006670</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To investigate the precise mechanisms of virus recognition by mast cells, the expression and functional characteristics of virus recognition receptors that lead to mast cell activation were investigated. Our results suggest that mast cells are partly responsible for the early in vivo production of antiviral cytokines and chemokines upon vesicular stomatitis virus (VSV) infection. Analysis of the expression of double-stranded RNA (dsRNA) recognition receptors in murine bone marrow-derived mast cells (BMMCs) revealed that BMMCs express melanoma differentiation-associated gene 5 (MDA5), protein kinase RNA-activated, retinoic acid-inducible gene-I (RIG-I) and Toll-like receptor 3. The expression levels of these receptors were found to increase upon stimulation of mast cells with VSV as well as synthetic dsRNA: polyinosinic-polycytidylic acid. Moreover, small interfering RNA analysis to identify the receptors responsible for mast cell activation by VSV revealed that both RIG-I and MDA5 were involved in cytokine production but not in the degranulation of mast cells. Our findings suggest that mast cells produce cytokines and chemokines in the early infection stage after recognizing viruses via RIG-I and MDA5, and may contribute to antiviral responses. These data provide additional novel information that improves our understanding of antiviral innate responses that involve mast cells.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Expression and functional characterization of retinoic acid-inducible gene-I-like receptors of mast cells in response to viral infection.</str>
    <str name="id">23171655</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>CD48 is a glycosylphosphatidylinositol-anchored protein expressed ubiquitously on many cell types. Despite the poor ability to signal on its own, CD48 can activate cells via interaction with its counter receptors CD2 and CD244 as well as influence the function of other cell surface molecules by costimulatory activities. We show, herein, that injection of anti-CD48 antibodies into mice can augment the antibody response to a T-independent antigen, NP-Ficoll, that is representative of antigenic determinants expressed on the surface of various pathogens, such as Streptococcus pneumoniae. In C57BL/6 mice, enhancement of the response is dependent on natural killer (NK) cells as well as on the presence of CD2 and CD244, ligands for CD48, suggesting a requirement for direct interaction between NK and B cells. Interestingly, in this case, despite a similar augmentation by anti-CD48 in BALB/C mice, the response is independent of NK or T cells, suggesting that help for this response can be derived from other innate cell types. These results provide a pathway by which CD48, when appropriately activated, can influence the course of an antigen-specific antibody response via the innate system.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Enhancement of antigen-specific immunoglobulin G responses by anti-CD48.</str>
    <str name="id">23208079</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Fibroblasts are known to eliminate intracellular bacteria, but the lethal hit of the bactericidal mechanism has not been defined. We show that primary embryonic and established fibroblasts can be induced by interferons or by intracellular bacterial infection to express a perforin-like mRNA previously described as macrophage-expressed gene 1 (Mpeg1). The presence and level of the perforin-like mRNA correlate with the ability of primary mouse embryonic fibroblasts (MEF) to eliminate intracellular bacteria. In addition, siRNA knockdown of the perforin-like molecule abolishes bactericidal activity and allows intracellular bacterial replication. Complementation of MEF in which the endogenous perforin-like molecule has been knocked down with a red fluorescent protein-tagged version restores bactericidal activity. The perforin-like molecule has broad bactericidal specificity for pathogenic and non-pathogenic bacteria, including Gram-positive and -negative, and acid fast bacteria. The perforin-like molecule renders previously lysozyme-resistant bacteria sensitive to lysis by lysozyme suggesting physical damage of the outer cell wall by the perforin-like protein. MEF damage cell walls of intracellular bacteria by insertion, polymerization, and pore formation of the perforin-like protein, analogous to pore formers of complement and perforin-1 of cytolytic lymphocytes. We propose the name perforin-2.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Inhibition of intracellular bacterial replication in fibroblasts is dependent on the perforin-like protein (perforin-2) encoded by macrophage-expressed gene 1.</str>
    <str name="id">23257510</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Serum concentrations of acute phase proteins, inflammatory cytokines, and other immunological components were individually assayed using high-sensitivity ELISA in a com-munity-based cohort of preclinical rheumatoid arthritis (pre-RA) and matched non-RA control (CN) subjects. Bivariate correlations of the biomarker panel concentrations were compared in pre-RA versus CN and female versus male subjects. Clinically elevated CRP levels (8+ mg/l) occurred in a higher (p = 0.010) frequency in 46 pre-RA (n = 8, 17.4%) subjects than in 179 CN (n = 9, 5.0%), and were independent of age, gender, smoking behaviors, and serum rheumatoid factor. Selected age and gender differences were found in levels of the immunological network factors. In each study group, the ratio of sTNF-RI to IL-2sRα mean concentrations was 2-fold higher in men than in women. Aging correlated positively with CRP, ASAA, and TNF-α levels, but negatively with IL-1β. Bivariate correlations were similar in pre-RA subjects versus CN and by gender, with few exceptions. Factor loadings in principal component analysis of the total subjects indicated that age- and gender-related variables constituted the two main components. Using multiple regression analyses, an integrative working model of all variable interrelations was generated. The tentative, directional model supports a concept of gender dimorphism of the ratio of sTNF-RI to IL-2sRα serum concentrations and displays differing effects of age on TNF-α versus IL-1β levels. These findings indicate complex age, gender, and cytokine interrelations in control of the immune systems network. Future research in testing such inflammatory pathways promises a better understanding of predisposition to diseases, like RA.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Serum acute phase protein and inflammatory cytokine network correlations: comparison of a pre-rheumatoid arthritis and non-rheumatoid arthritis community cohort.</str>
    <str name="id">23328621</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Opsonization and anaphylatoxin production are early events in the innate response to bacterial pathogens. Opsonization alone is frequently not lethal and production of anaphy-latoxins, especially C5a, allows for recruitment of cellular defenses. Complement biochemistry is extensively studied and computational models have been reported previously. However, a critical feature of complement-mediated attack is its spatial dependence: diffusion of mediators into and away from a bacterium is central to understanding C5a generation. Spatial dependence is especially important in biofilms, where diffusion limitation is crucial to bacterial counterdefense. Here we develop a model of opsonization and C5a production in the presence of a common blood-borne pathogen, Staphylococcus epidermidis. Our results indicate that when complement attacks a single cell, diffusion into the extracellular polymeric substance (EPS) is complete within 10 ms and that production of C5a peaks over the next 15 min. When longer diffusion lengths (as in an EPS-rich biofilm) are incorporated, diffusion limitation appears such that the intensity and duration of C5a production is increased. However, the amount of C5a produced under several likely clinical scenarios where single cells or sparse biofilms are present is below the kD of the C5a receptor suggesting that complement activation by a single bacterium may be difficult to detect when diffusion is taken into account.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Spatiotemporal dynamics of complement C5a production within bacterial extracellular polymeric substance.</str>
    <str name="id">23328643</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Candida albicans infections and candidiasis are difficult to treat and create very serious therapeutic challenges. In this study, based on interactive time profile microarray data of C. albicans and zebrafish during infection, the infection-related protein-protein interaction (PPI) networks of the two species and the intercellular PPI network between host and pathogen were simultaneously constructed by a dynamic interaction model, modeled as an integrated network consisting of intercellular invasion and cellular defense processes during infection. The signal transduction pathways in regulating morphogenesis and hyphal growth of C. albicans were further investigated based on significant interactions found in the intercellular PPI network. Two cellular networks were also developed corresponding to the different infection stages (adhesion and invasion), and then compared with each other to identify proteins from which we can gain more insight into the pathogenic role of hyphal development in the C. albicans infection process. Important defense-related proteins in zebrafish were predicted using the same approach. The hyphal growth PPI network, zebrafish PPI network and host-pathogen intercellular PPI network were combined to form an integrated infectious PPI network that helps us understand the systematic mechanisms underlying the pathogenicity of C. albicans and the immune response of the host, and may help improve medical therapies and facilitate the development of new antifungal drugs.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Identification of infection- and defense-related genes via a dynamic host-pathogen interaction network using a Candida albicans-zebrafish infection model.</str>
    <str name="id">23406717</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To assess anxiety and depression symptoms, suicidal ideation, and health-related quality of life (HRQOL) in a large series of consecutive patients with primary hyperparathyroidism (pHPT) before and after parathyroidectomy.</str>
      <str>This prospective multicenter study investigated preoperative and postoperative depression, anxiety, suicidal ideation, and HRQOL in patients with pHPT and compared these variables with a control group with nontoxic thyroid nodules.</str>
      <str>The study included 194 patients with pHPT and 186 control subjects.</str>
      <str>Depression was evaluated with the Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS) and the Patient Health Questionnaire-9, which also assessed suicidal ideation. Anxiety was evaluated with the HADS. Health-related quality of life was measured with the 36-Item Short Form survey.</str>
      <str>Parathyroidectomy achieved a 98% cure rate. Preoperatively, severe depression (HADS score ≥ 11) was seen in 20% of the pHPT group and 9% of the control group. The Patient Health Questionnaire-9 detected moderate to severe depression in 17% of the patients with pHPT and 7% of the control subjects. Patients with pHPT had higher HADS anxiety scores (mean, 7.7) than control subjects (P &lt; .01) or the German normative sample (P &lt; .001). Compared with control subjects, patients with pHPT had significantly lower 36-Item Short Form survey preoperative physical and mental health summary scores (42.7 vs 49.5 and 41.2 vs 46.8, respectively; P = .001 for both comparisons). At 12 months follow-up, depression and anxiety decreased significantly in patients with pHPT; the prevalence of suicidal ideation was more than halved from the baseline (10.7% vs 22%; P = .008). Both physical and mental health scores (45.7 and 47.7, respectively) improved in patients with pHPT (P &lt; .001 each) but not in control subjects.</str>
      <str>Depression, anxiety, and decreased HRQOL appear to be related to pHPT. Successful parathyroidectomy seems to reduce psychopathologic symptoms and improve HRQOL in this setting.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Parathyroidectomy, elevated depression scores, and suicidal ideation in patients with primary hyperparathyroidism: results of a prospective multicenter study.</str>
    <str name="id">23560281</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>HIV RNA viral load (VL) has been shown to increase during opportunistic illnesses (OIs), suggesting active HIV replication in response to infection among patients not taking antiretroviral therapy (ART). We assessed the effects of OIs on HIV RNA VL and CD4+ T cell counts among patients on ART with initially suppressed VL.</str>
      <str>Between 2003 and 2007, we enrolled and followed 1094 HIV-1-infected adults who initiated ART and had quarterly blood draws for VL and CD4+ T cell count. In VL/CD4+ T cell measurement intervals following undetectable VL, we compared the elevation in VL to detectable levels and CD4+ T cell count changes between intervals when participants had episodes of OIs and intervals when they did not have OIs.</str>
      <str>VL was more likely to be detectable if participants had OIs in the prior three months compared to when they did not (OR=4.0 (95% CI=1.9-8.6)). The CD4+ T cell counts declined 24.1 cells/µL per three months in intervals where the participants had OIs compared to an increase of 21.3 cells/µL per three months in intervals where they did not have OIs (adjusted difference in the rate of CD4+ T cell count change of 61.7 cells/µL per three months (95% CI=13.7-109.7), P value=0.012). The rate of CD4+ T cell count increase was 25.6 cells/µL per three months (95% CI=11.6-39.6) higher for females compared to males (p value=&lt;0.001), 1.4 cells/µL per three months lower per one year increase in age (p value=0.046) and 4 cells/µL per three months lower per 10 cells/µL increase in the starting CD4+ T cell count value (p value=&lt;0.001).</str>
      <str>Episodes of opportunistic infections among patients taking ART with undetectable VL were associated with elevation of HIV RNA VL to detectable levels and decline in CD4+ T cell counts.</str>
      <str>NCT00119093.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The effect of opportunistic illness on HIV RNA viral load and CD4+ T cell count among HIV-positive adults taking antiretroviral therapy.</str>
    <str name="id">23547778</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Exercise training is known to increase fat utilization during exercise. Diets containing antioxidants and branch chain amino acids (BCAAs) are also reported to have potential effects on fat utilization. Cashew apple juice (CAJ) comprises many nutritional components including vitamin C and BCAAs. This study aimed to investigate the effect of CAJ supplementation on substrate utilization during high-intensity exercise in trained and untrained subjects.</str>
      <str>Ten trained and ten untrained men were randomly supplemented with either placebo (PLA) or CAJ at 3.5 ml/kg body mass (BM) /day for 4 weeks with a 4-week washout between treatments in a randomized cross-over design. Before and after the 4-week supplementations all subjects performed cycling exercise at 85% of maximal oxygen consumption for 20 minutes. At rest, before, and immediately after the exercise, venous blood samples were taken to determine glucose, insulin and lipid concentrations. Expired air was collected during the 20 minutes of exercise to calculate substrate utilization.</str>
      <str>During the exercise in both trained and untrained groups, there were lower carbohydrate (CHO) and higher fat oxidation rates and contributions to total energy expenditure after the CAJ supplementation compared to the PLA supplementation (p&lt;0.05). These values were greater in the trained group than the untrained group except CHO oxidation rates (p&lt;0.05), which were not significantly different. Moreover, in both trained and untrained groups, resting plasma vitamin C concentrations were significantly higher after the CAJ supplementation compared to the PLA supplementation, without any change after the PLA supplementation. These values were greater in the trained group than the untrained group (p&lt;0.05). There were no significant differences in glucose, insulin or lipid concentrations between the groups' blood samples.</str>
      <str>The findings of this study suggest that CAJ supplementation enhanced fat oxidation during exercise may enhance endurance performance, but specific studies are needed to assess this possibility.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Cashew apple juice supplementation enhanced fat utilization during high-intensity exercise in trained and untrained men.</str>
    <str name="id">23497120</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>It is recommended that endurance athletes consume carbohydrate (CHO) supplements, providing 6-8% CHO concentration, during exercise &gt; 60 minutes to improve athletic performance. Recently research has compared carbohydrate-protein (CHO-P) supplementation to the traditionally used CHO supplementation during endurance exercise, following these supplementation recommendations, in controlled settings, but not under simulated applied conditions such as a field trial. Therefore, the purpose of the present investigation was to test CHO and CHO-P supplementation under applied conditions such that commercially-available isocaloric (CHO-P &amp; double-carbohydrate [CHO-CHO]) and isocarbohydrate (CHO-P &amp; CHO) supplements were compared to a placebo (PLA), within an outdoor running field trial &gt; 60 minutes in order to asses their influence on endurance performance.</str>
      <str>Twelve male recreational runners completed four, 19.2 km runs, where they were instructed to run at a pace similar to race pace including a final sprint to the finish, which in this case was the final two laps of the course (1.92 km). Supplementation was provided before the start and in 4 km increments. Performance was measured by time to complete the 19.2 km run and last 1.92 km sprint.</str>
      <str>Analyses found no difference between supplements in time to complete the 19.2 km run (PLA = 88.6 ± 11.6 min, CHO = 89.1 ± 11.3 min, CHO-P = 89.1 ± 11.8 min, CHO-CHO = 89.6 ± 11.9 min) or last 1.92 km sprint to the finish (PLA = 8.3 ± 1.2 min, CHO = 8.2 ± 1.2 min, CHO-P = 8.2 ± 1.2 min, CHO-CHO = 8.4 ± 1.5 min).</str>
      <str>When following recommendation for supplementation within a field trial, commercially available CHO and CHO-P supplements do not appear to enhance performance in male recreational runners.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The influence of commercially-available carbohydrate and carbohydrate-protein supplements on endurance running performance in recreational athletes during a field trial.</str>
    <str name="id">23537142</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>In systems biology, quantitative experimental data is the basis of building mathematical models. In most of the cases, they are stored in Excel files and hosted locally. To have a public database for collecting, retrieving and citing experimental raw data as well as experimental conditions is important for both experimentalists and modelers. However, the great effort needed in the data handling procedure and in the data submission procedure becomes the crucial limitation for experimentalists to contribute to a database, thereby impeding the database to deliver its benefit. Moreover, manual copy and paste operations which are commonly used in those procedures increase the chance of making mistakes. Excemplify, a web-based application, proposes a flexible and adaptable template-based solution to solve these problems. Comparing to the normal template based uploading approach, which is supported by some public databases, rather than predefining a format that is potentiall impractical, Excemplify allows users to create their own experiment-specific content templates in different experiment stages and to build corresponding knowledge bases for parsing. Utilizing the embedded knowledge of used templates, Excemplify is able to parse experimental data from the initial setup stage and generate following stages spreadsheets automatically. The proposed solution standardizes the flows of data traveling according to the standard procedures of applying the experiment, cuts down the amount of manual effort and reduces the chance of mistakes caused by manual data handling. In addition, it maintains the context of meta-data from the initial preparation manuscript and improves the data consistency. It interoperates and complements RightField and SEEK as well.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Excemplify: a flexible template based solution, parsing and managing data in spreadsheets for experimentalists.</str>
    <str name="id">23549603</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>This paper presents a study in the domain of semi-automated and fully-automated ontology mapping. A process for inferring additional cross-ontology links within the domain of anatomical ontologies is presented and evaluated on pairs from three model organisms. The results of experiments performed with various external knowledge sources and scoring schemes are discussed.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">A semi-automated approach for anatomical ontology mapping.</str>
    <str name="id">23549604</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Invasive thoughts: change or die!</str>
    <str name="id">23549487</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>While the impact of prior coronary artery bypass graft surgery (CABG) on in-hospital outcomes in patients with ST-elevation myocardial infarction (STEMI) has been described, data are limited on patients with prior percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) undergoing primary PCI in the setting of an STEMI. The aim of the present study was to assess the effect of previous revascularization on in-hospital outcomes in STEMI patients undergoing primary PCI. Between January 2004 and December 2007, a total of 1649 patients underwent primary PCI for STEMI at four New York State hospitals. Baseline clinical and angiographic characteristics and in-hospital outcomes were prospectively collected as part of the New York State PCI Reporting System (PCIRS). Patients with prior surgical or percutaneous coronary revascularization were compared to those without prior coronary revascularization. Of the 1649 patients presenting with STEMI, a total of 93 (5.6%) had prior CABG, 258 (15.7%) had prior PCI, and 1298 (78.7%) had no history of prior coronary revascularization. Patients with prior CABG were significantly older and had higher rates of peripheral vascular disease, diabetes mellitus, congestive heart failure, and prior stroke. Additionally, compared with those patients with a history of prior PCI as well as those without prior coronary revascularization, patients with previous CABG had more left main interventions (24% vs 2% and 2%; P&lt;.001), but were less often treated with drug-eluting stents (47% vs 61% and 72%; P&lt;.001). Despite a low incidence of adverse in-hospital events, prior CABG was associated with higher all-cause in-hospital mortality (6.5% vs 2.2%; P=.012), and as a result, higher overall MACE (6.5% vs 2.7%; P=.039). By multivariate analysis, prior CABG (odds ratio, 3.40; 95% confidence interval, 1.15-10.00) was independently associated with in-hospital mortality. In contrast, patients with prior PCI had similar rates of MACE (4.3% vs 2.7%; P=.18) and in-hospital mortality (3.1% vs 2.2%; P=.4) when compared to the de novo population. Patients with a prior history of CABG, but not prior PCI, undergoing primary PCI in the setting of STEMI have significantly worse in-hospital outcomes when compared with patients who had no prior history of coronary artery revascularization. Thus, only prior surgical - and not percutaneous - revascularization should be considered a significant risk factor in the setting of primary PCI.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The impact of previous revascularization on clinical outcomes in patients undergoing primary percutaneous coronary intervention.</str>
    <str name="id">23549488</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The in-hospital management of patients on warfarin undergoing coronary stent implantation (PCI-S) is variable, and the in-hospital outcome incompletely defined. To determine the adherence to the current recommendations, and the incidence of adverse events, we carried out the prospective, multicenter, observational WARfarin and coronary STENTing (WAR-STENT) registry (ClinicalTrials.gov identifier NCT00722319). All consecutive patients on warfarin undergoing PCI-S at 37 Italian centers were enrolled and followed for 12 months. Outcome measures were: major adverse cardiovascular events (MACE), including cardiovascular death, non-fatal myocardial infarction, need for urgent revascularization, stroke, and venous thromboembolism, and major and minor bleeding. In this paper, we report the in-hospital findings. Out of the 411 patients enrolled, 92% were at non-low (ie, moderate or high) thromboembolic risk. The radial approach and bare-metal stents were used in 61% and 60% of cases, respectively. Drug-eluting stents were essentially reserved to patients with diabetes, which in turn, significantly predicted the implantation of drug-eluting stents (odds ratio [OR], 2.02; 95% confidence interval [CI], 1.29-3.17; P=.002). The in-hospital MACE and major bleeding rates were 2.7% and 2.1%, respectively. At discharge, triple therapy (TT) of warfarin, aspirin, and clopidogrel was prescribed to 76% of patients. Prescription of TT was significantly more frequent in the non-low thromboembolic risk group. Non-low thromboembolic risk, in turn, was a significant predictor of TT prescription (OR, 11.2; 95% CI, 4.83-26.3; P&lt;.0001). In conclusion, real-world warfarin patients undergoing PCI-S are largely managed according to the current recommendations. As a consequence, the risk of in-hospital MACE and major bleedings appears limited and acceptable.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">In-hospital management and outcome of patients on warfarin undergoing coronary stent implantation: results of the multicenter, prospective WARfarin and coronary STENTing (WAR-STENT) registry.</str>
    <str name="id">23549489</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Computed tomography coronary angiography (CTCA) has been successfully integrated with the magnetic navigation system (MNS) to facilitate a roadmap-assisted percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI). The aim of this study was to compare this new approach of PCI versus conventional PCI regarding the difference of contrast usage, x-ray exposure, procedure success, and in-hospital expenses.</str>
      <str>Thirty-eight patients with stable coronary artery disease and coronary artery lesions of ≥70% diameter stenosis diagnosed by both pre-procedure CTCA and coronary angiography (CAG) were enrolled to receive the MNS and CT roadmap-assisted PCI. Another 38 patients were consecutively recruited to receive conventional PCI, matched with the MNS group by the vessel and lesion type base on American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association criteria.</str>
      <str>Regarding the process of the guidewire placement, wherein the technical difference of the two procedures exists, the median contrast usage for guidewire crossing was significantly lower in the MNS group than in the conventional group [0.0 mL (interquartile range [IQR], 0.0-3.0 mL) vs 5.0 mL (IQR, 3.1-6.8 mL); P&lt;.001], with zero contrast usage in 25 of the 44 guidewire placements in the MNS group, but in none of the conventional group; the radiation dosage for guidewire crossing in the MNS group was also significantly lower than in the conventional group (235.8 μGym² [IQR, 134.9-455.1 μGym²] vs 364.4 μGym² [IQR, 223.4-547.2 μGym²]; P=.033). There were no significant differences between the two groups concerning the total contrast usage, total radiation dosage of the PCI, the procedural fees, or the overall in-hospital expenses. All of the enrolled vessels were successfully intervened in both groups.</str>
      <str>In PCI of simple lesions, the application of CT guidance and magnetic navigation had modest impacts on radiation dosage and contrast usage for wire crossing, but no impact on overall radiation dosage or contrast usage for the procedure. In addition, the use of CT roadmap and MNS was likely more expensive compared to PCI using conventional radiographic technique.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Magnetic navigation system and CT roadmap-assisted percutaneous coronary intervention: a comparison to the conventional approach.</str>
    <str name="id">23549490</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The cobalt chromium everolimus-eluting stent (CoCr-EES) has shown the best safety and efficacy profile in the trials conducted so far. Recently, a new EES with a platinum-based platform (PtCr-EES) has been introduced in the market. There is only one study comparing both stents, but with important exclusion criteria.</str>
      <str>We sought to evaluate clinical outcomes with the PtCr-EES compared with the CoCr-EES in an all-comers population. We have conducted a randomized all-comers study aimed to compare these stents in a real-practice scenario.</str>
      <str>A total of 300 patients undergoing revascularization and suitable for long-term dual-antiplatelet therapy were randomized 1:1 to CoCr-EES or PtCr-EES. No exclusion criteria based on clinical presentation or lesion characteristics were applied.</str>
      <str>The clinical and angiographic characteristics were well balanced in both groups without significant differences. At 18 months, the survival free from death and infarction was 93.9% for CoCr-EES and 91.3% for PtCr-EES (P=.3), the survival free from revascularization was 95.2% vs 94.5% (P=.6) and the survival free from death, infarction, and revascularization was 90.6% vs 88%, respectively (P=.4). The incidence of definite or probable thrombosis was 1.3% for CoCr-EES and 0.66% for PtCr-EES (P=.9). No cases of longitudinal stent compression were observed.</str>
      <str>The results of this all-comers trial do not show significant differences between CoCr-EES and PtCr-EES. However, the sample size is not powered to exclude potential differences between stents.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">A real all-comers randomized trial comparing Xience Prime and Promus Element stents.</str>
    <str name="id">23549491</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The efficacy and safety of titanium-nitride-oxide-coated bioactive stents (BASs) were demonstrated in prior studies. In a prospective registry, we sought to explore the extent of neointimal coverage of stent struts by optical coherence tomography (OCT) at 30 days following the implantation of BASs in an unselected non-diabetic population.</str>
      <str>We enrolled 20 consecutive nondiabetic patients who underwent BAS implantation. OCT images were obtained at 30-day follow-up. Binary stent strut coverage was defined as the number of covered struts as a percentage of all analyzed struts.</str>
      <str>Patients underwent OCT examination at an average of 30.5 ± 5.7 days following stent implantation. In these, 411 cross-sections were analyzed, including 3780 struts. Binary stent strut coverage was 97.2%, and the prevalence of malapposed struts was 3.2%. Mean neointimal thickness was 109.7 ± 83.6 μm.</str>
      <str>In the current evaluation by OCT at 30-day follow-up after BAS implantation in an unselected non-diabetic cohort, binary stent strut coverage was satisfactory and the prevalence of malapposed struts was low.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Vascular healing early after titanium-nitride-oxide-coated stent implantation assessed by optical coherence tomography.</str>
    <str name="id">23549492</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Significant paravalvular aortic regurgitation (PAR) after transcatheter aortic valve implantation (TAVI) is associated with negative clinical consequences. We hypothesize that increased eccentricity of the aortic annulus is associated with greater PAR.</str>
      <str>Patients with severe aortic stenosis underwent multidetector computed tomography (MDCT) before successful TAVI with the Medtronic CoreValve bioprosthesis. The smallest (D(min)) and largest (D(max)) orthogonal diameters in the basal ring of the aortic annulus were determined. We defined circularity of aortic annulus using the eccentricity index (1 - D(min)/D(max)). The primary endpoint was early occurrence of significant PAR, defined as &gt; grade II PAR by postprocedural aortography.</str>
      <str>Eighty-four patients, mean age 83 ± 4 years with a mean aortic valve area of 0.7 ± 0.2 cm² were included. Twenty patients had postprocedural PAR &gt; grade II. Using a receiver operating characteristic (ROC) analysis, eccentricity index correlated with significant PAR (AUC = 0.834; P=.034). A retrospectively determined eccentricity index cut-off of &gt;0.25 was related to significant PAR with a sensitivity of 80%, specificity of 86%, and negative predictive value of 95% (P&lt;.001). On univariate logistic regression, eccentricity index of &gt;0.25 (P&lt;.001) and device implantation depth (P=.015) correlated with significant PAR, while other parameters such as annular calcification and cover index did not. On multivariate analysis including only parameters with P&lt;.1 on univariate analysis, eccentricity index &gt;0.25 was the sole independent predictor of significant PAR.</str>
      <str>Eccentricity index is related to significant PAR after TAVI with Medtronic CoreValve. Further larger studies are required to determine the utility of this novel index in screening suitable patients for this procedure.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Relationship of aortic annular eccentricity and paravalvular regurgitation post transcatheter aortic valve implantation with CoreValve.</str>
    <str name="id">23549493</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Transcatheter aortic valve implantation (TAVI) is an emerging technology used to treat high-risk patients with severe aortic stenosis. During TAVI with the CoreValve ReValving System, a balloon is used for the reduction of paravalvular regurgitation. However, in this paper, we describe the "balloon withdrawal" technique through which the positioning of a second valve can be avoided in case of initial malpositioning. The result of the technique was rather encouraging, and minimal paravalvular aortic regurgitation was recorded after echocardiographic assessment.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">"Balloon withdrawal technique" to correct prosthesis malposition and treat paravalvular aortic regurgitation during TAVI.</str>
    <str name="id">23549494</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Vascular and bleeding complications are a known risk of cardiac catheterization. In this article, we report a neck hematoma after left-sided transradial cardiac catheterization, which is a known but rarely reported complication of this procedure.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Pain in the neck: a rare complication of transradial cardiac catheterization.</str>
    <str name="id">23549495</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>While coronary artery bypass grafting (CABG) has been the standard of care for patients with unprotected left main coronary artery disease, advances in percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) have made stent placement a reasonable alternative in selected patients. In this review, we address the results of studies comparing PCI with CABG, discuss the invasive evaluation of these patients, and the technical approach to percutaneous revascularization. Furthermore, we discuss future pivotal trials, which will help define long-term outcomes comparing PCI with surgery.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Myocardial revascularization in patients with left main coronary disease.</str>
    <str name="id">23549496</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <str name="medline_article_title">An overhanging intracoronary stent: an incidental finding or the Sword of Damocles?</str>
    <str name="id">23549497</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>We report 2 cases of very late stent thrombosis (VLST) in patients previously treated with drug-eluting stent (DES). In both cases, VLST occurred during intense physical activities at high altitudes. Exposure to high altitudes alters the coagulation cascade, platelet morphology, and function, resulting in a hypercoagulable state. In addition, strenuous exercise provokes a procoagulant state along with increasing the risk of endothelial damage through the effects on coronary blood flow. In light of these cases, we hypothesize that individuals who are involved in intense physical activities at high altitudes may be at increased risk of stent thrombosis. Use of DES in such patients should be carefully considered.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Physical exertion at high altitude--another risk factor for coronary stent thrombosis?</str>
    <str name="id">23549498</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Patients undergoing right ventricular outflow tract reconstruction are subject to valve and cusp degeneration later in life, requiring further intervention to alleviate the pulmonary regurgitation that ensues. In these cases, percutaneous pulmonary valve implantation can be an effective alternative to surgery; however, since the indications have been limited to dysfunctional valved conduits, only a small number of patients have access to this treatment option. We present the case of an 18-year-old male with a patch-enlarged right ventricle to pulmonary artery conduit who underwent pulmonary valve implantation using two Melody transcatheter pulmonary valves (Medtronic, Inc) into the proximal right and left branch pulmonary arteries.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">A concert in the heart: bilateral Melody valve implantation in the branch pulmonary arteries.</str>
    <str name="id">23549499</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The retrograde approach using collaterals has been introduced for percutaneous dilatation and opening of chronic total occlusion of the coronary arteries. The controlled antegrade and retrograde tracking (CART) strategy has been developed to improve guidewire crossing and successful recanalization. We herein describe a case of left anterior descending chronic total occlusion that was successfully recanalized using ipsilateral intraseptal collateral by reverse CART technique.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Successful recanalization of a left anterior descending chronic total occlusion via an ipsilateral intraseptal collateral using reverse CART technique.</str>
    <str name="id">23549500</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Aorto-right ventricular tunnel (ARVT) is a very rare, congenital, abnormal extracardiac channel that connects the ascending aorta at or above the sinotubular junction to the cavity of the right ventricle. Only 16 cases have been reported thus far in the English literature. We report the first transcatheter closure of ARVT with the Amplatzer duct occluder II in an infant, with both coronary arteries arising from the left coronary sinus and with biventricular apical non-compaction.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Closure of aorto-right ventricular tunnel with Amplatzer duct occluder II.</str>
    <str name="id">23549501</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Percutaneous closure of postoperative malaligned residual atrial septal defect was successfully performed from the transjugular approach under transesophageal echocardiography guidance in a 38-year-old symptomatic woman with patent femoral venous access using the usual hardware. This demonstrates the feasibility of transjugular approach as an alternative to femoral or transhepatic approaches in patients with difficult atrial septal anatomy who are usually referred for surgery.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Percutaneous transjugular device closure of postoperative residual atrial septal defect.</str>
    <str name="id">23549502</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Von Willebrand disease (vWD) results from quantitative or qualitative deficiency of von Willebrand factor (vWF). The occurrence of myocardial infarction is very rare in patients with vWD. A few case reports of acute coronary syndrome (ACS) in vWD patients are present in the literature, but no definite management recommendations are available for such patients.</str>
      <str>We report a case of successful percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) with bare-metal stent (BMS) implantation in a 46-year-old woman with type 1 vWD and history of coronary artery disease (CAD). She received periprocedural dual-antiplatelet therapy for 2 weeks and then continued aspirin without any bleeding complications.</str>
      <str>The optimal management of patients with vWD and ACS is complex and presents a therapeutic challenge. We propose that dual-antiplatelet therapy can be used safely in most vWD patients presenting with ACS as most of them are type 1 vWD. PCI with BMS can be done safely. Long-term management of these patients requires a systemic approach including hematological consultation, ascertaining vWF levels, as well as patient education and close outpatient follow-up.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Percutaneous coronary intervention and the management of acute coronary syndromes in patients with von Willebrand disease.</str>
    <str name="id">23549503</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The objective of this experimental study was to investigate a possible myocardial involvement in acute liver failure.</str>
      <str>A porcine model of acute liver failure induced by hepatic devascularization was used. Twenty animals were allocated to the Acute Liver Failure (ALF) or Control Group (CG). Serum cardiac troponin I (cTnI), MB isoenzyme of creatine kinase (CK-MB), and also hemodynamic variables were measured and compared before surgery (T1), at 4 hr (T2), and at 7 hr (T3) after the end of surgery.</str>
      <str>Data from 10 pigs in the ALF and 7 in the CG were analyzed. In the ALF group, cTnI increased from 0.3 ± 0.055 to 0.35 ± 0.696 and 0.39 ± 0.06 ng/ml at T1, T2, and T3 time points, respectively (p &lt; .001). In the CG, cTnI was not significantly changed from 0.29 ± 0.07, to 0.31 ± 0.01, and 0.31 ± 0.11 ng/ml at T1, T2, and T3 time points, respectively (p = .895). A statistically significant difference was found in cTnI between the groups at T3 (z = -2.93, p = .002). CK-MB increased significantly in both groups: in ALF group, CK-MB changed from 3.43 ± 0.53 to 4.33 ± 0.73 and 7.14 ± 1.12 ng/ml at T1, T2, and T3 time points, respectively (p &lt; .001). In the CG, CK-MB changed from 3.6 ± 0.597 to 4.6 ± 1.07 and 6.2 ± 1.17 ng/ml at T1, T2, and T3 time points, respectively, (p = .001). Mean arterial pressure (MAP) was significantly reduced in the ALF group.</str>
      <str>In a porcine model of acute liver failure, a significant increase of cTnI serum levels was found, indicating that a subclinical myocardial damage may occur as a result of heart involvement in the multiple organ dysfunction.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Myocardial involvement during ischemia-induced acute liver failure in the pig.</str>
    <str name="id">23273174</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Anti-reflux barrier (ARB) resistance may be useful to test new treatments for gastroesophageal reflux (GER). The ARB has been estimated by increasing gastric yield pressure (GYP) and gastric yield volume (GYV) in animal models but has not been validated. This study aimed to develop an experimental model suitable for assessing the ARB resistance to increasing intragastric pressure and volume and its reproducibility in a seven-day interval. Ten two-month-old female Large-White swine were studied. Intragastric pressure and volume were recorded using a digital system connected to a Foley catheter inserted through gastrostomy into the stomach. GYP and GYV were defined as the gastric pressure and volume able to yield gastric contents into the esophagus detected by esophageal pH. A sudden pH drop below 3 sustained during 5 min was considered diagnostic for gastric yield. Animals were studied again after seven days. On days 0 and 7, there were no significant differences for GYP (mean ± SD = 7.66 ± 3.02 mmHg vs. 7.07 ± 3.54 mmHg, p = .686) and GYV (636.70 ± 216.74 ml vs. 608.30 ± 276.66 ml; p = .299), respectively. Concordance correlation coefficient (ρc) was significant for GYP (ρc = 0.634, 95% CI = 0.141-0.829, p = .006), but not for GYV (ρc = 0.291, 95% CI = -0.118 to 0.774, p = .196). This study demonstrated an experimental model, assessing the ARB resistance. GYP seems to be a more reliable parameter than GYV for assessment of ARB resistance.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Gastric yield pressure and gastric yield volume to assess anti-reflux barrier in a porcine model.</str>
    <str name="id">23273175</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The tissue content of E-cadherin changes in inflammatory bowel diseases; however, similar changes have not yet been evaluated in diversion colitis.</str>
      <str>The aim of this study was to evaluate the tissue expression of E-cadherin in the mucosa of the colon in both segments with and without a fecal stream.</str>
      <str>Sixty Wistar rats were subjected to deviation of fecal stream by proximal colostomy in left colon and a distal mucosal fistula. Animals were divided into three experimental groups that were sacrificed 6, 12, and 18 weeks after surgery. In each experimental group, five animals underwent laparotomy without intestinal deviation (control subgroup). Colitis was diagnosed based on the presence of three independent histological parameters: reduction of the crypt length, neutrophil infiltration of the mucosa and submucosa, and epithelial erosion or ulceration. The E-cadherin expression was evaluated by immunohistochemistry and the tissue levels by computerized morphometry. The Mann-Whitney and Kruskal-Wallis test were used to compare the groups adopting a significance level of 5% (p &lt; .05).</str>
      <str>Segments without fecal stream showed a reduction in E-cadherin content when compared with segments with fecal stream. In the segments with a fecal stream, E-cadherin was expressed at the apical surface of colon glands, while segments without fecal stream showed a decrease in the amount of apical E-cadherin. The content of E-cadherin was maintained over the entire time of the intestinal exclusion.</str>
      <str>Diversion of the fecal stream decreases the expression of E-cadherin of the colon epithelium.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">E-cadherin expression in colonic mucosa with and without fecal stream.</str>
    <str name="id">23273176</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Acute cholecystitis is a common cause of emergency hospital admission. Ultrasonography (US) plays a significant role in the prompt diagnosis of this medical condition. However, it is difficult to find a radiologist in attendance for performing gallbladder US "beyond daytime and on weekends." With this standpoint, we decided to assess prospectively the accuracy of surgeon-performed gallbladder US for identifying acute cholecystitis in patients with cholelithiasis.</str>
      <str>Seventy-one consecutive patients awaiting elective or acute gallbladder surgery were included in this study. The US findings of surgeons and radiologists are compared with the histopathology reports. The sensitivity, specificity, accuracy, PPV (positive predictive value), and NPV (negative predictive value) for acute cholecystitis by both surgeon-performed ultrasound (SPUS) and radiologist-performed ultrasound (RPUS) were evaluated.</str>
      <str>Both radiologists and surgeons visualized the gallstones of each patient in all cases. The sensitivity, specificity, accuracy, and NPV for acute cholecystitis by SPUS were 84.2%, 92.1%, 90%, and 94%, respectively, whereas the sensitivity, specificity, accuracy, and NPV for acute cholecystitis by RPUS were 92.3%, 85.9%, 87.1%, and 98%, respectively.</str>
      <str>Both SPUS and RPUS had a high accuracy rate in electing the acute cholecystitis. Our data support the fact that the use of US by general surgeons is effective in the diagnosis of acute cholecystitis.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Accuracy of surgeon-performed gallbladder ultrasound in identification of acute cholecystitis.</str>
    <str name="id">23273179</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The authors have extensive experience in surgery, anesthesia, and perioperative care in both miniature and domestic swine in the research setting. This manuscript describes the techniques that have been developed over the last four decades while developing porcine surgical models and their use in translational research. Swine are conditioned and socialized during a seven-day period prior to entering into a survival surgical protocol. Housing is designed to be nonstressful and accommodate the needs of the species. Induction of anesthesia is generally performed in the animal's pen. Injectable agents are administered sc in the neck using a butterfly catheter technique. The anesthetic protocol is designed to consider the physiologic effects of the agents and their potential effects on the research being performed. Complete aseptic technique is performed and includes final application of adhesive iodine impregnated drapes over the surgical site. Preemptive analgesia is performed using parenteral analgesics, local anesthetics, and/or epidural analgesics. Animals are monitored intensively intraoperatively and during the postoperative period with frequent recordings of physiologic parameters. Observation during the postoperative period is continuous until the animal fully recovers the righting reflex. Observations of the animals in the postoperative period are performed at least daily until surgical incisions are healed. In protocols which create defects or impede physiologic function daily monitoring may have to be performed in conjunction with specific therapies or tests throughout the duration of the protocol.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Best practices for performing experimental surgery in swine.</str>
    <str name="id">23281597</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Hippocrates of Cos.</str>
    <str name="id">23547622</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The aim of this study was to investigate the effects of oral carbohydrate solution (CHO) on perioperative discomfort, biochemistry, hemodynamics, and patient satisfaction in elective surgery patients under general anesthesia. Sixty cases in ASA I-II group who were planned to have operation under general anesthesia were included in the study. The cases were randomly divided into two groups having 30 subjects in each. The patients in the study group were given CHO in the evening prior to the surgery and 2-3 hr before the anesthesia while routine fasting was applied in the control group. In the study group; 2-3 hr before the surgery; malaise, thirst, hunger, and weakness; just before the surgery malaise, thirst, hunger, and fatigue; 2 hr after the operation thirst, hunger, weakness, and concentration difficulty; 24 hr after the operation malaise and weakness were found significantly lower. Fasting blood glucose (FBG) level was found to be higher in the control group at the 90th min of the operation. Gastric volumes were higher in the control group; gastric pH values were found significantly higher in the study group. The level of anxiety and depression risk rate were found lower in the study group. In conclusion, preoperative CHO reduces perioperative discomfort and improves perioperative well being when compared to overnight fasting.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Oral carbohydrate supplementation reduces preoperative discomfort in laparoscopic cholecystectomy.</str>
    <str name="id">23547623</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To evaluate the safety and efficacy of laparoscopic cholecystectomy (LC) in patients with a history of gastrectomy.</str>
      <str>The clinical data of 9,403 consecutive patients who underwent LC from January 2003 to September 2010 in our hospital were retrospectively analyzed; 30 of them had undergone previous gastrectomy. We compared the operative duration, hospitalization, and conversion rate between patients with, and those randomized selected patients without, a history of gastrectomy.</str>
      <str>All patients were treated by laparoscopic procedure successfully. The mean operative duration (55.00 min vs. 29.63 min, P &lt; .05) and mean hospitalization duration (4.57 days vs. 3.00 days, P &lt; .05) were significantly longer in the patients with a history of gastrecotomy. There are no complications such as bile duct and bowel injury in control group, however two bile duct injuries emerged in the observed group, which required surgical intervention.</str>
      <str>Although the operation is difficult, LC is a safe and effective treatment for the patients with a history of gastrectomy.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Laparoscopic cholecystectomy with previous gastrectomy.</str>
    <str name="id">23547624</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Rapid spontaneous resolution of traumatic acute subdural hematoma is an infrequent phenomenon and mainly develops in a case of simple acute subdural hematoma without parenchymal contusion. However, it has been rarely reported in a pediatric case with severe initial head injury.</str>
      <str>A 7-year-old Asian girl with traumatic acute subdural hematoma was transferred to our hospital for an emergency operation based on the results of an initial computed tomography scan and neurological examination. However, a repeat computed tomography scan two hours after trauma disclosed considerable reduction of the hematoma and midline shift with neurological improvements. Serial follow-up imaging studies demonstrated apparent redistribution of the hematoma over the cerebellar tentorium, posterior interhemispheric fissure and subarachnoid space. The patient was discharged with mild confusion 40 days after the admission.</str>
      <str>A follow-up computed tomography scan is strongly recommended before surgery when a child with a severe head injury presents with any sign of neurological improvement, especially with a mixed density hematoma on the initial computed tomography scan.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Rapid resolution of acute subdural hematoma in child with severe head injury: a case report.</str>
    <str name="id">23497374</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Small-cell colon carcinoma is a very rare disease among colon neoplasms; it is difficult to achieve long-term survival due to its aggressive tumor behavior. Here we report the long-term survival of a patient with advanced small-cell colon carcinoma achieved by a combination of surgery and continuous chemotherapy.</str>
      <str>A 67-year-old Japanese man underwent abdominal computed tomography in our institution for follow up after gastrectomy, and abnormal thickness of the sigmoid colon wall was revealed. An endoscopy demonstrated a 20mm Bormann 2 lesion with central ulceration located 20cm from the anal verge. A sigmoidectomy was performed. Histologically, the tumor deeply invaded the tissue and extended beyond the serosa, and was diagnosed as small-cell carcinoma. Cisplatin plus irinotecan was administered for adjuvant chemotherapy. Nine months after surgery, a follow-up computed tomography showed an enlarged lymph node behind the inferior vena cava and a 15×8mm nodule located at the ventral side of the cecum. Under consideration of progressive disease, cisplatin plus irinotecan therapy was performed again using the same regimen. After nine cycles of cisplatin plus irinotecan therapy, a follow-up gastric endoscopy demonstrated external tumor invasion to the duodenum wall. Carboplatin plus etoposide therapy was selected as a third-line regimen. After six cycles of carboplatin plus etoposide therapy, the recurrence sites were maintained in a stable condition, and the survival time reached approximately 30 months after the initial surgery.</str>
      <str>We report the long-term survival of a patient with advanced small-cell colon carcinoma. In the future, the accumulation and analysis of rare cases that obtain a better survival time will contribute to clarifying neuroendocrine carcinoma biology, and help to improve the prognosis.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Advanced small-cell colon carcinoma: a case report.</str>
    <str name="id">23506215</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>A high-quality gold standard is vital for supervised, machine learning-based, clinical natural language processing (NLP) systems. In clinical NLP projects, expert annotators traditionally create the gold standard. However, traditional annotation is expensive and time-consuming. To reduce the cost of annotation, general NLP projects have turned to crowdsourcing based on Web 2.0 technology, which involves submitting smaller subtasks to a coordinated marketplace of workers on the Internet. Many studies have been conducted in the area of crowdsourcing, but only a few have focused on tasks in the general NLP field and only a handful in the biomedical domain, usually based upon very small pilot sample sizes. In addition, the quality of the crowdsourced biomedical NLP corpora were never exceptional when compared to traditionally-developed gold standards. The previously reported results on medical named entity annotation task showed a 0.68 F-measure based agreement between crowdsourced and traditionally-developed corpora.</str>
      <str>Building upon previous work from the general crowdsourcing research, this study investigated the usability of crowdsourcing in the clinical NLP domain with special emphasis on achieving high agreement between crowdsourced and traditionally-developed corpora.</str>
      <str>To build the gold standard for evaluating the crowdsourcing workers' performance, 1042 clinical trial announcements (CTAs) from the ClinicalTrials.gov website were randomly selected and double annotated for medication names, medication types, and linked attributes. For the experiments, we used CrowdFlower, an Amazon Mechanical Turk-based crowdsourcing platform. We calculated sensitivity, precision, and F-measure to evaluate the quality of the crowd's work and tested the statistical significance (P&lt;.001, chi-square test) to detect differences between the crowdsourced and traditionally-developed annotations.</str>
      <str>The agreement between the crowd's annotations and the traditionally-generated corpora was high for: (1) annotations (0.87, F-measure for medication names; 0.73, medication types), (2) correction of previous annotations (0.90, medication names; 0.76, medication types), and excellent for (3) linking medications with their attributes (0.96). Simple voting provided the best judgment aggregation approach. There was no statistically significant difference between the crowd and traditionally-generated corpora. Our results showed a 27.9% improvement over previously reported results on medication named entity annotation task.</str>
      <str>This study offers three contributions. First, we proved that crowdsourcing is a feasible, inexpensive, fast, and practical approach to collect high-quality annotations for clinical text (when protected health information was excluded). We believe that well-designed user interfaces and rigorous quality control strategy for entity annotation and linking were critical to the success of this work. Second, as a further contribution to the Internet-based crowdsourcing field, we will publicly release the JavaScript and CrowdFlower Markup Language infrastructure code that is necessary to utilize CrowdFlower's quality control and crowdsourcing interfaces for named entity annotations. Finally, to spur future research, we will release the CTA annotations that were generated by traditional and crowdsourced approaches.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Web 2.0-based crowdsourcing for high-quality gold standard development in clinical natural language processing.</str>
    <str name="id">23548263</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>A prognostic model that predicts overall survival (OS) for metastatic urothelial cancer (MetUC) patients treated with cisplatin-based chemotherapy was developed, validated, and compared with a commonly used Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center (MSKCC) risk-score model. Data from 7 protocols that enrolled 308 patients with MetUC were pooled. An external multi-institutional dataset was used to validate the model. The primary measurement of predictive discrimination was Harrell's c-index, computed with 95% confidence interval (CI). The final model included four pretreatment variables to predict OS: visceral metastases, albumin, performance status, and hemoglobin. The Harrell's c-index was 0.67 for the four-variable model and 0.64 for the MSKCC risk-score model, with a prediction improvement for OS (the U statistic and its standard deviation were used to calculate the two-sided P = .002). In the validation cohort, the c-indices for the four-variable and the MSKCC risk-score models were 0.63 (95% CI = 0.56 to 0.69) and 0.58 (95% CI = 0.52 to 0.65), respectively, with superiority of the four-variable model compared with the MSKCC risk-score model for OS (the U statistic and its standard deviation were used to calculate the two-sided P = .02).</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Prognostic model for predicting survival of patients with metastatic urothelial cancer treated with cisplatin-based chemotherapy.</str>
    <str name="id">23411591</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The long and short of telomeres and cancer association studies.</str>
    <str name="id">23468461</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Recent meta-analyses have suggested that short telomere length was associated with increased risk of cancer. We therefore tested the hypotheses that short telomere length was associated with increased risk of cancer and with increased risk of early death after cancer.</str>
      <str>We measured leukocyte telomere length in a prospective study of 47 102 Danish general population participants from the Copenhagen City Heart Study and the Copenhagen General Population Study. Participants were followed for up to 20 years for cancer diagnosis and death. Follow-up was 100% complete. All statistical tests were two-sided.</str>
      <str>Telomere length decreased linearly with increasing age (P &lt;.001). During follow-up, we observed 3142 first cancers and, among these individuals, 1730 deaths. Decreasing quartiles of telomere length were associated with decreasing survival after cancer (log-rank P &lt;.001). Multivariable-adjusted hazard ratios of early death were 1.31 (95% confidence interval [CI] = 1.14 to 1.52) in individuals in the quartile and 1.43 (95% CI = 1.13 to 1.80) in individuals in the decile with the shortest telomeres vs the longest. Unadjusted hazard ratios of cancer risk were 1.74 (95% CI = 1.58 to 1.93) and 2.00 (95% CI = 1.70 to 2.35) in individuals in the quartile and decile with the shortest vs longest telomeres; however, multivariable adjustment changed these hazard ratios to 0.98 (95% CI = 0.88 to 1.08) and 0.95 (95% CI = 0.80 to 1.11), mainly because of age adjustment.</str>
      <str>Short telomere length is associated with reduced survival after cancer but not with cancer risk. The latter contrasts with findings from recent meta-analyses.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Short telomere length, cancer survival, and cancer risk in 47102 individuals.</str>
    <str name="id">23468462</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Ras-related nuclear protein (Ran) is required for cancer cell survival in vitro and human cancer progression, but the molecular mechanisms are largely unknown.</str>
      <str>We investigated the effect of the v-myc myelocytomatosis viral oncogene homolog (Myc) on Ran expression by Western blot, chromatin immunoprecipitation, and luciferase reporter assays and the effects of Myc and Ran expression in cancer cells by soft-agar, cell adhesion, and invasion assays. The correlation between Myc and Ran and the association with patient survival were investigated in 14 independent patient cohorts (n = 2430) and analyzed with Spearman's rank correlation and Kaplan-Meier plots coupled with Wilcoxon-Gehan tests, respectively. All statistical tests were two-sided.</str>
      <str>Myc binds to the upstream sequence of Ran and transactivates Ran promoter activity. Overexpression of Myc upregulates Ran expression, whereas knockdown of Myc downregulates Ran expression. Myc or Ran overexpression in breast cancer cells is associated with cancer progression and metastasis. Knockdown of Ran reverses the effect induced by Myc overexpression in breast cancer cells. In clinical data, a positive association between Myc and Ran expression was revealed in 288 breast cancer and 102 lung cancer specimens. Moreover, Ran expression levels differentiate better or poorer survival in Myc overexpressing breast (χ2 = 24.1; relative risk [RR] = 9.1, 95% confidence interval [CI] = 3.3 to 24.7, P &lt; .001) and lung (χ2 = 6.04; RR = 2.8, 95% CI = 1.2 to 6.3; P = .01) cancer cohorts.</str>
      <str>Our results suggest that Ran is required for and is a potential therapeutic target of Myc-driven cancer progression in both breast and lung cancers.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">RanGTPase: a candidate for Myc-mediated cancer progression.</str>
    <str name="id">23468463</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Real world effectiveness of population-based roll out of human papillomavirus vaccination against rates of genital warts.</str>
    <str name="id">23486549</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Incidence of condyloma, or genital warts (GW), is the earliest possible disease outcome to measure when assessing the effectiveness of human papillomavirus (HPV) vaccination strategies. Efficacy trials that follow prespecified inclusion and exclusion criteria may not be fully generalizable to real-life HPV vaccination programs, which target a broader segment of the population. We assessed GW incidence after on-demand vaccination with quadrivalent HPV vaccine using individual-level data from the entire Swedish population.</str>
      <str>An open cohort of girls and women aged 10 to 44 years living in Sweden between 2006 and 2010 (N &gt; 2.2 million) was linked to multiple population registers to identify incident GW in relation to HPV vaccination. For vaccine effectiveness, incidence rate ratios of GW were estimated using time-to-event analyses with adjustment for attained age and parental education level, stratifying on age at first vaccination.</str>
      <str>A total of 124 000 girls and women were vaccinated between 2006 and 2010. Girls and women with at least one university-educated parent were 15 times more likely to be vaccinated before age 20 years than girls and women whose parents did not complete high school (relative risk ratio = 15.45, 95% confidence interval [CI] = 14.65 to 16.30). Among those aged older than 20 years, GW rates declined among the unvaccinated, suggesting that HPV vaccines were preferentially used by women at high risk of GW. Vaccination effectiveness was 76% (95% CI = 73% to 79%) among those who received three doses of the vaccine with their first dose before age 20 years. Vaccine effectiveness was highest in girls vaccinated before age 14 years (effectiveness = 93%, 95% CI = 73% to 98%).</str>
      <str>Young age at first vaccination is imperative for maximizing quadrivalent HPV vaccine effectiveness.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Quadrivalent human papillomavirus vaccine effectiveness: a Swedish national cohort study.</str>
    <str name="id">23486550</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The metabolic alterations of cancer cells represent an opportunity for developing selective antineoplastic treatments. We investigated the therapeutic potential of ST1326, an inhibitor of carnitine-palmitoyl transferase 1A (CPT1A), the rate-limiting enzyme for fatty acid (FA) import into mitochondria.</str>
      <str>ST1326 was tested on in vitro and in vivo models of Burkitt's lymphoma, in which c-myc, which drives cellular demand for FA metabolism, is highly overexpressed. We performed assays to evaluate the effect of ST1326 on proliferation, FA oxidation, and FA mitochondrial channeling in Raji cells. The therapeutic efficacy of ST1326 was tested by treating Eµ-myc mice (control: n = 29; treatment: n = 24 per group), an established model of c-myc-mediated lymphomagenesis. Experiments were performed on spleen-derived c-myc-overexpressing B cells to clarify the role of c-myc in conferring sensitivity to ST1326. Survival was evaluated with Kaplan-Meier analyses. All statistical tests were two-sided.</str>
      <str>ST1326 blocked both long- and short-chain FA oxidation and showed a strong cytotoxic effect on Burkitt's lymphoma cells (on Raji cells at 72 hours: half maximal inhibitory concentration = 8.6 μM). ST1326 treatment induced massive cytoplasmic lipid accumulation, impairment of proper mitochondrial FA channeling, and reduced availability of cytosolic acetyl coenzyme A, a fundamental substrate for de novo lipogenesis. Moreover, treatment with ST1326 in Eµ-myc transgenic mice prevented tumor formation (P = .01), by selectively impairing the growth of spleen-derived primary B cells overexpressing c-myc (wild-type cells + ST1326 vs. Eµ-myc cells + ST1326: 99.75% vs. 57.5%, difference = 42.25, 95% confidence interval of difference = 14% to 70%; P = .01).</str>
      <str>Our data indicate that it is possible to tackle c-myc-driven tumorigenesis by altering lipid metabolism and exploiting the neoplastic cell addiction to FA oxidation.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Carnitine-acyltransferase system inhibition, cancer cell death, and prevention of myc-induced lymphomagenesis.</str>
    <str name="id">23486551</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <str name="medline_article_title">An engineer tackles metastasis.</str>
    <str name="id">23492348</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Contrast-enhanced ultrasound may aid prostate cancer detection.</str>
    <str name="id">23492350</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Adult survivors of childhood cancer are known to be at increased risk of subsequent malignancy, but only limited data exist describing the incidence and risk factors for secondary renal carcinoma. Among 14 358 5-year survivors diagnosed between 1970 and 1986, we estimated standardized incidence ratios (SIRs) for subsequent renal carcinoma and identified associations with primary cancer therapy using Poisson regression. Twenty-six survivors were diagnosed with renal carcinoma (median = 22.6 years from diagnosis; range = 6.3-35.7 years), reflecting a statistically significant excess (SIR = 8.0, 95% confidence interval [CI] = 5.2 to 11.7) compared with the general population. Highest risk was observed among neuroblastoma survivors (SIR = 85.8, 95% CI = 38.4 to 175.2) and, in multivariable analyses, with renal-directed radiotherapy of 5 Gy or greater (relative risk [RR] = 3.8, 95% CI = 1.6 to 9.3) and platinum-based chemotherapy (RR = 3.5, 95% CI = 1.0 to 11.2). To our knowledge, this is the first report of an association between cisplatin and subsequent renal carcinoma among survivors of childhood cancer.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Renal carcinoma after childhood cancer: a report from the childhood cancer survivor study.</str>
    <str name="id">23515901</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Handrim wheelchair propulsion is a complex bimanual motor task. The bimanually applied forces on the rims determine the speed and direction of locomotion. Measurements of forces and torques on the handrim are important to study status and change of propulsion technique (and consequently mechanical strain) due to processes of learning, training or the wheelchair configuration. The purpose of this study was to compare the simultaneous outcomes of two different measurement-wheels attached to the different sides of the wheelchair, to determine measurement consistency within and between these wheels given the expected inter- and intra-limb variability as a consequence of motor control.</str>
      <str>Nine able-bodied subjects received a three-week low-intensity handrim wheelchair practice intervention. They then performed three four-minute trials of wheelchair propulsion in an instrumented hand rim wheelchair on a motor-driven treadmill at a fixed belt speed. The two measurement-wheels on each side of the wheelchair measured forces and torques of one of the two upper limbs, which simultaneously perform the push action over time. The resulting data were compared as direct output using cross-correlation on the torque around the wheel-axle. Calculated push characteristics such as power production and speed were compared using an intra-class correlation.</str>
      <str>Measured torque around the wheel axle of the two measurement-wheels had a high average cross-correlation of 0.98 (std=0.01). Unilateral mean power output over a minute was found to have an intra-class correlation of 0.89 between the wheels. Although the difference over the pushes between left and right power output had a high variability, the mean difference between the measurement-wheels was low at 0.03 W (std=1.60). Other push characteristics showed even higher ICC's (&gt;0.9).</str>
      <str>A good agreement between both measurement-wheels was found at the level of the power output. This indicates a high comparability of the measurement-wheels for the different propulsion parameters. Data from both wheels seem suitable to be used together or interchangeably in experiments on motor control and wheelchair propulsion performance. A high variability in forces and timing between the left and right side were found during the execution of this bimanual task, reflecting the human motor control process.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Variability in bimanual wheelchair propulsion: consistency of two instrumented wheels during handrim wheelchair propulsion on a motor driven treadmill.</str>
    <str name="id">23360756</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Leukocytes are believed to be involved in delayed cell death following traumatic brain injury (TBI). However, data demonstrating that blood-borne inflammatory cells are present in the injured brain prior to the onset of secondary brain damage have been inconclusive. We therefore investigated both the interaction between leukocytes and the cerebrovascular endothelium using in vivo imaging and the accumulation of leukocytes in the penumbra following experimentally induced TBI.</str>
      <str>Experimental TBI was induced in C57/Bl6 mice (n = 42) using the controlled cortical impact (CCI) injury model, and leukocyte-endothelium interactions (LEI) were quantified using both intravital fluorescence microscopy (IVM) of superficial vessels and 2-photon microscopy of cortical vessels for up to 14 h post-CCI. In a separate experimental group, leukocyte accumulation and secondary lesion expansion were analyzed in mice that were sacrificed 15 min, 2, 6, 12, 24, or 48 h after CCI (n = 48). Finally, leukocyte adhesion was blocked with anti-CD18 antibodies, and the effects on LEI and secondary lesion expansion were determined 16 (n = 12) and 24 h (n = 21), respectively, following TBI.</str>
      <str>One hour after TBI leukocytes and leukocyte-platelet aggregates started to roll on the endothelium of pial venules, whereas no significant LEI were observed in pial arterioles or in sham-operated mice. With a delay of &gt;4 h, leukocytes and aggregates did also firmly adhere to the venular endothelium. In deep cortical vessels (250 μm) LEIs were much less pronounced. Transmigration of leukocytes into the brain parenchyma only became significant after the tissue became necrotic. Treatment with anti-CD18 antibodies reduced adhesion by 65%; however, this treatment had no effect on secondary lesion expansion.</str>
      <str>LEI occurred primarily in pial venules, whereas little or no LEI occurred in arterioles or deep cortical vessels. Inhibiting LEI did not affect secondary lesion expansion. Importantly, the majority of migrating leukocytes entered the injured brain parenchyma only after the tissue became necrotic. Our results therefore suggest that neither intravascular leukocyte adhesion nor the migration of leukocytes into cerebral tissue play a significant role in the development of secondary lesion expansion following TBI.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">In vivo temporal and spatial profile of leukocyte adhesion and migration after experimental traumatic brain injury in mice.</str>
    <str name="id">23448240</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Ghrelin is an orexigenic stomach hormone that acts centrally to increase mid-brain dopamine neurone activity, amplify dopamine signaling and protect against neurotoxin-induced dopamine cell death in the mouse substantia nigra pars compacta (SNpc). In addition, ghrelin inhibits the lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced release of pro-inflammatory cytokines from peripheral macrophages, T-cells and from LPS stimulated microglia. Here we sought to determine whether ghrelin attenuates pro-inflammatory cytokine release from dopaminergic neurones.</str>
      <str>The dopaminergic SN4741 cell-line, which derives from the mouse substantia nigra (SN) and expresses the ghrelin-receptor (growth hormone secretagogue receptor (GHS-R)) and the ghrelin-O-acyl transferase (GOAT) enzyme, was used to determine the neuro-immunomodulatory action of ghrelin. We induced innate immune activation via LPS challenge (1 μg/ml) of SN4741 neurones that had been pre-cultured in the presence or absence of ghrelin (1, 10, 100 nM) for 4 h. After 24 h supernatants were collected for detection of IL-1 beta (IL-1β ), TNF alpha (TNF-α) and IL-6 cytokines via enzyme linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) analysis. Nuclear translocation of the transcription factor nuclear factor kappa B (NF-κB) was analyzed by Western blotting, and to determine viability of treatments a cell viability assay and caspase-3 immunohistochemistry were performed.We provide evidence that while IL-1β and TNF-α were not detectable under any conditions, SN4741 neurones constitutively released IL-6 under basal conditions and treatment with LPS significantly increased IL-6 secretion. Pre-treatment of neurones with ghrelin attenuated LPS-mediated IL-6 release at 24 h, an affect that was inhibited by the GHS-R antagonist [D-Lys3]-GHRP-6. However, while ghrelin pre-treatment attenuated the LPS-mediated increase in NF-κB, there was no alteration in its nuclear translocation. Cell viability assay and caspase-3 immunocytochemistry demonstrated that the results were independent from activation of cytotoxic and/or apoptotic mechanisms in the neuronal population, respectively.</str>
      <str>Our results provide evidence that the gut-hormone, ghrelin, attenuates IL-6 secretion to LPS challenge in mid-brain dopaminergic neurones. These data suggest that ghrelin may protect against dopaminergic SN nerve cell damage or death via modulation of the innate immune response.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Ghrelin inhibits LPS-induced release of IL-6 from mouse dopaminergic neurones.</str>
    <str name="id">23509933</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Universal precautions mandate that health care workers wear gloves to prevent the unintended spread of bloodborne pathogens. Gloves may affect manual dexterity, generally delaying task completion. Our previous study showed that wearing the wrong size latex surgical glove degraded manual dexterity. The use of non-sterile and non-latex gloves may limit certain risks and be more cost-effective. However, such gloves may produce different results. We hypothesized that ambidextrous vinyl examination gloves would degrade manual dexterity compared with bare hands. We studied 20 random subjects from a medical environment. Subjects performed a standard battery of Grooved Pegboard tasks while bare-handed, wearing ambidextrous non-sterile vinyl gloves that were their preferred size, a size too small, and a size too large. The order was randomized with a Latin Square design to minimize the effects of time, boredom, and fatigue on the subjects. Subjects were also invited to comment on the fit of different size gloves. Wearing vinyl gloves of both the preferred size and a size up or down failed to affect manual dexterity vs. bare hands on time to insert pegs, and pegs dropped during insertion or removal. In contrast, the time to remove pegs was reduced by wearing preferred size vinyl gloves compared with performing the task with bare hands (P&lt;0.05). Subjects reported a generally poor fit in all sizes. Vinyl gloves that were too small caused significant hand discomfort. Vinyl gloves surprisingly do not degrade manual dexterity even when worn in ill-fitting sizes. Wearing a preferred size vinyl glove vs. bare hands may improve dexterity in selected tasks. Choosing a comfortable, large size seems the best strategy when the preferred size is unavailable. Thinner vinyl gloves may improve grip and may not degrade touch as much as latex surgical gloves and may thus represent a reasonable choice for selected tasks.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Wearing ambidextrous vinyl gloves does not impair manual dexterity.</str>
    <str name="id">23548060</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Airborne particles that are collected using closed-face filter cassettes (CFCs), which are used widely in the sampling of workplace aerosols, can deposit in places other than on the filter and thereby may not be included in the ensuing analysis. A technique for ensuring that internal non-filter deposits are included in the analysis is to collect airborne particles within an acid-soluble internal capsule that, following sampling, can be dissolved along with the filter for subsequent elemental analysis. An interlaboratory study (ILS) was carried out to evaluate the use of cellulosic CFC capsule inserts for their suitability in the determination of trace elements in airborne samples. The ILS was performed in accordance with an applicable ASTM International standard practice, ASTM E691, which describes statistical procedures for investigating interlaboratory precision. Performance evaluation materials consisted of prototype cellulose acetate capsules attached to mixed-cellulose ester filters. Batches of capsules were dosed with Pb-containing materials (standard aqueous solutions, and certified reference material soil and paint). Also, aerosol samples containing nine target analyte elements (As, Cd, Co, Cr, Cu, Fe, Pb, Mn, and Ni) were generated using a multiport sampler; various concentrations and sampling times were employed to yield samples fortified at desired loading levels. Triplicates of spiked capsules at three different loadings were conveyed to each volunteer laboratory; loading levels were unknown to the participants. The laboratories were asked to prepare the samples by acid dissolution and to analyze aliquots of extracted samples by atomic spectrometry in accordance with applicable ASTM International Standards. Participants were asked to report their results in units of μg of each target element per sample. For the elements investigated, inter-laboratory precision and recovery estimates from the participating laboratories demonstrated the utility of the cellulosic capsule inserts for the measurement of sampled trace elements.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Acid-soluble internal capsules for closed-face cassette elemental sampling and analysis of workplace air.</str>
    <str name="id">23548078</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>An estimated 200,000 to 500,000 U.S. workers in concentrated animal feeding operations (CAFOs) are at risk of adverse respiratory outcomes from exposures to indoor contaminants. In the wintertime, general ventilation is minimized in the Midwest due to high heating costs required to maintain indoor temperatures optimal for animal production. Pit fans typically operate to exhaust under-floor manure pits, but little other fresh air intake exists. Many operators believe that these systems are sufficient to reduce contaminant concentrations within the building during winter. Investigating whether these pit fans provide sufficient protection against classic CAFO contaminants during minimal wintertime ventilation was warranted. Direct-reading instruments were used to measure and record concentrations of multiple contaminants using both fixed-area and mobile contaminant mapping in a farrowing room during a Midwest winter. With the exception of CO, concentrations were significantly (p&lt;0.001) higher with the pit fan off compared with those with the pit fan on. Additional analyses identified that significant changes (p&lt;0.001) in mean room concentrations of respirable dust (decreased, 77% with pit fan off and 87% with pit fan on) and CO2 (increased, 24%) over the 5-hr study periods and that multiple fixed-area monitors rather than the much-used, single center-of-room monitor provided a more conservative (e.g., protective) assessment of room concentrations. While concentrations did not exceed occupational exposure limits from OSHA or ACGIH for individual contaminants, recommended agricultural health limits from exposure-response studies suggested in the literature were exceeded for respirable dust, CO2, and NH3, indicating a need to consider personal exposures and control options to reduce contaminant concentrations in farrowing rooms. Pit fans reduced NH3 and H2S concentrations, but these fans may not be sufficient to control dust and eliminate the need for secondary exposure prevention methods.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Wintertime factors affecting contaminant distribution in a swine farrowing room.</str>
    <str name="id">23548103</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Oxycodone hydrochloride controlled-release, also known as extended-release oxycodone (ER oxycodone), was reformulated with physicochemical barriers to crushing and dissolving intended to reduce abuse through nonoral routes of administration (ROAs) that require tampering (eg, injecting and snorting). Manufacturer shipments of original ER oxycodone (OC) stopped on August 5, 2010, and reformulated ER oxycodone (ORF) shipments started August 9, 2010. A sentinel surveillance sample of 140,496 individuals assessed for substance abuse treatment at 357 U.S. centers between June 1, 2009, and March 31, 2012, was examined for prevalence and prescription-adjusted prevalence rates of past-30-day abuse via any route, as well as abuse through oral, nonoral, and specific ROAs for ER oxycodone and comparators (ER morphine and ER oxymorphone) before and after ORF introduction. Significant reductions occurred for 8 outcome measures of ORF versus OC historically. Abuse of ORF was 41% lower (95% CI: -44 to -37) than historical abuse for OC, with oral abuse 17% lower (95% CI: -23 to -10) and nonoral abuse 66% lower (95% CI: -69 to -63). Significant reductions were not observed for comparators. Observations were consistent with the goals of a tamper resistant formulation for an opioid. Further research is needed to determine the persistence and generalizability of these findings.</str>
      <str>This article presents preliminary findings indicating that 8 outcome measures of abuse of a reformulated ER oxycodone were lower than that for original ER oxycodone historically, particularly through nonoral ROAs that require tampering (ie, injection, snorting, smoking), in a sentinel sample of individuals assessed for substance use problems for treatment planning.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Abuse rates and routes of administration of reformulated extended-release oxycodone: initial findings from a sentinel surveillance sample of individuals assessed for substance abuse treatment.</str>
    <str name="id">23127293</str></doc>
</result>
</response>
