<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<response>

<lst name="responseHeader">
  <int name="status">0</int>
  <int name="QTime">106</int>
  <lst name="params">
    <str name="q">PSMB7</str>
    <str name="indent">true</str>
    <str name="fl">id, medline_abstract_text, medline_journal_title, medline_article_title</str>
    <str name="rows">5000</str>
    <str name="wt">xml</str>
  </lst>
</lst>
<result name="response" numFound="18" start="0">
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To date individual markers have failed to correctly predict resistance against anticancer agents in breast cancer. We used gene expression patterns attributable to chemotherapy-resistant cells to detect potential new biomarkers related to anthracycline resistance. One of the genes, PSMB7, was selected for further functional studies and clinical validation.</str>
      <str>We contrasted the expression profiles of four pairs of different human tumour cell lines and of their counterparts resistant to doxorubicin. Observed overexpression of PSMB7 in resistant cell lines was validated by immunohistochemistry. To examine its function in chemoresistance, we silenced the gene by RNA interference (RNAi) in doxorubicin-resistant MCF-7 breast cancer cells, then cell vitality was measured after doxorubicin treatment. Microarray gene expression from GEO raw microarray samples with available progression-free survival data was downloaded, and expression of PSMB7 was used for grouping samples.</str>
      <str>After doxorubicin treatment, 79.8+/-13.3% of resistant cells survived. Silencing of PSMB7 in resistant cells decreased survival to 31.8+/-6.4% (P&gt;0.001). A similar effect was observed after paclitaxel treatment. In 1592 microarray samples, the patients with high PSMB7 expression had a significantly shorter survival than the patients with low expression (P&lt;0.001).</str>
      <str>Our findings suggest that high PSMB7 expression is an unfavourable prognostic marker in breast cancer.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">British journal of cancer</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">PSMB7 is associated with anthracycline resistance and is a prognostic biomarker in breast cancer.</str>
    <str name="id">20010949</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Proteasomal and autophagic pathways of protein degradation are two essential, endoplasmic reticulum (ER)-associated proteolytic systems involved in the ER stress response. The functional interaction between them has been shown by proteasome pharmacological inhibition. However, little data have been found concerning autophagy induction using an RNA interference approach due to the multisubunit composition of proteolytic systems. We suggested that silencing of single proteasome subunits can induce massive autophagy. Psmb7-specific small interference RNA added to isolated cardiomyocytes significantly affected mRNA expression of essential ER stress marker proteins, including DDIT3/CHOP and HSPA5/GRP78. mRNA expression of the key autophagy regulator MTOR was also increased. These findings were confirmed by single-cell reverse transcription real-time PCR on individual monodansylcadaverine (MDC)-labeled cardiomyocytes. RNA interference that decreased the levels of non-catalytic PSMB7 subunits of the proteasome had no influence on chymotrypsin- and trypsin-like activities, but significantly decreased peptidyl-glutamyl peptide-hydrolyzing activity. Immunohistochemical analysis showed increased levels of LC3-marked vacuoles in the cytoplasm of Psmb7-knockdown cells, and MDC staining showed significantly increased numbers of neonatal cardiomyocytes with autophagic vacuoles. After anoxia-reoxygenation, the number of cells with signs of autophagy after Psmb7 gene silencing was higher. Our results indicate that Psmb7 knockdown induces ER stress and autophagy in cardiomyocytes, which may be a useful approach to activate specific autophagy. </str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Pathobiology : journal of immunopathology, molecular and cellular biology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Knockdown of PSMB7 induces autophagy in cardiomyocyte cultures: possible role in endoplasmic reticulum stress.</str>
    <str name="id">23969338</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Proteasomes are the multisubunit protease involved in the generation of peptides presented by MHC class I molecules. When cells are stimulated with IFN-gamma, two MHC-encoded subunits, low Mr polypeptide 2 (LMP2) and LMP7, are incorporated into the proteasomal complex by displacing the housekeeping subunits, designated Y and X, respectively. Recent evidence indicates that besides the LMP2/Y and LMP7/X subunits, there is another pair of structurally similar beta-type subunits, designated MECL1 and Z, whose expression is regulated reciprocally by IFN-y. In the present study we determined the genomic organizations of the mouse genes, Psmb10 and Psmb7, that encode the MECL1 and Z subunits, respectively. Although the two genes differ &gt; 10-fold in size, they both have eight exons, with the exon-intron boundaries located precisely at the equivalent positions. The organization of the Psmb10 and Psmb7 genes differs from those of the genes encoding the other two pairs of IFN-gamma-regulated subunits. Thus, comparison of the gene structures supports the idea that Psmb10 and Psmb7 arose by duplication from an immediate common ancestor. The promoter region of the Psmb10 gene contains two IFN-stimulated response elements, the functionality of which was confirmed by in vitro mutagenesis. The mouse Psmb10 gene maps to chromosome 8, thus outside the MHC like its human counterpart. Besides the Psmb7 gene previously mapped to chromosome 2, a truncated processed pseudogene, designated Psmb7-ps, was identified and mapped to chromosome X.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Journal of immunology (Baltimore, Md. : 1950)</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The mouse genes encoding the third pair of beta-type proteasome subunits regulated reciprocally by IFN-gamma: structural comparison, chromosomal localization, and analysis of the promoter.</str>
    <str name="id">9300697</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) has high mortality partly due to acquiring drug resistance during chemotherapy treatment. Therefore, it is necessary to explore the underlying mechanism of drug resistance.</str>
      <str>We used 2-DE and MALDI-TOF-MS analysis to explore the possible molecular insight into 5-FU resistance in HCC. The differentially expressed proteins were validated by Western blot analysis.</str>
      <str>We identified 102 unique proteins including p16, maspin, PRDX6, PSMB7, MYL6, PHB, and HSP27 with alteration in SMMC- 7721/5-FU. Furthermore, down-regulation of PRDX6 and PSMB7 enhanced SMMC-7721/5-FU cells to 5-FU sensitivity.</str>
      <str>Our study suggests that targeting drug resistant genes such as PRDX6 and PSMB7 could be a novel approach to overcome 5-FU resistance in HCC cells.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Current pharmaceutical design</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Proteomic-based analysis for identification of proteins involved in 5-fluorouracil resistance in hepatocellular carcinoma.</str>
    <str name="id">23530500</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Proteasomes are the multi-subunit protease thought to play a key role in the generation of peptides presented by major histocompatibility complex (MHC) class I molecules. When cells are stimulated with interferon gamma, two MHC-encoded subunits, low molecular mass polypeptide (LMP) 2 and LMP7, and the MECL1 subunit encoded outside the MHC are incorporated into the proteasomal complex, presumably by displacing the housekeeping subunits designated Y, X, and Z, respectively. These changes in the subunit composition appear to facilitate class I-mediated antigen presentation, presumably by altering the cleavage specificities of the proteasome. Here we show that the mouse gene encoding the Z subunit (Psmb7) maps to the paracentromeric region of chromosome 2. Inspection of the mouse loci adjacent to the Psmb7 locus provides evidence that the paracentromeric region of chromosome 2 and the MHC region on chromosome 17 most likely arose as a result of a duplication that took place at an early stage of vertebrate evolution. The traces of this duplication are also evident in the homologous human chromosome regions (6p21.3 and 9q33-q34). These observations have implications in understanding the genomic organization of the present-day MHC and offer insights into the origin of the MHC.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Chromosomal localization of the proteasome Z subunit gene reveals an ancient chromosomal duplication involving the major histocompatibility complex.</str>
    <str name="id">8799160</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Reanalyses of vertebrate PSMB5 and PSMB8 genes were conducted with a newly obtained amphioxus sequence. The phylogenetic analysis indicated that the amphioxus sequence is an outgroup of both vertebrate PSMB5 and PSMB8 genes. The agnathan sequences were previously thought to be closer to PSMB5 than PSMB8 sequences. However, in this study the phylogenetic trees supported the clustering of agnathan sequences with PSMB8 rather than with PSMB5 sequences. In the alignment there are many sites in which the agnathan sequences are more similar to PSMB5 than PSMB8 sequences. Parsimony analysis showed that the amino acid pattern at these sites could be explained by one substitution on the ancestral branch leading to the jawed vertebrate PSMB8 cluster. The number of substitutions required at these sites was the same for different tree topologies with respect to the position of agnathans. The phylogenetic analyses of PSMB6/PSMB9 and PSMB7/PSMB10 genes indicated that all the interferon-gamma-inducible forms have evolved two to three times faster than the housekeeping forms in the jawed vertebrate lineage. Hence although the agnathan sequences cluster with the PSMB8 sequences, they have a slower rate of evolution similar to that of the housekeeping forms, and may be functioning as housekeeping forms.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Gene</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Sequencing of amphioxus PSMB5/8 gene and phylogenetic position of agnathan sequences.</str>
    <str name="id">11814690</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The proteasome inhibitor bortezomib is a novel anticancer drug that has shown promise in the treatment of refractory multiple myeloma. However, its clinical efficacy has been hampered by the emergence of drug-resistance phenomena, the molecular basis of which remains elusive. Toward this end, we here developed high levels (45- to 129-fold) of acquired resistance to bortezomib in human myelomonocytic THP1 cells by exposure to stepwise increasing (2.5-200 nM) concentrations of bortezomib. Study of the molecular mechanism of bortezomib resistance in these cells revealed (1) an Ala49Thr mutation residing in a highly conserved bortezomib-binding pocket in the proteasome beta5-subunit (PSMB5) protein, (2) a dramatic overexpression (up to 60-fold) of PSMB5 protein but not of other proteasome subunits including PSMB6, PSMB7, and PSMA7, (3) high levels of cross-resistance to beta5 subunit-targeted cytotoxic peptides 4A6, MG132, MG262, and ALLN, but not to a broad spectrum of chemotherapeutic drugs, (4) no marked changes in chymotrypsin-like proteasome activity, and (5) restoration of bortezomib sensitivity in bortezomib-resistant cells by siRNA-mediated silencing of PSMB5 gene expression. Collectively, these findings establish a novel mechanism of bortezomib resistance associated with the selective overexpression of a mutant PSMB5 protein.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Blood</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Molecular basis of bortezomib resistance: proteasome subunit beta5 (PSMB5) gene mutation and overexpression of PSMB5 protein.</str>
    <str name="id">18565852</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>A big bang expansion of the Vertebrate-type (V-type) TLRs was reported in amphioxus. To shed lights on its implications, a unique TLR which is reversely inserted into an intron of amphioxus PSMB7-10 by retrotransposition in the highly polymorphic proto-MHC region was cloned from Chinese amphioxus (Branchiostoma belcheri tsingtauense) and named as bbtTLR1. In situ assays showed that bbtTLR1 was predominantly expressed in pharynx and gut from larva to adult stages, which are considered as the first frontlines of amphioxus defense system. Acute immune challenges revealed that the expression of bbtTLR1 was stimulated by bacteria and their cell wall components, while suppressed by Glucan and Poly I:C in the digestive system. Amphioxus also had dozens of TIR adaptors from which we cloned bbtMyD88. BbtMyD88 expressed in 293T cells led to the activation of NF-kappaB pathway through its DEATH and middle domains. Moreover, this activation could be enhanced by bbtTLR1 through the direct association with bbtMyD88. In summary, this study provides evidence for the immune-relation of amphioxus V-type TLRs, and suggests that amphioxus TLR1 and MyD88 represent a basic evolutionary pathway.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Molecular immunology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">An amphioxus TLR with dynamic embryonic expression pattern responses to pathogens and activates NF-kappaB pathway via MyD88.</str>
    <str name="id">19394698</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Harlequin is a pigmentary trait of the domestic dog that is controlled by two autosomal loci: the melanosomal gene, SILV, and a modifier gene, harlequin (H), previously localized to chromosome 9. Heterozygosity for a retrotransposon insertion in SILV and a mutation in H causes a pattern of black patches on a white background. Homozygosity for H is embryonic lethal. Fine mapping of the harlequin locus revealed a 25 kb interval wherein all harlequin Great Danes are heterozygous for a common haplotype. This region contains one gene, PSMB7, which encodes the β2 catalytic subunit of the proteasome. Sequence analysis identified a coding variant in exon 2 that segregates with harlequin patterning. The substitution predicts the replacement of a highly conserved valine with a glycine. Described herein is the identification of a naturally-occurring mutation of the ubiquitin proteasome system that is associated with a discernable phenotype of dogs.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Genomics</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">A missense mutation in the 20S proteasome β2 subunit of Great Danes having harlequin coat patterning.</str>
    <str name="id">21256207</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Anti-Thy1 nephritis is a well-established experimental mesangial proliferative nephritis model. Exploring the molecular mechanisms of pathophysiology in anti-Thy1 nephritis may elucidate the pathogeneses of mesangial proliferation. We examined the roles and acting mechanisms of differentially expressed proteins (DEPs) by bioinformatics analysis of glomeruli proteomic profiles during the course of anti-Thy1 nephritis. In total, 108 DEPs were found by two-dimensional fluorescence difference gel electrophoresis (2D-DIGE), and 40 DEPs were identified by matrix-assisted laser desorption ionization/time of flight and liquid chromatography-MS. DEPs were classified into five clusters (Clusters 1-5), according to their expression trends using Cluster 3.0 software, involved in regulating biological processes such as the stress response, cell proliferation, apoptosis, energy metabolism, transport, and the actin cytoskeleton. The expression patterns of ten DEPs, distributed across five clusters, including AKR1A1, AGAT, ATP6V1B2, HIBADH, MDH1, MPST, NIT2, PRDX6, PSMB7, and TPI1, were validated by Western blotting. Based on Western blotting and immunohistochemistry, we also found that the DEP FHL2, which was primarily expressed in the mesangial region, was down-regulated on days 3 and 5, and up-regulated on day 10. In vitro, we found that FHL2 overexpression induced mesangial cell proliferation by increasing the number of S-phase cells and decreasing G2/M-phase cells, whereas inhibiting FHL2 had the opposite effect. This study explored novel DEPs and their expression patterns during anti-Thy1 nephritis, and elucidated FHL2's effect on mesangial cell proliferation. These results will contribute to our understanding of the pathogenesis of mesangial proliferation.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Molecular &amp; cellular proteomics : MCP</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Bioinformatics analysis of proteomic profiles during the process of anti-Thy1 nephritis.</str>
    <str name="id">22159597</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Decreases in the 26S proteasome are related to the toxicities of abnormal protein aggregates and may contribute to pathogenesis of degenerative diseases. Therefore, maintenance of proteasome function can be a novel strategy to protect cells against abnormal protein-mediated toxicity. In the present study, we have demonstrated the tissue specific increase of the catalytic subunits of the proteasome in mice following oral administration of 3H-1,2-dithiole-3-thione (D3T, 0.5 mmol/kg), which functions as a cancer preventive agent in animal and human studies. Expression of the 20S catalytic core subunits PSMB5, PSMB6, and PSMB7 were increased in liver, lung, small intestine, and colon of mice at 24 h after D3T treatment. Elevated expression of proteasome catalytic subunits led to increases in proteasomal peptidase activities in these tissues. Oral administration of D3T also exerted a pharmacodynamic action in some brain regions of these mice and proteasomal peptidase activities were significantly elevated in the cerebral cortex-hippocampus. Moreover, tissue extracts from D3T-treated mice and cell lysates obtained from D3T-incubated murine neuroblastoma cells exhibited the enhanced capacity to degrade mutant human SOD1G93A protein. These results indicate that the catalytic subunits of the 26S proteasome are inducible in multiple tissues of mouse including brain by exogenous chemical treatment. Increased proteasome expression by inducers may have a role in protection/attenuation of protein aggregate-mediated disorders.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Life sciences</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Tissue specific increase of the catalytic subunits of the 26S proteasome by indirect antioxidant dithiolethione in mice: enhanced activity for degradation of abnormal protein.</str>
    <str name="id">17521679</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The assembly of individual proteasome subunits into catalytically active mammalian 20S proteasomes is not well understood. Using subunit-specific antibodies, we characterized both precursor and mature proteasome complexes. Antibodies to PSMA4 (C9) immunoprecipitated complexes composed of alpha, precursor beta and processed beta subunits. However, antibodies to PSMA3 (C8) and PSMB9 (LMP2) immunoprecipitated complexes made up of alpha and precursor beta but no processed beta subunits. These complexes possess short half-lives, are enzymatically inactive and their molecular weight is approximately 300 kDa. Radioactivity chases from these complexes into mature, long-lived approximately 700 kDa proteasomes. Therefore, these structures represent precursor proteasomes and are probably made up of two rings: one containing alpha subunits and the other, precursor beta subunits. The assembly of precursor proteasomes occurs in at least two stages, with precursor beta subunits PSMB2 (C7-I), PSMB3 (C10-II), PSMB7 (Z), PSMB9 (LMP2) and PSMB10 (LMP10) being incorporated before others [PSMB1 (C5), PSMB6 (delta), and PSMB8 (LMP7)]. Proteasome maturation (processing of the beta subunits and juxtaposition of the two beta rings) is accompanied by conformational changes in the (outer) alpha rings, and may be inefficient. Finally, interferon-gamma had no significant effect on the half-lives or total amounts of precursor or mature proteasomes.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">The EMBO journal</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Intermediates in the formation of mouse 20S proteasomes: implications for the assembly of precursor beta subunits.</str>
    <str name="id">9311996</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Sequencing of zebrafish (Danio rerio) bacterial artificial chromosome and P1 artificial chromosome genomic clone fragments and of cDNA clones has led to the identification of five new loci coding for beta subunits of proteasomes (PSMB). Together with the four genes identified previously, nine PSMB genes have now been defined in the zebrafish. Six of the nine genes reside in the zebrafish MHC (Mhc) class I region, four of them reside in a single cluster closely associated with TAP2 on a 26-kb long genomic fragment, and two reside at some distance from the fragment. In addition to homologues of the human genes PSMB5 through PSMB9, two new genes, PSMB11 and PSMB12, have been found for which there are no known corresponding genes in humans. The new genes reside in the PSMB cluster in the Mhc. Homology and promoter region analysis suggest that the Mhc-associated genes might be inducible by IFN-gamma. The zebrafish class I region contains representatives of three phylogenetically distinguishable groups of PSMB genes, X, Y, and Z. It is proposed that these genes were present in the ancestral PSMB region before Mhc class I genes became associated with it.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Journal of immunology (Baltimore, Md. : 1950)</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Analysis of a 26-kb region linked to the Mhc in zebrafish: genomic organization of the proteasome component beta/transporter associated with antigen processing-2 gene cluster and identification of five new proteasome beta subunit genes.</str>
    <str name="id">10453006</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>We have described a family of adrenocortical tumor cell mutants (including clones OS3, Y6, and 10r9) that are resistant to ACTH because they fail to express the gene encoding the ACTH receptor (MC2R). The MC2R deficiency results from a mutation that impairs the activity of the nuclear receptor steroidogenic factor 1 (SF1) at the MC2R promoter. In this report, we show that ACTH resistance in the mutant clones is associated with a Sf1 gene that has Ser at codon 172 instead of Ala. In two of the three mutant clones, this Sf1 allele is amplified together with flanking DNA from chromosome 2 that includes the genes encoding germ cell nuclear factor and the beta-type proteosome subunit Psmb7. SF1(A172) and SF1(S172) exhibit little or no difference in transcriptional activity in SF1-dependent reporter gene assays, suggesting that SF1(S172) per se is not directly responsible for the loss of MC2R expression. Instead, the Sf1(S172) allele appears to be a marker of ACTH resistance in this family of adrenocortical tumor cell mutants, possibly reflecting the activity of a neighboring gene.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">A polymorphic form of steroidogenic factor 1 associated with ACTH receptor deficiency in mouse adrenal cell mutants.</str>
    <str name="id">12851310</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The molecular target(s) cooperating with proteasome inhibition in multiple myeloma (MM) remain unknown. We therefore measured proliferation in MM cells transfected with 13 984 small interfering RNAs in the absence or presence of increasing concentrations of bortezomib. We identified 37 genes, which when silenced, are not directly cytotoxic but do synergistically potentiate the growth inhibitory effects of bortezomib. To focus on bortezomib sensitizers, genes that also sensitized MM to melphalan were excluded. When suppressed, the strongest bortezomib sensitizers were the proteasome subunits PSMA5, PSMB2, PSMB3, and PSMB7 providing internal validation, but others included BAZ1B, CDK5, CDC42SE2, MDM4, NME7, RAB8B, TFE3, TNFAIP3, TNK1, TOP1, VAMP2, and YY1. The strongest hit CDK5 also featured prominently in pathway analysis of primary screen data. Cyclin-dependent kinase 5 (CDK5) is expressed at high levels in MM and neural tissues with relatively low expression in other organs. Viral shRNA knockdown of CDK5 consistently sensitized 5 genetically variable MM cell lines to proteasome inhibitors (bortezomib and carfilzomib). Small-molecule CDK5 inhibitors were demonstrated to synergize with bortezomib to induce cytotoxicity of primary myeloma cells and myeloma cell lines. CDK5 regulation of proteasome subunit PSMB5 was identified as a probable route to sensitization.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Blood</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">RNAi screen of the druggable genome identifies modulators of proteasome inhibitor sensitivity in myeloma including CDK5.</str>
    <str name="id">21289309</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The proteasome is a multi-subunit protease responsible for the production of peptides presented by major histocompatibility complex class I molecules. Accumulated evidence indicates that, upon stimulation with interferon-gamma (IFN-gamma), three beta-type subunits, designated LMP2, LMP7, and PSMB10, are incorporated into the 20S proteasome by displacing the housekeeping beta-type subunits designated PSMB6, PSMB5, and PSMB7, respectively. These changes in the subunit composition appear to facilitate class I-mediated antigen presentation, presumably by altering the cleavage specificities of the proteasome. In the present study, we determined the organization of the mouse gene Psmb5, coding for the PSMB5 subunit. Psmb5 is made up of three exons, spanning approximately 5 kilobases. Its exon-intron organization differs radically from those of the other IFN-gamma-regulated, beta-type subunit genes including Lmp7 with which Psmb5 is believed to share an immediate common ancestor. The structure of the mouse Psmb5 gene is identical to that of its recently characterized human counterpart. Thus, the unique organization of the gene coding for the PSMB5 subunit appears to have been established before mammalian radiation. As well as the Psmb5 gene, the mouse genome contains a processed pseudogene designated Psmb5-ps. Interspecific backcross mapping showed that Psmb5 maps close to the Gtrgal2 locus on chromosome 14 and that Psmb5-ps is located in the vicinity of the Psme3 locus on chromosome 11. These results were confirmed by fluorescent in situ hybridization analysis that localized Psmb5 to band C2 to proximal D1 of chromosome 14 and Psmb5-ps to band D of chromosome 11.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Immunogenetics</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Structural analysis and chromosomal localization of the mouse Psmb5 gene coding for the constitutively expressed beta-type proteasome subunit.</str>
    <str name="id">9382924</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Bipolar disorder (BD) is a psychiatric disease considered to polygenic with multiple factors in genetics, each of which is not dominant but collaborative during pathogenic progression. We describe a method that estimates the collaborative contribution to the disease between a certain well-studied pathway and the other candidate pathway using Gene Set Enrichment Analysis (GSEA). We describe a modified GSEA (improved derivation) to identify genes that are significantly and differentially expressed between disease and non-disease states and that are consistently co-expressed with a target pathway which is deeply related to disease etiology. The modified GSEA uses available gene expression data to identify molecular mechanism (ubiquitin-proteasome and inflammatory response) associated with the disease. We believe that this approach could reveal hidden relations between a certain well-studied pathway and the other candidate pathway known in literature.</str>
      <str>ATP5I - ATP synthase H+ transporting mitochondrial F0 complex subunit E, ATP5J - ATP synthase H+ transporting mitochondrial F0 complex subunit F6, BAD - Bcl-2-associated death promoter, BAX - Bcl-2-associated x protein, Bcl-2 - B-cell lymphoma 2, BDNF - brain derived neurotrophic factor, COX5B - Cytochrome c oxidase subunit Vb, COX7A2 - cytochrome c oxidase subunit VIIa polypeptide 2, DLK - dual leucine zipper-bearing kinase, GABA - Gamma aminobutyric acid, IL-8 - Interleukin 8, NDUFA1 - NADH dehydrogenase 1 alpha subcomplex 1, NDUFB2 - NADH dehydrogenase1 beta subcomplex 2, NDUFS4 - NADH dehydrogenase Fe-S protein 4, NGF - nerve growth factor, PPP2R5C - protein phosphatase 2 regulatory subunit B gamma, PSMA3 - proteasome subunit alpha type 3, PSMA7 - proteasome subunit alpha type 7, PSMB1 - proteasome subunit beta type 1, PSMB6 - proteasome subunit beta type 6, PSMB7 - proteasome subunit beta type 7, PSMC2 - proteasome 26S subunit ATPase 2, PSMC5 - proteasome 26S subunit ATPase 5, SLC6A4 - solute carrier family 6 member 4, TNFa - tumor necrosis factor a, UBE2A - ubiquitinconjugating enzyme E2A, UCRC - ubiquinol-cytochrome c reductase complex, UFC1 - ubiquitin-fold modifier conjugating enzyme 1, UQCRQ - ubiquinol-cytochrome c reductase complex III subunit VII, USP14 - ubiquitin specific protease 14.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Bioinformation</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Identification of collaborative activities with oxidative phosphorylation in bipolar disorder.</str>
    <str name="id">26124562</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Myostatin (GDF-8) is a key protein responsible for skeletal muscle growth and development, thus mutations in the mstn gene can have major economic and breeding consequences. The aim of the present study was to investigate myostatin gene expression and transcriptional profile in skeletal muscle of Holstein-Friesian (Black-and-White) bulls carrying a polymorphism in the 5'-flanking region of the mstn gene (G/C transversion at position -7828). Real-time qRT-PCR and cDNA microarray revealed significantly lower mstn expression in muscle of bulls with the CC genotype, as compared to GG and GC genotypes. The direct comparison of skeletal muscle transcriptional profiles between the CC genotype and GG and GC genotypes resulted in identification of genes, of which at least some can be putative targets for myostatin. Using cDNA microarray, we identified 43 common genes (including mstn) with significantly different expression in skeletal muscle of bulls with the CC genotype, as compared to GG and GC genotypes, 15 of which were upregulated and 28 were downregulated in the CC genotype. Classification of molecular function of differentially expressed genes revealed the highest number of genes involved in the expression of cytoskeleton proteins (9), extracellular matrix proteins (4), nucleic acid-binding proteins (4), calcium-binding proteins (4), and transcription factors (4). The biological functions of the largest number of genes involved: protein metabolism and modification (10), signal transduction (10), cell structure (8), and developmental processes (8). The main identified signaling pathways were: Wnt (4), chemokines and cytokines (4), integrin (4), nicotine receptor for acetylocholine (3), TGF-beta (2), and cytoskeleton regulation by Rho GTPase (2). We identified previously unrecognized putatively myostatin-dependent genes, encoding transcription factors (EGR1, Nf1b, ILF1), components of the proteasomal complex (PSMB7, PSMD13) and proteins with some other molecular function in skeletal muscle (ITGB1BP3, Pla2g1b, ISYNA1, TNFAIP6, MST1, TNNT1, CALB3, CACYBP, and CTNNA1).</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Journal of applied genetics</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Gene expression profiling in skeletal muscle of Holstein-Friesian bulls with single-nucleotide polymorphism in the myostatin gene 5'-flanking region.</str>
    <str name="id">18670060</str></doc>
</result>
</response>
