<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<response>

<lst name="responseHeader">
  <int name="status">0</int>
  <int name="QTime">37</int>
  <lst name="params">
    <str name="q">T</str>
    <str name="indent">true</str>
    <str name="fl">id, medline_abstract_text, medline_journal_title, medline_article_title</str>
    <str name="rows">5000</str>
    <str name="wt">xml</str>
  </lst>
</lst>
<result name="response" numFound="869079" start="0">
  
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Skull size and shape were examined among 14 species of the tree shrews (Tupaia montana, T. picta, T. splendidula, T. mulleri, T. longipes, T. glis, T. javanica, T. minor, T. gracilis, T. dorsalis, T. tana, Dendrogale melanura, D. murina, and Ptilocercus lowii). The bones of face were rostro-caudally longer in T. tana and T. dorsalis, contrasting with T. minor and T. gracilis, D. melanura, D. murina and P. lowii which have smaller facial length ratios. The arbo-terrestrial species (T. longipes and T. glis) were similar to terrestrial species in length ratios of bones of face unlike the other arbo-terrestrial species (T. montana, T. picta, T. splendidula, and T. mulleri). We propose that T. longipes and T. glis have adapted to foraging for termites and ants as have T. tana and T. dorsalis. Additionally small body size in T. javanica may be the result of being isolated in Java. We separated the species into 5 groups from the measurment values of skulls: 1) Terrestrial species; T. tana and T. dorsalis, 2) Arboreal species; T. minor and T. gracilis, 3) Arbo-terrestrial species group 1: T. montana, T. splendidula, T. picta and T. mulleri, and T. javanica, 4) Arbo-terrestrial species group 2: T. glis and T. longipes, 5) Arboreal species of Dendrogale and Ptilocercus. Principal component analysis separated species into 8 clusters as follows: 1) T. tana, 2) T. dorsalis, 3) T. montana, T. splendidula, T. picta and T. mulleri, 4) T. glis and T. longipes, 5) T. javanica, 6) T. minor and T. gracilis, 7) D. melanura and D. murina, and 8) P. lowii. We suggest that these clusters correspond to behavioral strategies and peculiarities observed in foraging, feeding and locomotion in each species.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">The Journal of veterinary medical science / the Japanese Society of Veterinary Science</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Morphological adaptation of the skull for various behaviors in the tree shrews.</str>
    <str name="id">12951419</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Let T(k) (epsilon)(lambda; t(1),..., t(k)) = rho(X(t) (1))q(epsilon)(X(t) (2) - X(t) (1))... q(epsilon)(X(t(k) ) - X(t(k) )-1), where X(t) is a Brownian motion in R(2), lambda(dx) = rho(x)dx, and q(epsilon) converges to Dirac's delta function as epsilon downward arrow 0. The self-intersection local times of order k are described by a generalized random field T(k)(lambda; t(1),..., t(k)) = lim(epsilon downward arrow0)T(k) (epsilon)(lambda; t(1),..., t(k)) for 0 &lt; t(1) &lt;... &lt; t(k). The field "blows up" as t(i) - t(j) --&gt; 0 for some i not equal j. I show that with a proper choice of the coefficients B(k) (l)(epsilon), a generalized random field [unk] (k)(lambda; t(1),..., t(k)) = lim(epsilon downward arrow0) [T(k) (epsilon)(lambda; t(1),..., t(k)) + Sigma(l=1) (k-1) [B(k) (l)(epsilon)T(l) (epsilon)](lambda; t(1),..., t(k))] is well defined for all 0 &lt;/= t(1) &lt;/=... &lt;/= t(k) and it coincides with T(k)(lambda; t(1),..., t(k)) for t(1) &lt;... &lt; t(k).</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Generalized random fields related to self-intersections of the Brownian motion.</str>
    <str name="id">16593700</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The type material of the Oriental Carpelimus species from five museums have been investigated. Thirty four lectotypes are designated for the following species: Trogophloeus bengalensis Cameron, 1930; T. bicolor Cameron, 1940; T. calcuttanus Bemhauer, 1911; T. chatterjeei Cameron, 1930; T. congruus Cameron, 1930;T. coriaceus Cameron, 1930; T. flavipennis Cameron, 1930; T. formosae Cameron, 1940; T. formosanus Cameron, 1940; Tfoveicollis Kraatz, 1859; T. gratus Cameron, 1930; T. halophiloides Cameron, 1918; T. javanicus Cameron, 1936; T. laticeps Cameron, 1930; T. lepidicornis Fauvel, 1904; T. littoralis Cameron, 1918; T. louwerensi Cameron, 1938; T. lucens Cameron, 1918; T. nitidipennis Cameron, 1919; T. palitans Cameron, 1930; T. pallidicornis Cameron, 1945; T. papuensis Fauvel, 1879; T. piceicollis Cameron, 1930; T. planicollis Bernhauer, 1902; T. praelongus Bernhauer, 1938; T. pusae Cameron, 1930; T. ruficornis Cameron, 1930; T. rufoniger Cameron, 1945; T. sadiyanus Cameron, 1945; T. saigonensis Cameron, 1940; T. scabrosus Kraatz, 1859; T. simplex Motschulsky, 1857; T. taprobanae Walker, 1859; T. trivialis Cameron, 1930. The genital figures for all species (excepT. Tflavipennis) are presented.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Zootaxa</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Designations of the lectotypes for the oriental species of the genus Carpelimus Leach, 1819 (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae).</str>
    <str name="id">26176094</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Analysis of the T-cell receptor (TCR) repertoire of innate CD4(+) T cells selected by major histocompatibility complex (MHC) class II-dependent thymocyte-thymocyte (T-T) interaction (T-T CD4(+) T cells) is essential for predicting the characteristics of the antigens that bind to these T cells and for distinguishing T-T CD4(+) T cells from other types of innate T cells. Using the TCR(mini) Tg mouse model, we show that the repertoire of TCRα chains in T-T CD4(+) T cells was extremely diverse, in contrast to the repertoires previously described for other types of innate T cells. The TCRα chain sequences significantly overlapped between T-T CD4(+) T cells and conventional CD4(+) T cells in the thymus and spleen. However, the diversity of the TCRα repertoire of T-T CD4(+) T cells seemed to be restricted compared with that of conventional CD4(+) T cells. Interestingly, the frequency of the parental OT-II TCRα chains was significantly reduced in the process of T-T interaction. This diverse and shifted repertoire in T-T CD4(+) T cells has biological relevance in terms of defense against diverse pathogens and a possible regulatory role during peripheral T-T interaction. </str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Experimental &amp; molecular medicine</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Analyses of the TCR repertoire of MHC class II-restricted innate CD4⁺ T cells.</str>
    <str name="id">25813222</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Human peripheral blood T cells and T cell subsets were studied for the proliferative response in the autologous mixed lymphocyte reaction (AMLR) upon stimulation with mitogen- or AMLR-activated T cells and T cell subsets. T cells exhibited a vigorous proliferative response when stimulated with autologous activated T cells but not with unactivated T cells. The stimulatory capacity of activated T cells in the T-T AMLR was inhibited by prior treatment with 7.2 anti-DR monoclonal antibody in the absence of complement A BUdR and light experiment clearly demonstrated that T cells responding to activated T cells in the AMLR were distinct from those responding in allogeneic MLR. Further analysis with OKT4+ and OKT8+ T cell subsets demonstrated that OKT8+ T cells were the major responder upon stimulation with PHA-activated T cells. In contrast, OKT4+ T cells were the major responder in the T-T AMLR, when AMLR-activated T-cells were used as stimulators. T cells activated in T-T AMLR (PHA-activated T cells as stimulators) demonstrated suppressor activity against the proliferative response of autologous responder T cells. This study demonstrates that distinct subsets of T cells respond in the T-T AMLR and express suppressor activity.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Behring Institute Mitteilungen</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Cellular interactions in the human T-T autologous mixed lymphocyte reaction.</str>
    <str name="id">6242329</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The species of the Afrotropical genus Trichiscus are revised. Fourteen species are recognized, two previously described species, T. wittei Benoît and T. suzannae Benoît, and twelve new: T. noorti sp. nov., T. denisi sp. nov., T. briani sp. nov., T. copelandi sp. nov., T. mourei sp. nov., T. lynnae sp. nov., T. normani sp. nov., T. luboi sp. nov., T. zuparkoi sp. nov., T. ohli sp. nov., T. camargoi sp. nov. and T. jimi sp. nov.. A key to species is proposed. </str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Zootaxa</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Revision of Trichiscus benoît, 1956 (Hymenoptera, Bethylidae).</str>
    <str name="id">24871013</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>We analyzed the classical cytotaxonomy of the Brasiliensis subcomplex (Triatoma brasiliensis Neiva, T. juazeirensis Costa &amp; Felix, T. melanica Costa, Argolo &amp; Felix, T. melanocephala Neiva &amp; Pinto, T. petrochiae Pinto &amp; Barreto, T. lenti Sherlock &amp; Serafim, T. sherlocki Papa, Jurberg, Carcavallo, Cerqueira &amp; Barata, T. tibiamaculata Pinto and T. vitticeps Stal) and the T. brasiliensis complex (T. b. brasiliensis, T. b. macromelasoma Neiva &amp; Lent, T. juazeirensis, T. melanica and T. sherlocki). The five members of the T. brasiliensis complex share the same cytogenetic characteristics. Merely T. sherlocki show differences in spermatids, which confirms the status of more differentiated member of the complex. T. lenti also presented the same cytogenetic characteristics described for the species of the T. brasiliensis complex, which supports possible grouping of the species as sixth member of the complex, although further analysis as molecular and experimental crosses are needed to corroborate this hypothesis. T. petrochiae, T. vitticeps, T. tibiamaculata and T. melanocephala presented one or more characteristics that allow questioning grouping in the proposed Brasiliensis subcomplex. Thus, we suggested that Brasiliensis subcomplex and T. brasiliensis complex should be constituted by the same triatomines (T. b. brasiliensis, T. b. macromelasoma, T. juazeirensis, T. melanica and T. sherlocki). However, we draw attention to T. lenti and suggest that although new analyzes should be performed, possibly this species is the sixth member of the T. brasiliensis complex.  </str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Zootaxa</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Cytotaxonomy of the Brasiliensis subcomplex and the Triatoma brasiliensis complex (Hemiptera: Reduviidae: Triatominae).</str>
    <str name="id">25081800</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The paper describes the characteristics, receptor profile and functions of T lymphocyte subpopulations (helper, cytotoxic, regulatory, memory and others). Among T helper cells one can enumerate Th0, Th1, Th2, Th9, Th17, Th22, T(FH) and nTh2, while T cytotoxic cells include Tc, NKT, Tγδ, and T CD8αα (IEL). Among regulatory cells there are nTreg, iTreg, T(R)1, and iT(R)35, as well as T lymphocytes with CD8, such as CD8+CD122+, CD8+CD28-, and CD11c+CD8+. And among memory T cells there are Tcm and Tem. Moreover, there are some so-called other T cells, such as Tn (T αβ CD4+ and T αβ CD8+), T exhausted and T anergic.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Postȩpy higieny i medycyny doświadczalnej (Online)</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">[Characteristics of T lymphocyte subpopulations].</str>
    <str name="id">23667096</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The chemical synthesis of lactose operator DNA segments is described. The 31-base-paired duplex contains the DNA recognized by lac repressor protein and twofold rotationally symmetric base pairs on either side of the tight binding region. The synthesis includes the deoxyoligonucleotides d(T-G-T-G-G), d(A-A-T-T-G-T-G-A-G), d(C-G-G-A-T-A-A-C-A-A-T-T), d(T-C-A-C-A), d(T-G-T-G-A-A-A-T-T-G-T), d(T-A-T-C-C-G-C-T-C-A-C), and d(A-A-T-T-C-C-A-C-A). These deoxyoligonucleotides were characterized by two-dimensional sequencing techniques, paper chromatography, and thin-layer chromatography.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Biochemistry</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Studies on gene control regions. 1. Chemical synthesis of lactose operator deoxyribonucleic acid segments.</str>
    <str name="id">322706</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>A definition is proposed for biological ("internal") time tau(t) for a growing organism whose weight variation obeys the law w(t): tau(t) = 1/c(w) (t) = w(t)/w'(t), where t is physical ("external") time, w'(t) is weight increase rate, and c(w) (t) = w'(t)/w(t) is specific growth rate. Properties of functions tau(t) and w(tau) were studied for those cases when growth curves w(t) were described by Bertalanffy's or logistic equations.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Zhurnal obshcheĭ biologii</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">[A concept of relation between physical and biological time in animals].</str>
    <str name="id">15810672</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The taxonomic status of 'Actinoplanes liguriae' A/6353 and 'Actinoplanes teichomyceticus' AB8327 was established by using a polyphasic approach. Strains A/6353 and AB8327 form distinct phylogenetic lineages in the 16S rRNA gene tree of members of the genus Actinoplanes and are related moderately and closely to Actinoplanes rectilineatus and Actinoplanes cyaneus, respectively. Morphological, cultural and physiological properties indicated that strains A/6353 and AB8327 represent separate, novel species of the genus Actinoplanes, Actinoplanes liguriensis sp. nov. (type strain A/6353(T)=FH 2244(T)=DSM 43865(T)=ATCC 31048(T)=BCRC 12121(T)=CBS 355.75(T)=IMSNU 22127(T)=JCM 3250(T)=KCTC 9536(T)=KCC A-0250(T)=NBRC 13997(T)=NCIMB 12636(T)=NRRL B-16723(T)=SANK 62178(T)) and Actinoplanes teichomyceticus sp. nov. (type strain AB8327(T)=FH 2149(T)=DSM 43866(T)=ATCC 31121(T)=BCRC 12106(T)=FERM P-3462(T)=IMSNU 20043(T)=IMET 9254(T)=JCM 3252(T)=KCC A-0252(T)=KCTC 9543(T)=NBRC 13999(T)=NCIMB 12640(T)=NRRL B-16726(T)=SANK 60479(T)).</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">International journal of systematic and evolutionary microbiology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Actinoplanes liguriensis sp. nov. and Actinoplanes teichomyceticus sp. nov.</str>
    <str name="id">16957109</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>A review is presented of functional studies performed with the expanded T cells in Sézary syndrome, T-cell chronic lymphocytic leukemia (T-CLL), T-prolymphocytic leukemia (T-PLL), adult T-cell leukemia lymphoma (ATLL), T-cell acute lymphoblastic leukemia (T-ALL) and T gamma lymphocytosis. The immunological and clinical relevance of immunological studies of functional properties of T-cell expansions is discussed.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Leukemia research</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Immunobiology of the expanded T cells in T-cell leukemia and T-gamma lymphocytosis.</str>
    <str name="id">2872369</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>In 1986, Robert Coffman and Timothy Mossman first described the division of CD4(+) T cells into functional subsets, termed T helper 1 (T(H)1) and T(H)2, based on cytokine production, and in doing so unwittingly opened a Pandora's box of complexity and controversy. Although the mechanisms that regulate T(H)1 and T(H)2 cells are now well known, recent descriptions of other CD4(+) T cell subsets--such as regulatory T cells, T follicular helper cells, T(H)17, T(H)22 and most recently T(H)9 and T(H)22 cells--have questioned how we think of T cell subsets and what commitment to a functional T cell subset means. Here, Nature Reviews Immunology asks four leaders in the field their thoughts on the functional plasticity of T cell subsets.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Nature reviews. Immunology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The functional plasticity of T cell subsets.</str>
    <str name="id">19809471</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The immune sera for Torulopsis apicola, T. bovine, T. colliculosa, T. fructus, T. glabrata, T. haemulonii and T. kestoni agglutinated Salmonella cholerae-suis (6,7). The immune serum for S. cholerae-suis agglutinated Torulopsis apicola, T. bovina, T. colliculosa, T. fructus, T. glabrata, T. haemulonii and T. kestoni. Absorption and agglutination cross test demonstrated common antigen factors in the tested Torulopsis species and in S. cholerae-suis (6,7).</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Zentralblatt für Bakteriologie, Parasitenkunde, Infektionskrankheiten und Hygiene. Erste Abteilung Originale. Reihe A: Medizinische Mikrobiologie und Parasitologie</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">[On the similarity of antigen between torulopsis and salmonella (author's transl)].</str>
    <str name="id">70908</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Anti-T. dionisii and anti-T. vespertilionis monoclonal antibodies secreted by 17 hybridoma clones were tested against various strains of T. dionisii, T. vespertilionis, T. cruzi and T. cruzi marinkellei. Strain and species specific antigens were detected for the homologous immunizing strains. The common antigenic determinants of the tested trypanosome species include a component of the flagellum and different cell structures. Seventeen T. cruzi strains could be classified into two groups when tested with anti-T. dionisii monoclonal antibodies. The cross reactions between T. dionisii and T. cruzi demonstrate a strong correlation between T. dionisii and T. cruzi group 2. On the other hand T. cruzi group 1 and T. cruzi marinkellei show very similar antigenic character.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Acta tropica</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Differentiation of Trypanosoma cruzi, T. cruzi marinkellei, T. dionisii and T. vespertilionis by monoclonal antibodies.</str>
    <str name="id">2424290</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To investigate whether polyomavirus T antigen linked to histones through nucleosome-T antigen complexes has the potential to terminate histone-specific T cell anergy.</str>
      <str>Blood mononuclear cells from healthy individuals were used as the source to establish T cell lines initiated and maintained by T antigen, histones, nucleosome-T antigen complexes, or nucleosomes. Proliferative responses of these lines to T antigen, histones, and nucleosomes were determined.</str>
      <str>Whereas T cell lines could be established using T antigen or T antigen-nucleosome complexes, histones or nucleosomes did not have this potential. However, T cell lines selected by T antigen-nucleosome complexes responded subsequently to histones and nucleosomes. Identical results were obtained with murine and human nucleosomes, provided that they were complexed with T antigen.</str>
      <str>T antigen-specific T cells possess the potential to proliferate when interacting with an antigen-presenting cell that presents T antigen. In the presence of T antigens complexed with nucleosomes, T antigen-specific T cells offer bystander help that may terminate histone-specific T cell anergy. These T cells may progress into functional, autoimmune T cells if histones are properly presented.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Arthritis and rheumatism</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Termination of human T cell tolerance to histones by presentation of histones and polyomavirus T antigen provided that T antigen is complexed with nucleosomes.</str>
    <str name="id">10555041</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The taxonomy of the Tetramorium naganum, T. plesiarum, T. schaufussii, and T. severini species groups are revised for the Malagasy region. A total of 31 species are treated, of which 22 are newly described and nine redescribed. This increases the richness of the hyper-diverse genus Tetramorium in the Malagasy region to 106 species, which makes it the most species-rich genus in the region. Twenty-nine of the treated species are endemic to Madagascar, one is endemic to the Comoros, and one species is found predominantly in Madagascar but also on the island of Reunion. The T. naganum species group contains five species, which are mainly distributed in the rainforests and montane rainforests of eastern and northern Madagascar: T. alperti sp. n., T. dalek sp. n., T. enkidu sp. n., T. gilgamesh sp. n., and T. naganum Bolton, 1979. The T. plesiarum species group holds five species: T. bressleri sp. n., T. hobbit sp. n., T. gollum sp. n., T. mars sp. n., and T. plesiarum Bolton, 1979. All five are arid-adapted species occurring in the southwest and west of Madagascar. The second-most species-rich group in the region is the T. schaufussii species group with 20 species, most of which inhabit rainforests or montane rainforests of eastern and northern Madagascar. This group includes two species complexes each containing ten species: the T. cognatum complex with the species T. aspis sp. n., T. camelliae sp. n., T. cognatum Bolton, 1979, T. freya sp. n., T. gladius sp. n., T. karthala sp. n., T. myrmidon sp. n., T. proximum Bolton, 1979, T. rumo sp. n., and T. tenuinode sp. n.; and the T. schaufussii complex with the species T. merina sp. n., T. monticola sp. n., T. nassonowii Forel, 1892 stat. n., T. obiwan sp. n., T. pseudogladius sp. n., T. rala sp. n., T. schaufussii Forel, 1891, T. sikorae Forel, 1892 (= T. latior (Santschi, 1926)), T. scutum sp. n., T. xanthogaster Santschi, 1911. The last group treated in this study is the T. severini species group, which contains only the species T. severini (Emery, 1895). This very conspicuous species is widely distributed in the rainforests and montane rainforests of eastern and northern Madagascar. All four groups are fully revised with group diagnoses, illustrated species-level identification keys, and detailed descriptions for all species that include multifocused montage images and distribution maps. </str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">ZooKeys</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The hyper-diverse ant genus Tetramorium Mayr (Hymenoptera, Formicidae) in the Malagasy region taxonomic revision of the T. naganum, T. plesiarum, T. schaufussii, and T. severini species groups.</str>
    <str name="id">25009414</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The purpose of this study was to characterize intestinal temperature (T(in)) in comparison to esophageal (T(es)) and rectal temperature (T(re)) during supine exercise.</str>
      <str>Seven subjects completed a continuous supine protocol of 20 min of rest, 20 min of cycle exercise at 40% peak oxygen consumption (V(O2peak)), 20 min of cycle exercise at 65G% V(O2peak), and 20 min of recovery. T(es), T(re), and T(in) were recorded each min.</str>
      <str>Temperatures were not different after 20 min of rest, but T(es) and T(in) were greater than T(re) at the end of the 40% (T(es): 37.38 +/- 0.11; T(in): 37.35 +/- 0.06; T(re): 37.20 +/- 0.10 degrees C) and 65% V(O2peak) stages (T(es): 37.83 +/- 0.10; T(in): 37.75 +/- 0.05; T(re): 37.63 +/- 0.08 degrees C). After 20 min of recovery, T(es) (37.24 +/- 0.011 degrees C) was less than either T(re) or T(in), which were not different from each other (T(in): 37.39 +/- 0.09; T(re): 37.44 +/- 0.09 degrees C). Time to threshold for increased temperature from rest (+0.10 degrees C) for T(es) (10.0 +/- 1.1 min) was not different from T(in) (14.0 +/- 1.2 min) but less than T(re) (15.7 +/- 1.6 min). Time to reach peak temperature was less for T(es) (36.6 +/- 1.8 min) than T(in) (40.6 +/- 0.9 min) and T(re) (41.4 +/- 0.5 min). Similarly, time to a decrease in temperature (-0.10 degrees C) after exercise was less for T(es) (3.7 +/- 0.4 min) than T(in) (7.1 +/- 1.5 min) and T(re) (10.6 +/- 1.9).</str>
      <str>Measurement of T(in) may be an alternative to T(es) to measure T(core) specific time points during exercise with an understanding of the slower response of Tin compared with T(es).</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Aviation, space, and environmental medicine</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Core temperature measurement during supine exercise: esophageal, rectal, and intestinal temperatures.</str>
    <str name="id">11001349</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>T-box-containing protein expressed in T cells (T-bet) is a master transcription factor for the development of interferon (IFN) gamma-producing T helper 1 (Th1) cells and also functions in other immune cells including natural killer (NK), cytotoxic T lymphocytes and dendritic cells. T-bet-deficient mice increased susceptibility to viral infection and tumor development due to the defective functions of immune cells. T-bet is known to play a key role in NK-mediated antimetastatic response; however, it remains to be characterized whether T-bet is essential for in vivo tumor suppression mediated by T cells. Here, we have investigated in vivo tumor suppression effect of T-bet-restored T cells using T cell-specific and inducible T-bet transgenic mice generated in a T-bet-deficient background. T-bet-null mice increased susceptibility to tumor development, whereas induction of T cell-specific T-bet expression upon melanoma cell injection substantially suppressed tumor development by inducing IFNgamma production in T cells and tumor cell apoptosis. Late induction of T-bet expression in tumor-bearing mice produced comparable amounts of IFNgamma with control and significantly decreased tumor volume. In addition, increased melanoma lung metastasis in T-bet-deficient mice was strikingly inhibited by T-bet restoration in T cells. Intravenous injection of activated Th1 cells, not T-bet-null Th1 cells, attenuated metastatic melanoma progression, in addition, restoration of T-bet in T-bet-null Th1 cells certainly retrieved antimetastatic activity. These results suggest that T-bet expression in T cells is crucial for the control of tumor development and antimetastatic activity.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">International journal of cancer. Journal international du cancer</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">In vivo tumor suppression activity by T cell-specific T-bet restoration.</str>
    <str name="id">20143391</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The range of regulatory T cell (T(R) cell) types that control immune responses is poorly understood. We describe here a population of T(R) cells that developed in vivo from naive CD4(+)CD25(-) T cells during a T helper type 1 (T(H)1)-polarized response, distinct from CD25(+) T(R) cells. These antigen-specific T(R) cells were induced by CD8alpha(+) DCs, produced both interleukin 10 and interferon-gamma, and potently inhibited the development of airway hyper-reactivity. These T(R) cells expressed the transcription factors Foxp3 and T-bet, indicating that these T(R) cells are related to T(H)1 cells. Thus, adaptive T(R) cells are heterogeneous and comprise T(H)1-like T(R) cells as well as previously described T(H)2-like T(R) cells, which express Foxp3 and are induced during the development of respiratory tolerance by CD8alpha(-) DCs.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Nature immunology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Induction of T helper type 1-like regulatory cells that express Foxp3 and protect against airway hyper-reactivity.</str>
    <str name="id">15448689</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>In a total of 38 typical T-cell lineage acute lymphocytic leukemia (T-ALL) and T-cell lineage chronic lymphocytic leukemia (T-CLL) cases investigated, we found that CC chemokine receptor CCR9 was selectively and frequently expressed on T-ALL CD4+ T cells, was moderately expressed on T-CLL CD4+ T cells, and was rarely expressed on normal CD4+ T cells. These findings were demonstrated at protein and mRNA levels using flow cytometry and real-time quantitative reverse transcription-PCR technique and were verified by digital confocal microscopy and Northern blotting. Thymus-expressed chemokine, a ligand for CCR9, selectively induced T-ALL CD4+ T-cell chemotaxis and adhesion. Interleukin (IL)-2 and IL-4, together, down-regulated the expression and functions of CCR9 in T-ALL CD4+ T cells including chemotaxis and adhesion. It was also demonstrated that IL-2 and IL-4, together, internalized CCR9 on T-ALL CD4+ T cells and subsequently inhibited functions of CCR9 in these cells. Thymus-expressed chemokine mRNA was highly expressed in CD4+ T cells, involving lymph node and skin in T-ALL patients, and was expressed at moderate levels in lymph node and skin tissues in T-CLL patients. Our findings may provide new clues to understanding various aspects of T-ALL CD4+ T cells, such as functional expression of CCR9-thymus-expressed chemokine receptor-ligand pairs as well as the effects of IL-2 and IL-4, which may be especially important in cytokine/chemokine environment for the pathophysiological events of T-ALL CD4+ T-cell trafficking.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Cancer research</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Selectively increased expression and functions of chemokine receptor CCR9 on CD4+ T cells from patients with T-cell lineage acute lymphocytic leukemia.</str>
    <str name="id">14559839</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To investigate the association between oral neoplasm genetic susceptibility and genetic polymorphism of p53 intron 7.</str>
      <str>The intron 7 ApaI polymorphism of p53 was analyzed in 95 oral neoplasm patients and 105 healthy individuals by utilizing polymerase chain reaction-restriction fragment length polymorphism (PCR-RFLP) genotyping assay technique, and direct sequencing was performed in 30 cases which were selected from the patients and controls by random sampling.</str>
      <str>In oral neoplasms cases, haplotype combinations were T-G 43.2%, C-T 56.8%, and frequencies of genotype were T-G/T-G 15.8%, C-T/T-G 54.7%, C-T/C-T 29.5%, while in controls they were T-G 30.9%, C-T 69.1% and T-G/T-G 10.5%, C-T/T-G 41.0%, C-T/C-T 48.5%. There was a significant difference in the allelic frequency and the genotypical distributions between the oral neoplasm patients and the controls. The individuals with the T-G allele had a slight increasing neoplasm risk than individuals with C-T allele; the OR for T-G versus C-T was 1.69 (95% CI, 1.12 - 2.51). The risk of suffering from oral neoplasms was higher in the individuals of T-G/T-G genotype and of T-G/C-T genotype than in individuals of C-T/CT genotype with odds ratio of 2.48 versus 2.20.</str>
      <str>There are two polymorphic points in the 7th intron of human p53 gene, which could be associated with genetic susceptibility of oral neoplasms. T-G allele may be the risk factor of oral neoplasms.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Zhonghua kou qiang yi xue za zhi = Zhonghua kouqiang yixue zazhi = Chinese journal of stomatology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">[p53 gene intron 7 polymorphism and its association with oral neoplasms].</str>
    <str name="id">16255923</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>T follicular helper (T(FH)) cells reside in the light zone of germinal centers and are considered the cell of origin of angioimmunoblastic T-cell lymphoma. Recently, CXCL13, PD-1 and SAP were described as useful markers for T(FH) cells and angioimmunoblastic T-cell lymphoma but also reported in some peripheral T-cell lymphomas, not otherwise specified.</str>
      <str>In the present study the expression pattern of ICOS protein was investigated by immunohistochemistry-based techniques in routine sections of normal lymphoid tissues and 633 human lymphomas.</str>
      <str>Cells strongly positive for ICOS were restricted to the light zone of germinal centers and co-expressed T(FH)-associated molecules. In addition, weak to moderate ICOS expression was observed in a small proportion of FOXP3-positive cells. In lymphomas, ICOS expression was confined to angioimmunoblastic T-cell lymphoma (85/86), peripheral T-cell lymphomas of follicular variant (18/18) and a proportion of peripheral T-cell lymphomas, not otherwise specified (24/56) that also expressed other T(FH)-associated molecules.</str>
      <str>ICOS is a useful molecule for identifying T(FH) cells and its restricted expression to angioimmunoblastic T-cell lymphoma and a proportion of peripheral T-cell lymphomas, not otherwise specified (showing a T(FH)-like profile) suggests its inclusion in the antibody panel for diagnosing T(FH)-derived lymphomas. Our findings provide further evidence that the histological spectrum of T(FH)-derived lymphomas is broader than previously assumed.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Haematologica</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The inducible T-cell co-stimulator molecule is expressed on subsets of T cells and is a new marker of lymphomas of T follicular helper cell-derivation.</str>
    <str name="id">20207847</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Three novel moderately anaerobic, thermophilic, rod-shaped bacterial strains, KY38(T), KY46(T) and KA13(T), were isolated from shellfish collected on the Pacific coastline of Enoshima, Japan. Phylogenetic analysis of the 16S rRNA gene sequences indicated that these bacteria belong to the genus Symbiobacterium, sharing sequence similarities of 97.8% (KY38(T)), 96.4% (KY46(T)) and 93.3% (KA13(T)) with the type strain of Symbiobacterium thermophilum, the only species of the genus with a validly published name. These isolates reduced nitrate and grew optimally at 55-60 °C. Strains KY38(T) and KA13(T) formed endospore-like structures in the terminal or subterminal part of their cells at low frequencies. Genomic DNA G+C contents were 68.8 (KY38(T)), 67.2 (KY46(T)) and 67.1 (KA13(T)) mol%. The isolates all presented the predominant menaquinone MK-6, major fatty acids iso-C15:0, C16:0 and iso-C17:0 and the major polar lipids phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine and unknown glycol-containing phospholipids. On the basis of their morphological, physiological and phylogenetic properties, strains KY38(T), KY46(T) and KA13(T) represent three novel species, for which the names Symbiobacterium ostreiconchae sp. nov. (type strain KY38(T) = DSM 27624(T) = KCTC 4567(T) = JCM 15048(T)), Symbiobacterium turbinis sp. nov. (type strain KY46(T) = DSM 27625(T) = KCTC 4568(T) = JCM 15996(T)) and Symbiobacterium terraclitae sp. nov. (type strain KA13(T) = DSM 27138(T) = KCTC 4569(T) = JCM 15997(T)) are proposed. An emended description of the genus Symbiobacterium is also presented. The phylogenetic distinctiveness of the genus Symbiobacterium indicates its affiliation with a novel family, for which the name Symbiobacteriaceae fam. nov. is proposed.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">International journal of systematic and evolutionary microbiology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Description of Symbiobacterium ostreiconchae sp. nov., Symbiobacterium turbinis sp. nov. and Symbiobacterium terraclitae sp. nov., isolated from shellfish, emended description of the genus Symbiobacterium and proposal of Symbiobacteriaceae fam. nov.</str>
    <str name="id">25013225</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Effector memory T cells (T(EM)) have an important role in immunity against infection. However, little is known about the factors regulating T(EM) maintenance and proliferation. In this study, we investigated the role of direct interactions between CD4(+) and CD8(+) T cells (TC) for human T(EM) expansion. Proliferation of separated or mixed CD4(+) and CD8(+)T(EM) populations was analyzed after polyclonal stimulation in vitro. Compared to each isolated subset mixed T(EM) populations showed increased proliferation and expansion of both CD4(+) and CD8(+)T(EM) subpopulations. Combined activation of CD4(+) and CD8(+) memory T cells (Tmem) induced an increased expression of CD40L and CD40 on both populations. Subsequently, CD40/CD40L caused a bi-directional stimulation of CD40(+)CD4(+)T(EM) by CD40L(+)CD8(+)T(EM) and of CD40(+)CD8(+)T(EM) by CD40L(+)CD4(+)T(EM). Blocking of CD40L on activated CD8(+)T(EM) selectively inhibited proliferation of CD4(+)T(EM), while blocking of CD40L on CD4(+)T(EM) abrogated proliferation of CD8(+)T(EM). Taken together, we demonstrate for the first time that the expression of CD40L is exploited on the one hand by CD8(+)T(EM) to increase the proliferation of activated CD4(+)T(EM) and on the other hand by CD4(+)T(EM) to support the expansion of activated CD8(+)T(EM). Thus, efficient T(EM) expansion requires bi-directional interactions between CD4(+) and CD8(+)T(EM) cells.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Immunology and cell biology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">CD40L co-stimulation from CD8+ to CD4+ effector memory T cells supports CD4+ expansion.</str>
    <str name="id">21151195</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Immune control of the protozoan parasite Trypanosoma cruzi requires the activation of both CD4+ and CD8+ T cells. We recently identified two T. cruzi trans-sialidase peptides that are targets of approximately 30% of all CD8+ T cells during acute T. cruzi infection in mice. To determine whether CD4+ T cells are required for generation of these dominant CD8+ T-cell responses, major histocompatibility complex class II (MHC II)-deficient mice were infected with the Brazil strain of T. cruzi and examined for the generation of antigen-specific CD8+ T cells. Strong trans-sialidase TSKB18- and TSKB20-specific CD8+ T-cell responses were generated in both the presence and the absence of CD4+ help. However, the magnitudes of the immunodominant TSKB20-specific CD8+ T-cell responses detectable using class I MHC-peptide tetramers were consistently lower in the blood and spleens of MHC II-deficient mice. Spleen cells from infected MHC II-deficient mice produced gamma interferon after in vitro stimulation with T. cruzi peptides at levels similar to those in wild-type mice, and MHC II-deficient mice displayed strong T. cruzi peptide-specific cytotoxic T-lymphocyte activity in vivo. Thus, primary CD8+ T-cell responses in experimental T. cruzi infection are generated in the absence of CD4+ T cells, providing further evidence that T. cruzi directly activates and licenses antigen-presenting cells. Nevertheless, unhelped CD8+ T cells in T. cruzi-infected mice fail to reach the frequencies achieved in the presence of CD4 T-cell help and are unable to prevent acute-phase death of these mice.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Infection and immunity</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Limited role for CD4+ T-cell help in the initial priming of Trypanosoma cruzi-specific CD8+ T cells.</str>
    <str name="id">17043105</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Kawasaki disease (KD) is a pediatric self-limited vasculitis characterized by immune-mediated destruction of the arterial wall and myocardium. Neither the trigger that incites the inflammation nor the switch that turns it off is known. To further our understanding of KD pathogenesis and the role of regulatory T-cells in modulating the inflammatory response, we studied circulating effector memory T-cells (CCR7- and IL-15+ T(em)) and central memory T-cells (CCR7+ and IL-15+ T(cm)) in six KD subjects. In two of the subjects, we cloned the remaining T-cell population by limiting dilution. TaqMan analysis of T(em) studied in two KD subjects suggested that T(em) are pro-inflammatory CD4+T-helper 1 cells and CD8+ cytotoxic T-cells. Following memory T-cells over time, we defined that circulating T(em) and T(cm) are detectable during the acute phase in some KD subjects before treatment with intravenous immunoglobulin. Both T(em) and T(cm) expand rapidly within 2 weeks of treatment. The circulating T(em) pool contracts, while T(cm) further proliferate in the convalescent phase. Following depletion of memory T-cells, numerous T-cell clones were derived from two acute KD subjects. The large majority of these T-cells displayed the functional phenotype of peripherally induced regulatory T-cells (T(reg)). These findings provide insight into the nature and kinetics of the adaptive immune response in KD.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Autoimmunity</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Memory T-cells and characterization of peripheral T-cell clones in acute Kawasaki disease.</str>
    <str name="id">20166878</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The T cell repertoire in patients with advanced cutaneous T cell lymphoma (CTCL) is significantly contracted despite the presence of relatively normal absolute numbers of T cells. We propose that many normal T cells were being lost in patients with CTCL, with the remaining normal T cells expanding clonally to fill the T cell compartment. T-cell receptor excision circles (TREC) form as a result of the initial gene rearrangement in naïve T cells. Although they are stable, they do not replicate and are subsequently diluted with the expansion of a population of T cells. Their concentration is therefore a measure of unexpanded naïve T cells relative to T cells that have undergone expansion.</str>
      <str>We analyzed TRECs from unfractionated peripheral blood T cells from 108 CTCL patients by quantitative PCR. In patients with obvious peripheral blood involvement, we also analyzed TRECs from clonal and nonclonal T cells.</str>
      <str>We found a decrease in the number of TRECs in peripheral blood of patients with CTCL at all stages of disease, and this decrease was proportional to the loss of complexity of the T cell repertoire as measured by complementarity-determining region 3 spectratyping. In patients with leukemic CTCL and a numerically expanded clone, we also found a significantly lower-than-expected number of TRECs in the nonclonal normal T cells.</str>
      <str>We hypothesize that the nonmalignant T cells have proliferated to fill the empty T cell repertoire space left by the loss of other T cells, leading to diminished TRECs and loss of T-cell receptor diversity.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Clinical cancer research : an official journal of the American Association for Cancer Research</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Decreased T-cell receptor excision circles in cutaneous T-cell lymphoma.</str>
    <str name="id">16115912</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The aim of the study was to evaluate the influence of alloimmunization on the composition of PBL subpopulations in women with recurrent spontaneous abortions (RSA) of unknown etiology.</str>
      <str>25 women with history of 3-6 consecutive RSA were selected for this study. Immunization with paternal lymphocytes, isolated from 100 ml of peripheral blood, was performed two times before conception (4-weeks interval). The following parameters were studied: (%) of peripheral T CD3+, T CD4+, T CD8+, T CD4+/CD45-RO+, T CD4+/CD29+, T CD8+/CD45-RO+, BCD19+ and NK CD16+/CD56+ lymphocytes; (%) of T CD3+ cells with markers of early (CD69+) and late activation (HLA-DR+) and presenting with IL-2 receptors (CD25+); the influence of alloimmunization on the expression of CD69+ receptors on cultured T CD3+ lymphocytes activated by PHA (CD3+/CD69+/FCS).</str>
      <str>The (%) of T CD3+ (61.0% vs. 68.6%), T CD4+ (37.4% vs. 45.3%) cells as well as T CD4+/T CD8+ ratio (1.3 vs. 1.0) significantly increased, whereas the (%) of T CD8+ (41.3% vs. 32.5%) and NK CD16+/CD56+ cells (23.9% vs. 16.2%) decreased after alloimmunization. The procedure didn't influence the (%) of T CD4+/CD45-RO+, T CD4+/CD29+, T CD8+/CD45-RO+ and BCD19+ lymphocytes. We observed significant increase of the (%) of T CD3+/CD69+ (4.4% vs. 7.3%) and T CD3+/CD25+ (5.8% vs. 10.9%) cells after immunotherapy. Moreover we observed the significant increase of the CD69+ expression on T CD3+ cells activated by PHA (CD3+/CD69+/FCS) (42.1 vs. 47.1%).</str>
      <str>Our study suggests that alloimmunization of women with RSA of unknown etiology results in increase of T lymphocytes' activity and a shift of the immune balance towards T helper and T supressor lymphocytes.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Ginekologia polska</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">[Influence of paternal lymphocyte immunization on the selected subpopulations of peripheral blood lymphocytes in women with recurrent spontaneous abortions of unknown etiology].</str>
    <str name="id">12916271</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The 53-kDa proteins in larval excretory and secretory (E-S) products were expressed from five Trichinella species (T. spiralis, T. britovi, T. nativa, T. pseudospiralis, and T. papuae), using the Escherichia coli expression system, and the antibody responses to the 53-kDa recombinant proteins in mice infected with Trichinella spp. were analyzed by Western blotting. The 53-kDa protein is conserved among the five Trichinella species, with &gt;60% similarity in amino acid sequences. The 53-kDa recombinant proteins of T. spiralis and T. pseudospiralis reacted to sera from mice infected with T. spiralis and T. pseudospiralis at 8 days postinfection (p.i.), respectively. An antibody against the 53-kDa recombinant protein of T. spiralis recognized the 53-kDa protein in the crude extracts from adult worms and 30-day p.i. muscle larvae and E-S products from muscle larvae of T. spiralis but did not recognize any proteins from T. pseudospiralis. The sera from the mice infected with T. spiralis strongly reacted with the 53-kDa recombinant protein of T. spiralis but did not react with the 53-kDa recombinant proteins of T. britovi, T. nativa, T. pseudospiralis, and T. papuae. Similarly, the sera from mice infected with T. britovi, T. nativa, T. pseudospiralis, or T. papuae strongly reacted with the 53-kDa recombinant proteins of T. britovi, T. nativa, T. pseudospiralis, or T. papuae, respectively. These results showed that the 53-kDa recombinant proteins provide early and species-specific antibody responses in mice infected with Trichinella spp.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Clinical and vaccine immunology : CVI</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Species-specific antibody responses to the recombinant 53-kilodalton excretory and secretory proteins in mice infected with Trichinella spp.</str>
    <str name="id">18184826</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Myelodysplastic syndrome (MDS) and T-cell large granular lymphocytic disease (T-LGL) are bone marrow failure disorders. Successful use of immunosuppressive agents to treat cytopenia in MDS and LGL suggests a common pathophysiology for the two conditions. Of 100 patients with initial diagnoses of either MDS or T-LGL referred to the National Institutes of Health for immunosuppressive treatment of cytopenia, nine had characteristics of both T-LGL and MDS (T-LGL/MDS). Fifteen patients with T-LGL received cyclosporin (CSA) (10 responses). Eight out of nine patients with T-LGL/MDS received CSA (two responses) and one patient received ATG (one response). Of 76 patients with MDS, eight received CSA (one response) and 68 received ATG (21 responses). The response to immunosuppression was significantly lower in patients with T-LGL/MDS and MDS than in patients with T-LGL disease alone (28% vs. 66%, P = 0.01). The proportion of T-helper cells and T-suppressor cells with an activated phenotype (HLA-DR(+)) was increased in patients with T-LGL, T-LGL/MDS and MDS, but the increase in activated T-suppressor cells in patients with T-LGL/MDS was not statistically significant. Autoreactive T cells may suppress haematopoiesis and contribute to the cytopenia in T-LGL and some patients with MDS, leading to T-LGL/MDS. The lower response rate of MDS or T-LGL/MDS to immunosuppression, compared with T-LGL alone, may reflect the older age and intrinsic stem cell abnormalities in MDS and T-LGL/MDS patients.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">British journal of haematology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Coincident myelodysplastic syndrome and T-cell large granular lymphocytic disease: clinical and pathophysiological features.</str>
    <str name="id">11167802</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Previous studies have shown that tolerogenic anti-CD4 (W3/25) and anti-LFA-1 mAb (LRTC1) which block T cell activation paradoxically enhance T cell-mediated antigen presentation. Lasting T cell APC (T-APC) activity requires and initial exposure of T cells to these mAb in the presence of professional APC and antigen. This study revealed a central mechanism regulating the duration of T-APC activity. T cell recognition of class II MHC complexes of T-APC catalyzed a rapid decay in the presentation of agonistic antigens, whereas partial agonistic signals decayed at a shower rate. Likewise, blockade of agonistic T-T cell autorecognition by these mAb led to the persistence of agonistic MHC/antigen on T-APC. The best predictor of T-APC activity was related to the ability of clonal T cells to respond to antigen presented by neighboring T cells. Strong responders were inefficient T-APC, whereas inefficient responders were strong T-APC. Addition of irradiated myelin basic protein (MBP0-specific responders to T-APC cultures specifically inhibited the subsequent presentation of MBP but not conalbumin, and vice versa. T-APC presentation of antigen to responder T cells also resulted in reduced surface expression of class II MHC I-A glycoproteins on T-APC. These findings indicate that agonistic recognition of antigen of T-APC specifically inhibits subsequent presentation of that antigen, whereas antagonistic MHC/antigen complexes are preserved for an enduring T-APC activity.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Cellular immunology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Class II MHC/peptide complexes on T cell antigen-presenting cells: agonistic antigen recognition inhibits subsequent antigen presentation.</str>
    <str name="id">9665753</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>We attempted to optimize scan parameters for T₁-weighted fluid-attenuated inversion recovery (T₁-FLAIR) sequence at 3 and 1.5 tesla (T) using computer simulation.</str>
      <str>We measured the T₁ and T₂ relaxation time values (T₁v and T₂v) of gray (GM) and white matter (WM) at 3 and 1.5T, generated computer-simulated T₁-FLAIR (CS-T₁-FLAIR) images using those values, and compared the simulated and actual T₁-FLAIR images to verify the contrast reliability of our computer simulation. We mathematically and visually evaluated CS-T₁-FLAIR images at various repetition times (TR) and echo times (TE).</str>
      <str>At 3T, the measured relaxation values for GM were T₁v, 1524 ms, and T₂v, 85 ms, and for WM, T₁v, 750 ms, and T₂v, 65 ms. At 1.5T, the measured relaxation values for GM were T₁v, 1251 ms, and T₂v, 99 ms, and for WM, T₁v, 623 ms, and T₂v, 75 ms. Contrast of CS-T₁-FLAIR and actual T₁-FLAIR images was identical. An optimal TR of 3140 ms was determined for T₁-FLAIR at 3T and 2440 ms at 1.5T based on mathematical evaluation. The optimal TR ranges were 2400 to 3900 ms at 3T and 1800 to 3200 ms at 1.5T based on visual assessment of CS-T₁-FLAIR. A shorter TE provided better T₁ contrast.</str>
      <str>We optimized T₁-FLAIR by focusing on its most important scan parameters using computer simulations and determined that a longer TR was suitable at 3T than at 1.5T. Our computer simulation was useful for determining the optimal scan parameters.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Magnetic resonance in medical sciences : MRMS : an official journal of Japan Society of Magnetic Resonance in Medicine</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Optimization of scan parameters for T₁-FLAIR imaging at 1.5 and 3T using computer simulation.</str>
    <str name="id">23857155</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>T lymphocytes recognize specific ligands by clonally distributed T-cell receptors (TCR). In humans and most animals, the vast majority of T cells express a TCR composed of an alpha chain and a beta chain, whereas a minor T-cell population is characterized by the TCR gamma/delta. Almost all of our knowledge about T cells stems from alpha/beta T cells and only now are we beginning to understand gamma/delta T cells. In contrast to conventional alpha/beta T cells, which are specific for antigenic peptides presented by gene products of the major histocompatibility complex, gamma/delta T cells directly recognize proteins and even nonproteinacious phospholigands. These findings reveal that gamma/delta T cells and alpha/beta T cells recognize antigen in a fundamentally different way and hence mitigate the dogma of exclusive peptide-major histocompatibility complex recognition by T cells. A role for gamma/delta T cells in antimicrobial immunity has been firmly established. Although some gamma/delta T cells perform effector functions, regulation of the professional and the nonprofessional immune system seems to be of at least equal importance. The prominent residence of gamma/delta T cells in epithelial tissues and the rapid mobilization of gamma/delta T cells in response to infection are consistent with such regulatory activities under physiological and pathologic conditions. Thus, although gamma/delta T cells are a minor fraction of all T cells, they are not just uninfluential kin of alpha/beta T cells but have their unique raison d'être.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">gamma/delta and other unconventional T lymphocytes: what do they see and what do they do?</str>
    <str name="id">8637862</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>CD8+ T cells are the major mediators of cytotoxic T cell activity controlling viral infections in normal mice. CD8+ T cells have also been implicated in regulating the activity of other immune cells. We have examined the possible regulatory role of CD8+ T cells on CD4+ T cells by comparing immune responses in mice expressing normal CD8+ T cell responses and in CD8+ T cell-deficient beta2-microglobulin "knockout" mice. In normal mice, infection with lymphocytic choriomeningitis virus (LCMV) results in a biphasic T cell immune response. First, CD8+ T cells proliferate and produce interferon-gamma (IFN-gamma), and then 2 to 4 days later CD4+ T cells proliferate and produce IFN-gamma. CD8+ T cell activity is not detected during LCMV infection in beta2-microglobulin-deficient mice. However, in beta2-microglobulin-deficient mice the CD4+ T cell expansion is exaggerated and occurs 2 days earlier than observed in normal mice. Furthermore, the CD4+ T cells have substantial cytotoxic activity, which is not observed in the CD4+ T cell population in normal mice. However, CD4+ T cell IFN-gamma production in beta2-microglobulin-deficient mice lags behind the proliferative response, resulting in a relative delay in overall T cell IFN-gamma production compared to normal mice. Taken together, these data suggest that CD8+ T cell activation peaks at an earlier time point than CD4+ T cell activation during the primary immune response to LCMV and that CD8+ T cells may inhibit CD4+ T cell proliferation and the development of CD4+ T cell cytotoxic activity.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Cellular immunology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Altered kinetics of CD4+ T cell proliferation and interferon-gamma production in the absence of CD8+ T lymphocytes in virus-infected beta2-microglobulin-deficient mice.</str>
    <str name="id">8912885</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>CD8 T cells exhibit dynamic alterations in proliferation and apoptosis during various phases of the CD8 T-cell response, but the mechanisms that regulate cellular proliferation from the standpoint of CD8 T-cell memory are not well defined. The cyclin-dependent kinase inhibitor p27(Kip1) functions as a negative regulator of the cell cycle in T cells, and it has been implicated in regulating cellular processes, including differentiation, transcription and migration. Here, we investigated whether p27(Kip1) regulates CD8 T-cell memory by T-cell-intrinsic or T-cell-extrinsic mechanisms, by conditional ablation of p27(Kip1) in T cells or non-T cells. Studies of T-cell responses to an acute viral infection show that p27(Kip1) negatively regulates the proliferation of CD8 T cells by T-cell-intrinsic mechanisms. However, the enhanced proliferation of CD8 T cells induced by T-cell-specific p27(Kip1) deficiency minimally affects the primary expansion or the magnitude of CD8 T-cell memory. Unexpectedly, p27(Kip1) ablation in non-T cells markedly augmented the number of high-quality memory CD8 T cells by enhancing the accumulation of memory precursor effector cells without increasing their proliferation. Further studies show that p27(Kip1) deficiency in immunizing dendritic cells fail to enhance CD8 T-cell memory. Nevertheless, we have delineated the T-cell-intrinsic, anti-proliferative activities of p27(Kip1) in CD8 T cells from its role as a factor in non-T cells that restricts the development of CD8 T-cell memory. These findings have implications in vaccine development and understanding the mechanisms that maintain T-cell homeostasis.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Immunology and cell biology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">T-cell intrinsic and extrinsic mechanisms of p27Kip1 in the regulation of CD8 T-cell memory.</str>
    <str name="id">23207280</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Three new immunogens which were prepared by conjugation of the carboxymethyl oxime (CMO) derivatives of HT-2 toxin, T-2 tetraol (T-2 4ol), and T-2 tetraol tetraacetate (T-2 4Ac) to bovine serum albumin (BSA) were tested for the production of antibodies against the major metabolites of T-2 toxin. Antibodies against HT-2 toxin and T-2 4Ac were obtained from rabbits 5 to 10 weeks after immunizing the animals with CMO-HT-2-BSA and CMO-T-2 4Ac-BSA conjugates. Immunization with CMO-T-2 4ol-BSA resulted in no antibody against T-2 4ol. The antibody produced against HT-2 toxin had great affinity for HT-2 toxin as well as good cross-reactivity with T-2 toxin. The relative cross-reactivities of anti-HT-2 toxin antibody with HT-2 toxin, T-2 toxin, iso-T-2 toxin, acetyl-T-2 toxin, 3'-OH HT-2, 3'-OH T-2, T-2 triol, and 3'-OH acetyl-T-2, were 100, 25, 10, 3.3, 0.25, 0.15, 0.12 and 0.08%, respectively. Antibody against CMO-T-2 4Ac was very specific for T-2 4Ac and had less than 0.1% cross-reactivity with T-2 toxin, HT-2 toxin, acetyl-T-2 toxin, diacetoxyscirpenol, deoxynivalenol, and deoxynivalenol triacetate as compared with T-2 4Ac. The detection limits for HT-2 toxin and T-2 4ol by radioimmunoassay were approximately 0.1 and 0.5 ng per assay, respectively.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Applied and environmental microbiology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Production and characterization of antibodies against HT-2 toxin and T-2 tetraol tetraacetate.</str>
    <str name="id">3827243</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>This study aimed to determine the feasibility, reproducibility, and reliability of the multiecho T*(2) Magnetic resonance imaging technique at 3 T for myocardial and liver iron burden quantification and the relationship between T*(2) values at 3 and 1.5 T. Thirty-eight transfusion-dependent patients and 20 healthy subjects were studied. Cardiac segmental and global T*(2) values were calculated after developing a correction map to compensate the artifactual T*(2) variations. The hepatic T*(2) value was determined over a region of interest. The intraoperator and interoperator reproducibility for T*(2) measurements at 3 T was good. A linear relationship was found between patients' R *2 (1000/T*(2) ) values at 3 and 1.5 T. Segmental correction factors were significantly higher at 3 T. A conversion formula returning T*(2) values at 1.5 T from values at 3 T was proposed. A good diagnostic reliability for T*(2) assessment at 3 T was demonstrated. Lower limits of normal for 3 T T*(2) values were 23.3 ms, 21.1 ms, and 11.7 ms, for the global heart, mid-ventricular septum, and liver, respectively. In conclusion, T*(2) quantification of iron burden in the mid-ventricular septum, global heart, and no heavy-moderate livers resulted to be feasible, reproducible, and reliable at 3 T. Segmental heart T*(2) analysis at 3 T may be challenging due to significantly higher susceptibility artifacts.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Magnetic resonance in medicine</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Feasibility, reproducibility, and reliability for the T*2 iron evaluation at 3 T in comparison with 1.5 T.</str>
    <str name="id">22127999</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The developmental pathways of long-lived memory CD8 T cells and the lineage relationship between memory T cell subsets remain controversial. Although some studies indicate the two major memory T cell subsets, central memory T (T(CM)) and effector memory T (T(EM)), are related lineages, others suggest that these subsets arise and are maintained independently of one another. In this study, we have investigated this issue and examined the differentiation of memory CD8 T cell subsets by tracking the lineage relationships of both endogenous and TCR transgenic CD8 T cell responses after acute infection. Our data indicate that TCR transgenic as well as nontransgenic T(EM) differentiate into T(CM) in the absence of Ag. Moreover, the rate of memory CD8 T cell differentiation from T(EM) into the self-renewing and long-lived pool of T(CM) is influenced by signals received during priming, including Ag levels, clonal competition, and/or the duration of infection. Although some T(EM) appear to not progress to T(CM), the vast majority of T(CM) are derived from T(EM). Thus, long-lasting, Ag-independent CD8 T cell memory results from progressive differentiation of memory CD8 T cells, and the rate of memory T cell differentiation is governed by events occurring early during T cell priming.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Journal of immunology (Baltimore, Md. : 1950)</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Strength of stimulus and clonal competition impact the rate of memory CD8 T cell differentiation.</str>
    <str name="id">17982060</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Low serum testosterone (T) is common and increasingly prevalent with increased age. Recent studies report an 'epidemic' of T prescribing and concern about unnecessary T treatment. We investigated the number of men tested for T, the prevalence of low serum T levels, and initiation of T treatment among those with low T levels in men treated at Veterans Affairs (VA) facilities in the Northwest US (VISN 20). We identified male Veterans aged 40-89 years and examined yearly proportions of men tested for T, found to have low T levels (total T &lt; 280 ng/dL, free T &lt; 34 pg/mL, or bioavailable T &lt; 84 ng/dL), and subsequently treated with T from 2002 to 2011. We excluded men who had T treatment in the year prior and men with diagnoses of prostate or breast cancer. Treatment initiation was defined as the first prescription for T within a year following a low T test. From 2002 to 2011, the yearly population of eligible men in VISN 20 increased from 129 247 to 163 572. The proportion of men who had serum T tests increased from 3.2% in 2002 to 5.8% in 2011. Among the tested men, the percentage of men with low T levels increased from 35.0 to 47.3%. However, the proportion of men with low T levels who were given T treatment within a year decreased from 31.0 to 28.0%. Despite large increases in T testing, and detection of men with low T levels, there was a slight decrease in the proportion of men with low T levels who were treated with T. The decrease in T treatment during this time period contrasts with other studies and may be related to higher comorbidity in Veterans and/or VA formulary restrictions on the use of transdermal T formulations.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Andrology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Recent trends in testosterone testing, low testosterone levels, and testosterone treatment among Veterans.</str>
    <str name="id">25684636</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To gain further understanding of the mechanisms involved in Agrobacterium-mediated genetic transformation and T-DNA integration, we analysed 156 T-DNA/rice, 69 T-DNA/T-DNA and 11 T-DNA/vector backbone (VB) junctions, which included 171 left borders (LB) and 134 right borders (RB). Conserved cleavage was observed in 6% of the LB and 43% of the RB. Terminal microhomology (1-10bp) was identified in 58% of T-DNA/rice, 43% of T-DNA/T-DNA and 82% of T-DNA/VB junctions, and this occurred particularly at the LB junctions. Approximately 32% of both T-DNA/rice and T-DNA/T-DNA junctions harboured 1-344bp of filler DNA that was derived mainly from the T-DNA region adjacent to the breakpoint and/or from the rice genome flanking the T-DNA integration site. Structure of the filler DNA was more complicated at the T-DNA/T-DNA junction than at the T-DNA/rice junction, indicating the presence of T-DNA recombination or rearrangement prior to or during T-DNA integration. When two T-DNAs were integrated in the inverted repeat configuration, significant truncation was always observed in one of the two T-DNAs whereas with direct repeat configuration, a large truncation was less frequent. Most integration events analysed in this study could be addressed by previously proposed models; however, the characteristics of the T-DNA repeats and the complicated filler DNA between two T-DNA copies imply that multiple mechanisms are involved in the formation of T-DNA repeats as well as in T-DNA integration in plants.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Plant science : an international journal of experimental plant biology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Transgene structures suggest that multiple mechanisms are involved in T-DNA integration in plants.</str>
    <str name="id">22980200</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Transducin (T alpha and T beta gamma) is a GTP-binding protein involved in the visual transduction process in a rod outer segment. We have previously demonstrated that T beta gamma is a mixture composed of two components, T beta gamma-1 and T beta gamma-2, with distinctive gamma-subunits, T gamma-1 and T gamma-2, respectively (Fukada et al., 1989, J. Biol. Chem., 264, 5937-5943). To investigate the interaction between T alpha and the two components of T beta gamma, the effect of either T beta gamma-1 or T beta gamma-2 on the ADP-ribosylation of T alpha catalyzed by pertussis toxin (IAP) was examined. T beta gamma-2 stimulated the ADP-ribosylation of T alpha by IAP, while T beta gamma-1 displayed almost no enhancement of the ADP-ribosylation. Addition of T beta gamma-1 to the mixture of T alpha and T beta gamma-2 had no effect on the ADP-ribosylation of T alpha. These results indicate that T alpha and T beta gamma-2 form a complex that serves as a substrate of IAP in the ADP-ribosylation reaction, while T beta gamma-1 has a little affinity for T alpha. It was suggested that T gamma-2 is an essential subunit for T beta to interact with T alpha.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Biochemical and biophysical research communications</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">A specific beta gamma-subunit of transducin stimulates ADP-ribosylation of the alpha-subunit by pertussis toxin.</str>
    <str name="id">2322268</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Using the framework of multiconfiguration theory, where the wavefunction Φ(t) of a many-electron system at time t is expanded as Φ(t)=Σ(I)C(I)(t)Φ(I)(t) in terms of electron configurations {Φ(I)(t)}, we divided the total electronic energy E(t) as E(t)=Σ(I)|C(I)(t)|(2)E(I)(t) . Here E(I)(t) is the instantaneous phase changes of C(I)(t) regarded as a configurational energy associated with Φ(I)(t). We then newly defined two types of time-dependent states: (i) a state at which the rates of population transfer among configurations are all zero; (ii) a state at which {E(I)(t)} associated with the quantum phases of C(I)(t) are all the same. We call the former time-dependent state a classical stationary state by analogy with the stationary (steady) states of classical reaction rate equations and the latter one a quantum stationary state. The conditions (i) and (ii) are satisfied simultaneously for the conventional stationary state in quantum mechanics. We numerically found for a LiH molecule interacting with a near-infrared (IR) field ε(t) that the condition (i) is satisfied whenever the average velocity of electrons is zero and the condition (ii) is satisfied whenever the average acceleration is zero. We also derived the chemical potentials μ(j)(t) for time-dependent natural orbitals ϕ(j)(t) of a many-electron system. The analysis of the electron dynamics of LiH indicated that the temporal change in Δμ(j)(t) ≡ μ(j)(t) + ε(t) · d(j)(t) - μ(j)(0) correlates with the motion of the dipole moment of ϕ(j)(t), d(j)(t). The values Δμ(j)(t) are much larger than the energy ζ(j)(t) directly supplied to ϕ(j)(t) by the field, suggesting that valence electrons exchange energy with inner shell electrons. For H2 in an intense near-IR field, the ionization efficiency of ϕ(j)(t) is correlated with Δμ(j)(t). Comparing Δμ(j)(t) to ζ(j)(t), we found that energy accepting orbitals of Δμ(j)(t) &gt; ζ(j)(t) indicate high ionization efficiency. The difference between Δμ(j)(t) and ζ(j)(t) is significantly affected by electron-electron interactions in real time.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">The Journal of chemical physics</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Characterization of multielectron dynamics in molecules: a multiconfiguration time-dependent Hartree-Fock picture.</str>
    <str name="id">25240343</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>We investigated the function of CD56+ CD8+ T cells (CD56+ T cells) and CD56- CD57+ CD8+ T cells (CD57+ T cells; natural killer (NK)-type T cells) and compared them with those of normal CD56- CD57- CD8+ T cells (CD8+ T cells) and CD56+ NK cells from healthy volunteers. After the stimulation with immobilized anti-CD3 antibodies, both NK-type T cells produced much larger amounts of interferon-gamma (IFN-gamma) than CD8+ T cells. Both NK-type T cells also acquired a more potent cytotoxicity against NK-sensitive K562 cells than CD8+ T cells while only CD56+ T cells showed a potent cytotoxicity against NK-resistant Raji cells. After the stimulation with a combination of interleukin (IL)-2, IL-12 and IL-15, the IFN-gamma amounts produced were NK cells &gt; or = CD56+ T cells &gt; or = CD57+ T cells &gt; CD8+ T cells. The cytotoxicities against K562 cells were NK cells &gt; CD56+ T cells &gt; or = CD57+ T cells &gt; CD8+ T cells while cytotoxicities against Raji cells were CD56+ T cells &gt; CD57+ T cells &gt; or = CD8+ T cells &gt; or = NK cells. However, the CD3-stimulated proliferation of both NK-type T cells was smaller than that of CD8+ T cells partly because NK-type T cells were susceptible to apoptosis. In addition to NK cells, NK-type T cells but not CD8+ T cells stimulated with cytokines, expressed cytoplasmic perforin and granzyme B. Furthermore, CD3-stimulated IFN-gamma production from peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMC) correlated with the proportions of CD57+ T cells in PBMC from donors. Our findings suggest that NK-type T cells play an important role in the T helper 1 responses and the immunological changes associated with ageing.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Immunology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Systematic characterization of human CD8+ T cells with natural killer cell markers in comparison with natural killer cells and normal CD8+ T cells.</str>
    <str name="id">11454057</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The purpose of this study was to investigate the detectability of small hot lesions in 2-dimensional transmission+emission (2D T/E), 2-dimensional simultaneous transmission+emission (2D simultaneous T/E) and 3-dimensional transmission+emission (3D T/E) acquisition modes in an 18F-fluorodeoxyglucose positron emission tomography (FDG PET) scan. The correlation between target detectability, target size, target to non-target uptake ratio (T/N ratio), and standardized uptake value (SUV) were studied. Small hot lesions ranging from 4.4 mm to 36.9 mm in diameter were set in a cylindrical phantom. The images of phantoms with T/N ratios of 2.0, 4.0, 6.0, 8.0, 9.6, 13.2, 17.5, 23.8 and 30.3 were obtained in 2D T/E, 2D simultaneous T/E and 3D T/E scans. Tumour uptake of 2-[18F]fluoro-2-deoxy-d-glucose (FDG) in a rabbit bearing VX-2 tumours was also studied in 2D T/E, 2D simultaneous T/E and 3D T/E scans. The target with a diameter &gt; 10.6 mm and an actual T/N ratio from 6.0 to 30.3 could be identified on the images obtained with all the 2D T/E, 2D simultaneous T/E and 3D T/E acquisition modes. The detectability efficiency of a small hot target was found to be 77.8% in 2D T/E and 3D T/E, but 75.9% in 2D simultaneous T/E. The T/N ratio and recovery coefficient (RC) of the target from the 2D simultaneous T/E image was very similar to that from 2D T/E, and the SUV of the target from the 2D T/E image was almost the same as that from the 2D simultaneous T/E and 3D T/E images. This study indicated that 2D simultaneous T/E scanning and 3D T/E had similar abilities for detecting the tumour as did 2D T/E scanning. 2D T/E, 2D simultaneous T/E and 3D T/E scanning had the same feasibility for semi-quantitative analysis using SUV, as well as using the T/N ratios for 2D T/E and 2D simultaneous T/E. In contrast, the use of the T/N ratio in 3D T/E scanning gave an inferior result in semi-quantative analysis, although there might have been an improvement if a scatter correction had been performed.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Nuclear medicine communications</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Tumour detectability in 2-dimensional and 3-dimensional positron emission tomography using the SET-2400W: a phantom study.</str>
    <str name="id">11314763</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>T cell immune responses are regulated by the interplay between effector and suppressor T cells. Immunization with Ag leads to the selective expansion and survival of effector CD4(+) T cells with high affinity TCR against the Ag and MHC. However, it is not known if CD4(+)CD25(+) regulatory T cells (T(reg)) recognize the same Ag as effector T cells or whether Ag-specific TCR repertoire modification occurs in T(reg). In this study, we demonstrate that after a primary Ag challenge, T(reg) proliferate and TCR repertoire modification is observed although both of these responses were lower than those in conventional T cells. The repertoire modification of Ag-specific T(reg) after primary Ag challenge augmented the total suppressive function of T(reg) against TCR repertoire modification but not against the proliferation of memory CD4(+) T cells. These results reveal that T cell repertoire modification against a non-self Ag occurs in T(reg), which would be crucial for limiting excess primary and memory CD4(+) T cell responses. In addition, these studies provide evidence that manipulation of Ag-specific T(reg) is an ideal strategy for the clinical use of T(reg).</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Journal of immunology (Baltimore, Md. : 1950)</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Antigen-specific T cell repertoire modification of CD4+CD25+ regulatory T cells.</str>
    <str name="id">15100262</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Although CD4(+) T cells form a major subset of TCRalphabeta T cells, only a small number of TCRgammadelta T cells express CD4. Factors contributing to the down-regulation of CD4(+) TCRgammadelta T cells have not been identified. The CD5 molecule is expressed on most TCRgammadelta T cells in the spleen, whereas only a few intestinal intraepithelial TCRgammadelta T cells express this molecule in wild-type mice and TCRbeta mutant (beta(-/-)) mice. Unexpectedly, in the present studies, the lack of CD5 led to a remarkable increase of a CD4(+) TCRgammadelta T cell subset in CD5(-/-)beta(-/-) mice. The CD4(+) TCRgammadelta T cells were also detectable in MHC II(-/-)CD5(-/-)beta(-/-) triple-mutant mice. This CD4(+) TCRgammadelta T cell subset provided help in Mycobacterium-induced germinal center (GC) formation and showed a T(h)-like cytokine profile. In contrast, CD5(+) TCRgammadelta T cells suppressed the CD4(+) TCRgammadelta T cell-mediated GC formation, presumably by eliminating this CD4(+) subset. Unlike intraepithelial gammadelta T cells, &gt;30% of TCRgammadelta T cells in the colonic lamina propria (LP) expressed CD5. The lack of CD5 also led to increased numbers of CD4(+) TCRgammadelta T cells in the colonic LP and increased susceptibility to development of chronic colitis in beta(-/-) mice. Cell transfer studies suggest that CD5(+) TCRgammadelta T cells are capable of selectively eliminating CD4(+) TCRgammadelta T cells in the intestine. The CD4(+) TCRgammadelta T cells possess immune functions similar to CD4(+) TCRalphabeta T cells.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">International immunology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Role of the CD5 molecule on TCR gammadelta T cell-mediated immune functions: development of germinal centers and chronic intestinal inflammation.</str>
    <str name="id">12502730</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The magnitude and complexity of Ag-specific CD8(+) T cell responses is determined by intrinsic properties of the immune system and extrinsic factors, such as vaccination. We evaluated mechanisms that regulate the CD8(+) T cell response to two distinct determinants derived from the same protein Ag, SV40 T Ag (T Ag), following immunization of C57BL/6 mice with T Ag-transformed cells. The results show that direct presentation of T cell determinants by T Ag-transformed cells regulates the magnitude of the CD8(+) T cell response in vivo but not the immunodominance hierarchy. The immunodominance hierarchy was reversed in a dose-dependent manner by addition of excess naive T cells targeting the subdominant determinant. However, T cell competition played only a minor role in limiting T cell accumulation under physiological conditions. We found that the magnitude of the T cell response was regulated by the ability of T Ag-transformed cells to directly present the T Ag determinants. The hierarchy of the CD8(+) T cell response was maintained when Ag presentation in vivo was restricted to cross-presentation, but the presence of T Ag-transformed cells capable of direct presentation dramatically enhanced T cell accumulation at the peak of the response. This enhancement was due to a prolonged period of T cell proliferation, resulting in a delay in T cell contraction. Our findings reveal that direct presentation by nonprofessional APCs can dramatically enhance accumulation of CD8(+) T cells during the primary response, revealing a potential strategy to enhance vaccination approaches.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Journal of immunology (Baltimore, Md. : 1950)</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Direct presentation regulates the magnitude of the CD8+ T cell response to cell-associated antigen through prolonged T cell proliferation.</str>
    <str name="id">20660711</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Heterologous antisera to murine or rat T-cell antigen-binding molecules (T-ABM) were raised in rabbits or sheep. The T-ABM used for immunization were purified by affinity for antigen and did not bear known immunoglobulin isotypes. T-ABM and anti-T-ABM were raised in three separate laboratories. Antisera to T-ABM were exchanged and tested for binding to T-ABM in three separate laboratories. Thus antisera to at least three distinct T-ABM were tested directly for binding to T-ABM or by adsorption of biological activity. Rabbit antisera to murine trinitrophenol (TNP)-specific T-ABM or rat AgB-specific T-ABM bound both murine or rat T-ABM, indicating evolutionary conservation of T-ABM. Similar results were found with sheep antisera to murine T-ABM. In addition, all heterologous anti-T-ABM antisera used bound murine T-ABM specific for TNP, 4-hydroxy-3-nitrophenyl acetate (NP), SRBC, or T-cell membrane proteins with similar structure. Thus, there is a commonality of antigenic determinants between various T-ABM and T-cell membrane homologues which may be T-cell surface receptors for foreign antigen.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Cellular immunology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Affinity-purified antigen-specific products produced by T cells share epitopes recognized by heterologous antisera raised against several different antigen-specific products from T cells.</str>
    <str name="id">6197189</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>T-cell proliferation rates in vitro depend on factors including initial T-cell number, dose of stimulus, culture time, and available physical space. The role of forkhead box P3 (FoxP3) in the identification of T cells with a regulatory phenotype remains controversial in humans. Through 5-carboxyfluorescein diacetate succinimidyl ester labeling of human T cells and subsequent culture of different numbers of T cells and antigen-presenting cells (APC), we studied proliferative T-cell responses and FoxP3 expression in divided T cells. T-cell proliferation rates depended on initial T-cell/APC numbers. Proliferation rates decreased when high initial T-cell numbers were increased. FoxP3 expression was expressed exclusively in virtually all divided T cells cultured at high T-cell densities, irrespective of their CD4 nature or cytokine content, and was coexpressed with T-bet. However, when T cells were cultured on larger surfaces or at lower initial numbers, FoxP3 expression was not induced in divided T cells, even when most of the cells had undergone cell division. FoxP3(+) T cells generated at high cell densities did not elicit a suppressive phenotype and FoxP3 expression was subsequently lost in time when the stimulus was removed. Therefore, caution should be observed in the use of FoxP3 expression to identify regulatory T cells in humans because its expression may be only a consequence of activation status in a restricted environment.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Human immunology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">T-cell proliferation and forkhead box P3 expression in human T cells are dependent on T-cell density: physics of a confined space?</str>
    <str name="id">22248741</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Specific cellular immunotherapy of cancer requires efficient generation and expansion of cytotoxic T lymphocytes (CTLs) that recognize tumor-associated self-antigens. Here, we investigated the capacity of human γδ T cells to induce expansion of CD8+ T cells specific for peptides derived from the weakly immunogenic tumor-associated self-antigens PRAME and STEAP1. Coincubation of aminobisphosphonate-stimulated human peripheral blood-derived γδ T cells (Vγ9+Vδ2+), loaded with HLA-A*02-restricted epitopes of PRAME, with autologous peripheral blood CD8+ T cells stimulated the expansion of peptide-specific cytolytic effector memory T cells. Moreover, peptide-loaded γδ T cells efficiently primed antigen-naive CD45RA+ CD8+ T cells against PRAME peptides. Direct comparisons with mature DCs revealed equal potency of γδ T cells and DCs in inducing primary T-cell responses and peptide-specific T-cell activation and expansion. Antigen presentation by γδ T-APCs was not able to overcome the limited capacity of peptide-specific T cells to interact with targets expressing full-length antigen. Importantly, T cells with regulatory phenotype (CD4+ CD25hiFoxP3+) were lower in cocultures with γδ T cells compared to DCs. In summary, bisphosphonate-activated γδ T cells permit generation of CTLs specific for weakly immunogenic tumor-associated epitopes. Exploiting this strategy for effective immunotherapy of cancer requires strategies that enhance the avidity of CTL responses to allow for efficient targeting of cancer.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Cancer immunology, immunotherapy : CII</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Activated human γδ T cells induce peptide-specific CD8+ T-cell responses to tumor-associated self-antigens.</str>
    <str name="id">21928126</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The nuclear hormone receptor retinoic acid receptor-related orphan receptor gamma t (RORgamma t) is required for the generation of T helper 17 cells expressing the proinflammatory cytokine interleukin (IL)-17. In vivo, however, less than half of RORgamma t(+) T cells express IL-17. We report here that RORgamma t(+) T alphabeta cells include Foxp3(+) cells that coexist with IL-17-producing RORgamma t(+) T alphabeta cells in all tissues examined. The Foxp3(+) RORgamma t(+) T alphabeta express IL-10 and CCL20, and function as regulatory T cells. Furthermore, the ratio of Foxp3(+) to IL-17-producing RORgamma t(+) T alphabeta cells remains remarkably constant in mice enduring infection and inflammation. This equilibrium is tuned in favor of IL-10 production by Foxp3 and CCL20, and in favor of IL-17 production by IL-6 and IL-23. In the lung and skin, the largest population of RORgamma t(+) T cells express the gammadelta T cell receptor and produce the highest levels of IL-17 independently of IL-6. Thus, potentially antagonistic proinflammatory IL-17-producing and regulatory Foxp3(+) RORgamma t(+) T cells coexist and are tightly controlled, suggesting that a perturbed equilibrium in RORgamma t(+) T cells might lead to decreased immunoreactivity or, in contrast, to pathological inflammation.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">The Journal of experimental medicine</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">In vivo equilibrium of proinflammatory IL-17+ and regulatory IL-10+ Foxp3+ RORgamma t+ T cells.</str>
    <str name="id">18504307</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Three bacterial isolates from air samples in Korea, designated strains 6424S-25(T), 6515J-31(T) and 6424S-61(T), were characterized using a polyphasic approach. The cells were strictly aerobic, Gram-stain-negative, non-motile, non-spore-forming and rod-shaped. Phylogenetic analysis of their 16S rRNA gene sequences revealed a clear affiliation with the phylum Bacteroidetes. Strains 6424S-25(T) and 6515J-31(T) showed 16S rRNA gene sequence similarities of 92.7-94.8 % to type strains of recognized species of the genus Adhaeribacter and strain 6424S-61(T) was closely related to Segetibacter koreensis Gsoil 664(T) (93.9 % similarity). The G+C contents of the DNA of strains 6424S-25(T), 6515J-31(T) and 6424S-61(T) were 44.5, 43.9 and 38.4 mol%, respectively. Major fatty acids of strains 6424S-25(T) and 6515J-31(T) were summed feature 4 (iso-C₁₇:₁ I and/or anteiso-C₁₇ :₁ B), iso-C₁₅:₀ and C₁₆:₁ω5c. The fatty acid content of strain 6424S-61(T) mainly comprised iso-C₁₅ :₁ G and iso-C₁₅:₀. Comparative analysis of phenotypic and phylogenetic traits indicated that strains 6424S-25(T) and 6515J-31(T) represented two novel species of the genus Adhaeribacter and that strain 6424S-61(T) should be considered as a novel species of the genus Segetibacter. The names Adhaeribacter aerophilus sp. nov. (type strain 6424S-25(T) =KACC 14118(T) =NBRC 106134(T)), Adhaeribacter aerolatus sp. nov. (type strain 6515J-31(T) =KACC 14117(T) =NBRC 106133(T)) and Segetibacter aerophilus sp. nov. (type strain 6424S-61(T) =KACC 14119(T) =NBRC 106135(T)) are proposed for these organisms.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">International journal of systematic and evolutionary microbiology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Adhaeribacter aerophilus sp. nov., Adhaeribacter aerolatus sp. nov. and Segetibacter aerophilus sp. nov., isolated from air samples.</str>
    <str name="id">19946049</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Some of the recently observed functional features characteristic of immunocompetent cells residing in the human intestinal lamina propria could be mediated by interleukin-10 (IL-10). To investigate the role of IL-10 in the human intestinal mucosa, the regulation of IL-10 production by lamina propria T lymphocytes (LPL-T) was determined and compared with that of peripheral blood T lymphocytes (PBL-T).</str>
      <str>Following activation by using different stimuli, IL-10 release by LPL-T and PBL-T into the supernatant was measured by enzyme linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA). In parallel, cell growth was determined by [3H]-thymidine incorporation.</str>
      <str>Neither LPL-T nor PBL-T release IL-10 constitutively. Triggering through CD2 or the T cell receptor (TCR)/CD3 complex in the presence of autologous monocytes induces significantly greater IL-10 secretion by LPL-T than by PBL-T. Engagement of the CD45 receptor enhances IL-10 release and proliferation of CD2 triggered CD45RO+ PBL-T. In contrast, it reduces CD2 induced IL-10 production by LPL-T without altering cell growth significantly.</str>
      <str>Activated LPL-T release relatively high amounts of IL-10. Enhanced IL-10 production by activated LPL-T, in comparison with activated PBL-T, is not only related to the presence of a higher proportion of CD45RO+ T cells in the intestinal lamina propria, but is also caused by increased sensitivity of LPL-T to CD2 co-stimulation. The differential responsiveness of LPL-T, compared with PBL-T, to CD45 engagement demonstrates that CD45 could be involved in the altered CD2 reactivity of LPL-T.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Gut</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">T cells of the human intestinal lamina propria are high producers of interleukin-10.</str>
    <str name="id">9301501</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>CD4 and CD8 T cell subsets involved in primary allo-MLR responses were re-evaluated in the present study. The slope analysis of B6 allo-MLR responses to MHC class I-disparate bm1 and class II-disparate bm12 revealed the presence of a T-T cell interaction between CD4 and CD8 T cell subsets. The allo-MLR response of B6 CD4 T cells to bm12 was completely blocked by anti-L3T4, indicating that the function of CD4 T cells is required for allo-MLR responses to bm12. It was further demonstrated that the function of CD8 T cells in class II-disparate allo-MLR is to augment the proliferative response of CD4 T cells. On the other hand, CD8 T cells primarily responded to class I-disparate allo-MLR, and CD4 T cells function to augment the proliferative response of CD8 T cells. It was further indicated that CD4 and CD8 T cells recognize both class I and class II MHC. The CD4 T cell recognition of allo-class I and CD8 T cell recognition of allo-class II induces insufficient signals for proliferation of these T cells. Thus, the class I-reactive CD4 and class II-reactive CD8 T cell subsets function as helper cells ('MLR helper' T cells) for proliferating T cells in MLR responses.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">International immunology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Synergistic T-T cell interaction present in alloreactivity: determination of 'MLR helper' T cell subsets.</str>
    <str name="id">1982500</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Although gamma/delta T cells express numerous in vitro functions similar to alpha/beta T cells, little is known about their biological functioning in vivo. Furthermore, it is unclear whether alpha/beta T cells and gamma/delta T cells act independently or in a coordinated way. In the present study, gamma/delta T cells were modulated in vivo by i.p. injection of the anti-gamma/delta T-cell receptor (TCR) monoclonal antibody GL3. GL3 administration caused disappearance of the gamma/delta TCR in spleen and lymph node cells and the gamma/delta TCR was reexpressed after in vitro cultivation for a few days. When cultured in vitro for 4 days, in the absence of foreign antigens, spleen and lymph node alpha/beta T cells from GL3-modulated mice showed vigorous proliferative responses. CD4 T lymphocytes from GL3-modulated mice produced interleukin 2, and CD8 T cells developed into cytolytic T lymphocytes in vitro capable of lysing syngeneic and allogeneic targets. Treatment with heat-inactivated GL3 or with normal hamster immunoglobulin did not cause any of these effects. These findings suggest that the anti-gamma/delta TCR monoclonal antibody GL3 modulates gamma/delta T cells in vivo and that this modulation has profound effects on alpha/beta T-cell reactivity. Hence, the data suggest a role for gamma/delta T cells in the regulation of alpha/beta T-cell activation in vivo.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Crosstalk between alpha/beta T cells and gamma/delta T cells in vivo: activation of alpha/beta T-cell responses after gamma/delta T-cell modulation with the monoclonal antibody GL3.</str>
    <str name="id">8105480</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Two novel thermophilic, spore-forming bacterial strains, T-11(T) and E-112(T), were isolated from hot springs in Tengchong and Eryuan counties of Yunnan province in south-west China. The strains were Gram-stain-positive rods, occurring singly or in chains. Growth of strain T-11(T) was observed between 30 and 75 °C (optimum 50 °C) and at pH 7-11 (optimum pH 8.5), while the temperature range for strain E-112(T) was 35-70 °C (optimum 55 °C) and the pH range was 7.0-11.0 (optimum pH 8.0). The DNA G+C contents of strains T-11(T) and E-112(T) were 41.1 and 42.6 mol%, respectively. On the basis of 16S rRNA gene sequence similarity, the two strains were shown to be related most closely to Anoxybacillus species. The chemotaxonomic characteristics [predominant isoprenoid quinone menaquinone 7 (MK-7); major fatty acids iso-C(15 : 0) and iso-C(17 : 0)] also supported the affiliation of strains T-11(T) and E-112(T) to the genus Anoxybacillus. The results of DNA-DNA hybridization and physiological and biochemical tests allowed genotypic and phenotypic differentiation of strains T-11(T) and E-112(T) from Anoxybacillus species with validly published names. Strains T-11(T) and E-112(T) therefore represent two novel species, for which the names Anoxybacillus tengchongensis sp. nov. (type strain T-11(T) =CCTCC AB209237(T) =KCTC 13721(T)) and Anoxybacillus eryuanensis sp. nov. (type strain E-112(T) =CCTCC AB209236(T) =KCTC 13720(T)) are proposed.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">International journal of systematic and evolutionary microbiology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Anoxybacillus tengchongensis sp. nov. and Anoxybacillus eryuanensis sp. nov., facultatively anaerobic, alkalitolerant bacteria from hot springs.</str>
    <str name="id">20173008</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Aging is associated with a decrease in naïve (T(N)) and central memory (T(CM)), and an accumulation of effector memory (T(EM) and T(EMRA)) T cell subsets. Previously, we have demonstrated an increased sensitivity of T(N) and T(CM) CD4+ and CD8+ T cells in aging to TNF-alpha-induced apoptosis. In this investigation, we examined whether similar differential sensitivity is applicable to CD95-mediated apoptosis. We show that T(N) and T(CM) CD4+ and CD8+ T cells from aged subjects are significantly more sensitive to CD95-mediated apoptosis. Increased apoptosis is associated with increased activation of caspase-8 and caspase-3. Both caspase-8 and caspase-3 inhibitors blocked CD95-mediated apoptosis and activation of caspase-8 and caspase-3 in T(N) and T(CM) CD4+ and CD8+ T cells. No significant difference was observed in apoptosis or in activation of caspase-8 and caspase-3 in T(EM) and T(EMRA) CD4+ and CD8+ T cells between young and aged subjects; both populations were relatively and comparably resistant to CD95-mediated apoptosis and caspase activation. No correlation was observed between the sensitivity/resistance of any of the subsets of CD4+ or CD8+T cells to CD95-mediated apoptosis and the expression of CD95. Our data suggest that increased CD95-mediated apoptosis of T(N) and T(CM) CD8+ and CD4+ T cells may play a role in their decline in human aging.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Experimental gerontology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">CD95-mediated apoptosis in naïve, central and effector memory subsets of CD4+ and CD8+ T cells in aged humans.</str>
    <str name="id">18215485</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The absorption of L-thyroxine (T(4)) and L-triiodothyronine (T(3)) and the fractional rate of conversion of T(4) to T(3) were determined from the turnover rates of T(4) and T(3) in seven patients without endogenous thyroid function during separate treatment periods with these iodothyronines. Serum T(3) concentration was measured by a radioimmunoassay procedure in which the iodothyronines are separated from the plasma proteins before incubation with anti-T(3) antibody. Metabolic clearance rates were calculated by an integral (noncompartmental) approach since the use of single compartment kinetics led to a 40% overestimation of the metabolic clearance rate of T(3). Based on the amount of hormone ingested and the observed hormonal turnover rates, the absorption of T(4) and T(3) (iodothyronine turnover/iodothyronine ingested) in man could be estimated. Absorption of T(3) was complete in three subjects but decreased to 43% in a fourth who was suffering from mild congestive heart failure. Mean T(4) absorption was 48.0+/-2.6% (SEM) for seven subjects. The mean fractional rate of T(4) to T(3) conversion determined during T(4) replacement therapy (T(3) turnover/T(4) turnover) was 42.6% (range 30.7-50.8%). Thus, approximately one-half of the T(4) which was deiodinated was converted to T(3) suggesting that monodeiodination is an obligatory step in the peripheral metabolism of T(4). Calculations based on these results together with other available data suggest that under normal physiologic circumstances the major portion of the T(3) pool is derived from monodeiodination of T(4).</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">The Journal of clinical investigation</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Determination of iodothyronine absorption and conversion of L-thyroxine (T 4 ) to L-triiodothyronine (T 3 ) using turnover rate techniques.</str>
    <str name="id">4693647</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The mechanism(s) responsible for autoimmunity to DNA and nucleosomes in SLE is largely unknown. We have demonstrated that nucleosome-polyomavirus T-Ag complexes, formed in context of productive polyomavirus infection, activate dsDNA-specific B cells and nucleosome-specific CD4(+) T cells. To investigate whether de novo expressed T-Ag is able to terminate nucleosome-specific T cell tolerance and to maintain anti-dsDNA Ab production in nonautoimmune mice, we developed two binary transgenic mouse variants in which expression of SV40 large T-Ag is controlled by tetracycline, MUP tTA/T-Ag (tet-off), and CMV rtTA/T-Ag (tet-on) mice. Data demonstrate that MUP tTA/T-Ag mice, but not CMV rtTA/T-Ag mice, are tightly controlling T-Ag expression. In MUP tTA/T-Ag transgenic mice, postnatal T-Ag expression activated CD8(+) T cells but not DNA-specific B cells, while immunization with T-Ag and nucleosome-T-Ag-complexes before T-Ag expression resulted in elevated and remarkably stable titers of anti-T-Ag and anti-dsDNA Abs and activation of T-Ag-specific CD4(+) T cells. Immunization of nonexpressing MUP tTA/T-Ag mice resulted in transient anti-T-Ag and anti-dsDNA Abs. This system reveals that a de novo expressed DNA-binding quasi-autoantigen maintain anti-dsDNA Abs and CD4(+) T cell activation once initiated by immunization, demonstrating direct impact of a single in vivo expressed molecule on sustained autoimmunity to DNA and nucleosomes.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Journal of immunology (Baltimore, Md. : 1950)</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Autoimmunity to DNA and nucleosomes in binary tetracycline-regulated polyomavirus T-Ag transgenic mice.</str>
    <str name="id">15585891</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The deficient regulatory T cells may play a role in the development of allergic rhinitis.</str>
      <str>A subpopulation of regulatory T cell that produce IL-17a were proved to show an apparent duality of regulatory T cell and effector T helper-17 cells. We studied this subpopulation in patients with allergic rhinitis.</str>
      <str>Fresh whole blood from 20 patients with allergic rhinitis and 19 healthy donors was used to investigate the frequencies of CD4(+)IFN-γ(+) T cells (effector T helper-1), CD4(+)IL-4(+) T cells (effector T helper-2) and CD4(+)IL-17a(+) T cells (effector T helper-17) by flow cytometry after stimulation for 4-6 h. Simultaneously, CD4(+) T lymphocytes were isolated from peripheral blood mononuclear cells and then the frequencies of regulatory T cells and IL-17a-producing regulatory T cells in the allergic rhinitis group were compared with healthy controls after T-cell antigen receptor stimulation for 48 h. The suppressive capacity of CD4(+)CD25(high)CD127(low) regulatory T cells that were stimulated by Dermatophagoides pteronyssinus in both groups was isolated and assessed.</str>
      <str>The frequencies of effector T helper-17 and effector T helper-2 cells were higher in the allergic group compared with healthy controls. Regulatory T cells were similar in both groups, but IL-17a-producing regulatory T cells were increased in the allergic group. In addition, the capacity of regulatory T cells to suppress effector T helper-17 cytokine production was significantly decreased in the allergic group.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Acta oto-laryngologica</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">FOXP3-marked IL-17a-producing regulatory T cells are increased in patients with allergic rhinitis.</str>
    <str name="id">22992221</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Histidine-rich glycoprotein (HRGP) is a plasma and platelet protein with undefined function in vivo. It has been reported to inhibit rosette formation between murine T cells and erythrocytes. We have shown that HRGP binds specifically to human T lymphocytes but not sheep erythrocytes and have demonstrated a 56-kDa HRGP-binding protein on the T cell surface which is distinct from the CD2 sheep erythrocyte receptor. We have now investigated whether HRGP can inhibit human T cell-sheep erythrocyte rosette formation and whether HRGP can modulate T cell activation. HRGP at physiologic concentrations specifically inhibited rosette formation between human T lymphocytes and sheep erythrocytes. HRGP suppressed proliferation of antigen receptor (CD3)-triggered T cells induced by interleukin 2; this suppression was specifically reversed by prior incubation of HRGP with affinity-purified anti-HRGP IgG. Addition of HRGP 12-24 h after CD3 triggering no longer suppressed T cell proliferation, suggesting HRGP suppressed T cell division by interfering with one or more early events in the process of T cell activation. Human serum (containing 100-150 micrograms/ml HRGP) was also capable of suppressing T cell proliferation; serum which had been immunodepleted of HRGP no longer inhibited T cell proliferation. Furthermore, HRGP inhibited interleukin 2 receptor expression on activated T cells, causing decreased T cell interferon-gamma release and altered T cell-dependent inhibition of erythropoiesis. HRGP is thus capable of modulating T cell activation and T cell immunoregulation; HRGP may function as a natural suppressive regulator of human T lymphocyte activation.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">The Journal of biological chemistry</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Histidine-rich glycoprotein blocks T cell rosette formation and modulates both T cell activation and immunoregulation.</str>
    <str name="id">2524479</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Infection with species of Trichostrongylus is common among man and animals in most parts of Iran, and human infections with T. orientalis, T. colubriformis, T. vitrinus, T. axei, T. capricola, T. probolurus, T. skrjabini, and a possibly new, unnamed species have been reported. All are found in Isfahan, central Iran, where the overall prevalence is 67% and the predominant species are T. orientalis and T. colubriformis. Among 737 nomads migrating from the central parts to the south, 86% were found to be infected with one or more of five species (in order of frequency): T. colubriformis, T. orientalis, T. axei, T. capricola, and T. vitrinus. In Khuzestan, southwest Iran, human infections with T. orientalis, T. colubriformis, T. axei, and T. vitrinus with an overall prevalence of 71% have been reported. In the northern parts, along the Caspian Sea, the rate is 7% and the species found, in order of frequency, are T. colubriformis, T. axei, T. vitrinus, and T. orientalis. Trichostrongylus infections are also found in the northwest but are rarely seen in the northeast. In most areas females are more frequently and more heavily infected than are males. All species found in man, except the new, unnamed species, are also found in sheep, goats, cattle, and camels; the number of species found and the order of their frequency differ in various animals and in different areas. Infection in other mammals, such as hares (T. retortaeformis and T. orientalis) and porcupines (T. orientalis), has also been reported.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">The American journal of tropical medicine and hygiene</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Present status of trichostrongyliasis in Iran.</str>
    <str name="id">1239198</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Autoimmune diseases result from a failure of tolerance. Although many self-reactive T cells are present in animals and humans, their activation appears to be prevented normally by regulatory T cells. In this study, we show that regulatory CD4(+) T cells do protect mice against the spontaneous occurrence of experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis (EAE), a mouse model for multiple sclerosis. Anti-myelin basic protein (MBP) TCR transgenic mice (T/R+) do not spontaneously develop EAE although many self-reactive T cells are present in their thymi and peripheral lymphoid organs. However, the disease develops in all crosses of T/R+ mice with recombination-activating gene (RAG)-1 knockout mice in which transgenic TCR-expressing cells are the only lymphocytes present (T/R- mice). In this study, crosses of T/R+ mice with mice deficient for B cells, CD8(+) T cells, NK1.1 CD4(+) T (NKT) cells, gamma/delta T cells, or alpha/beta T cells indicated that alpha/beta CD4(+) T cells were the only cell population capable of controlling the self-reactive T cells. To confirm the protective role of CD4(+) T cells, we performed adoptive transfer experiments. CD4(+) T cells purified from thymi or lymph nodes of normal mice prevented the occurrence of spontaneous EAE in T/R- mice. To achieve full protection, the cells had to be transferred before the recipient mice manifested any symptoms of the disease. Transfer of CD4(+) T cells after the appearance of symptoms of EAE had no protective effect. These results indicate that at least some CD4(+) T cells have a regulatory function that prevent the activation of self-reactive T cells.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">The Journal of experimental medicine</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">CD4(+) T cells prevent spontaneous experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis in anti-myelin basic protein T cell receptor transgenic mice.</str>
    <str name="id">9815265</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Although salivary testosterone (T) is often used in clinical studies accuracy is mostly questionable. State of the art data for men is sparse and for women absent. Our objective was to perform a critical evaluation of salivary T (Sal-T) as a method for indirect assessment of serum T using state of the art methods. Saliva was collected via 'Salivette' and 'passive drooling' methods. Sal-T and free T in serum after equilibrium dialysis were measured by LC-MS/MS RESULTS: Evaluation of Sal-T results versus free T by equilibrium dialysis (ED-T) for men gave: 'Salivette' Sal-T=0.05+0.88x ED-T, r=0.43; 'passive drooling' Sal-T=0.17+0.91x ED-T r=0.71. In women, correlation was comparable but values are higher than free T: 'passive drooling' Sal-T=0.12+2.32x ED-T, r=0.70. The higher than expected T values in saliva, appear to be explained by T binding to salivary proteins. Iso-electric focusing of saliva proteins, followed by fractionation and LC-MS/MS assay of T showed marked testosterone peaks at pH 5.3 and 8.4, providing evidence for T binding in saliva to proteins such as albumin and proline rich protein (PRP).</str>
      <str>Passive drooling is the collection method of choice for testosterone in saliva. Sal-T is not directly comparable to serum free T due to T binding to saliva proteins, which substantially affects the low Sal-T in women but not the higher Sal-T in healthy adult men.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Steroids</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">A critical evaluation of salivary testosterone as a method for the assessment of serum testosterone.</str>
    <str name="id">24793565</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>CD4(+) T cells promote CD8(+) T cell priming by licensing dendritic cells (DCs) via CD40-CD154 interactions. However, the initial requirement for CD40 signaling may be replaced by the direct activation of DCs by pathogen-derived signals. Nevertheless, CD40-CD154 interactions are often required for optimal CD8(+) T cell responses to pathogens for unknown reasons. Here we show that CD40 signaling is required to prevent the premature contraction of the influenza-specific CD8(+) T cell response. CD40 is required on DCs but not on B cells or T cells, whereas CD154 is required on CD4(+) T cells but not CD8(+) T cells, NKT cells, or DCs. Paradoxically, even though CD154-expressing CD4(+) T cells are required for robust CD8(+) T cell responses, primary CD8(+) T cell responses are apparently normal in the absence of CD4(+) T cells. We resolved this paradox by showing that the interaction of CD40-bearing DCs with CD154-expressing CD4(+) T cells precludes regulatory T cell (T reg cell)-mediated suppression and prevents premature contraction of the influenza-specific CD8(+) T cell response. Thus, CD4(+) T helper cells are not required for robust CD8(+) T cell responses to influenza when T reg cells are absent. </str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">The Journal of experimental medicine</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">CD4+ T helper cells use CD154-CD40 interactions to counteract T reg cell-mediated suppression of CD8+ T cell responses to influenza.</str>
    <str name="id">23835849</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To investigate the effect of siRNAs specific for T-bet and Eomesodermin (Eomes) in interferon-gamma (IFN-gamma) production of different human T cell subsets.</str>
      <str>Double-stranded small interfering RNA (siRNA) sequences specific for genes of T-bet and Eomes were chemically synthesized and transfected into anti-CD3 mAb activated alphabeta T cells and Mtb-Ag activated gammadelta T cells. CD4(+), CD8(+) T and gammadelta T cells were sorted by flow cytometry and the expressions of T-bet and Eomes gene mRNA were detected by RT-PCR technique. The changes of IFN-gamma production were determined by flow cytometry.</str>
      <str>After two series of transfection, the siRNA-FAM(+) cells were about 50% in the transfected cells. The IFN-gamma(+) cells in CD4(+) T cells (50.20%) decreased in the cells transfected with T-bet siRNA (18.46%) but no obvious decrease was observed in the cells transfected with Eomes siRNA, whereas the IFN-gamma(+) cells in CD8(+) T cells (76.51%) decreased in the cells transfected with Eomes siRNA (25.37%) and no obvious decrease was observed in the cells transfected with T-bet siRNA. However, the IFN-gamma producing cells in gammadelta T cells (76.52%) decreased in the cells transfected with T-bet siRNA (56.57%) or with Eomes siRNA (42.53%).</str>
      <str>At the level of transcription factors, T-bet and Eomes are important transcription factors for the regulation of IFN-gamma production in CD4(+) and CD8(+) T cells, respectively. Both T-bet and Eomes may simultaneously be involved in the regulation of the IFN-gamma production of gammadeltaT cells.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Xi bao yu fen zi mian yi xue za zhi = Chinese journal of cellular and molecular immunology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">[Role of transcription factor T-bet and Eomes in IFN-gamma secretion of different human T cell subsets].</str>
    <str name="id">20056084</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To determine how the activation of γδ T cells affects the generation of uveitogenic αβ T cells and the development of experimental autoimmune uveitis (EAU).</str>
      <str>γδ T cells were isolated from B6 mice immunized with the uveitogenic peptide IRBP(1-20) and αβ T cells from immunized TCR-δ(-/-) mice. Resting γδ T cells were prepared by culture of separated γδ T cells in cytokine-free medium for 3 to 5 days, when they showed downregulation of CD69 expression. Activated γδ T cells were prepared by incubating resting γδ T cells with anti-γδ TCR (GL3) for 2 days. Responder αβ T cells were cocultured with immunizing antigen and antigen-presenting cells. The numbers of antigen-specific T cells expressing IL-17 or IFN-γ were determined by intracellular staining followed by FACS analysis after stimulation, with or without the addition of purified γδ T cells. The cytokines in the culture medium were measured by ELISA.</str>
      <str>Highly enriched γδ T cells exert widely different effects on autoreactive αβ T cells in EAU, depending on the activation status of the γδ T cells. Whereas nonactivated γδ T cells had little effect on the activation of interphotoreceptor retinoid-binding protein-specific αβ T cells in vitro and in vivo, activated γδ T cells promoted the generation of uveitogenic T cells and exacerbated the development of EAU.</str>
      <str>The functional ability of γδ T cells is greatly influenced by their activation status. Activated γδ T cells exacerbate EAU through increased activation of uveitogenic T cells.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Investigative ophthalmology &amp; visual science</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Activated gammadelta T cells promote the activation of uveitogenic T cells and exacerbate EAU development.</str>
    <str name="id">21296823</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The content of T-lymphocytes and their basic subpopulations T-helpers and T-suppressors have been studied by means of monoclonal antibodies in the peripheral blood of 104 patients with different forms of psoriasis (56 patients with psoriasis vulgaris, 25 with exudative psoriasis, 10 with psoriasis arthropathica, and 13 with erythrodermic psoriasis). In all forms of psoriasis with a slight alteration in T-lymphocyte content a significant dysbalance of T-helpers and T-suppressors was found that brought about a decrease in the correlation ratio T-helpers/T-suppressors (T-helpers/T-suppressors in patients suffering from psoriasis vulgaris, 1.55 +/- 0.12; in those with exudative psoriasis, 1.24 +/- 0.16; with psoriasis arthropathica, 1.33 +/- 0.16; with erythrodermic psoriasis, 1.33 +/- 0.18; the control showed 1.82 +/- 0.08). The decrease in T-helpers/T-suppressors to 1.2 and lower that corresponded to a more severe clinical course of the disease was revealed in 27 patients having psoriasis vulgaris, in 13 with exudative psoriasis, in 7 with psoriasis arthropathica, and in 9 with erythrodermic psoriasis. The dysbalance in T-helpers/T-suppressors was due to a decrease in T-helpers and an increase in T-suppressors. To normalize T-helpers/T-suppressors, 27 psoriatics (20 with psoriasis vulgaris, 6 with exudative psoriasis, 1 with erythrodermic psoriasis) received immunomodulators Thymalinum and Natrii nucleinas in addition to antipsoriatic therapy, which resulted in an increase in T-helper/T-suppressor ratio, on the average up to 1.74 +/- 0.16 (prior to treatment T-helper/T-suppressor ratio in these patients was 1.0 +/- 0.14) and was followed by a favorable clinical course (shorter periods of skin rash regression, prolonged remissions).(ABSTRACT TRUNCATED AT 250 WORDS)</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Subpopulations of T lymphocytes in psoriasis patients and their changes during immunotherapy.</str>
    <str name="id">2963042</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The author reviews the immunophenotypic profiles displayed by the major clinicopathologic categories of T cell neoplasia, the immunophenotypic criteria useful in the immunodiagnosis of T cell neoplasia, and the contributions made by antigen receptor gene rearrangement analysis to the understanding of T cell neoplasia. Neoplasms belonging to distinct clinicopathologic categories of T cell neoplasia often exhibit characteristic immunophenotypic profiles. Approximately 80% of lymphoblastic lymphomas and 20% of acute lymphoblastic leukemias express phenotypes consistent with prethymic and intrathymic stages of T cell differentiation, including intranuclear terminal deoxynucleotidyl transferase. Cutaneous T cell lymphomas of mycosis fungoides type usually express pan-T cell antigens CD2, CD5, and CD3, often lack the pan-T cell antigen CD7, and usually express the mature, peripheral helper subset phenotype, CD4+ CD8-. Cutaneous T cell lymphomas of nonmycosis fungoides type and peripheral T cell lymphomas often lack one or more pan-T cell antigens and, in addition, occasionally express the anomalous CD4+ CD8+ or CD4- CD8- phenotypes. T gamma-lymphoproliferative disease is divisable into two broad categories: those cases that are CD3 antigen positive and exhibit clonal T cell receptor beta chain (TCR-beta) gene rearrangements and those cases that are CD3 antigen negative and exhibit the TCR-beta gene germline configuration. Human T cell lymphotropic virus-I (HTLV-I) associated Japanese, Carribean, and sporadic adult T cell leukemia/lymphomas usually express pan-T cell antigens, the CD4+ CD8- phenotype, and various T cell-associated activation antigens, including the interleukin-2 receptor (CD25). Immunophenotypic criteria useful in the immunodiagnosis of T cell neoplasia include, in increasing order of utility, T cell predominance, T cell subset antigen restriction, anomalous T cell subset antigen expression, and deletion of one or more pan-T cell antigens. Only in exceptional circumstances do normal, non-neoplastic T cell populations express the CD4- CD8- or the CD4+ CD8+ phenotype and/or lack one or more pan-T cell antigens. T cell receptor beta chain gene rearrangement analysis represents an accurate, objective, and sensitive molecular genetic marker of T cell lineage and clonality that allows discrimination among non-T cell, polyclonal T cell and monoclonal T cell populations. Non-T cells exhibit the TCR-beta gene germline configuration.(ABSTRACT TRUNCATED AT 400 WORDS)</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">The American journal of pathology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Immunophenotypic and antigen receptor gene rearrangement analysis in T cell neoplasia.</str>
    <str name="id">2495724</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Chromosome abnormalities were documented in the PHA-stimulated lymphoid cells from 10 patients with chronic T-cell leukemias (6 T-PLL, 3 T-CLL and 1 T-LCL). One or more marker chromosomes were present in most metaphases in every case of T-PLL but they were different in each case. Structural abnormalities were also observed in T-CLL and T-LCL but less consistently. Chromosomes involved in marker formation in two or more cases were: Nos. 2, 7, 8, 9, 11 and 16. The karyotype was hypodiploid in five cases and hyperdiploid in two. Chromosomes Nos. 2 and 8 were the most frequently involved in structural and numerical abnormalities: Nos. 8 in 2 T-CLL and the 6 T-PLL and No. 2 in 1 T-CLL, 1 T-LCL and 5 T-PLL. Abnormalities of chromosome No. 2 are rare in human neoplastic disease but may be common in T-lymphoproliferative disorders. The differences between T-PLL and T-CLL reported here may have some bearing on the clinical features. T-PLL, characterised in all cases by clonal abnormalities, has an aggressive clinical course. In contrast, T-CLL with less consistent karyotypic changes has a protracted and benign clinical evolution.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Leukemia research</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Chronic T-cell leukemias. II. Cytogenetic studies.</str>
    <str name="id">6978433</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Cytotoxic T lymphocyte antigen-4 (CTLA-4) is an inhibitory receptor on T cells essential for maintaining T cell homeostasis and tolerance to self. Mice lacking CTLA-4 develop an early onset, fatal breakdown in T cell tolerance. Whether this autoimmune disease occurs because of the loss of CTLA-4 function in regulatory T cells, conventional T cells, or both is unclear. We show here that lack of CTLA-4 in regulatory T cells leads to aberrant activation and expansion of conventional T cells. However, CTLA-4 expression in conventional T cells prevents aberrantly activated T cells from infiltrating and fatally damaging nonlymphoid tissues. These results demonstrate that CTLA-4 has a dual function in maintaining T cell tolerance: CTLA-4 in regulatory T cells inhibits inappropriate naïve T cell activation and CTLA-4 in conventional T cells prevents the harmful accumulation of self-reactive pathogenic T cells in vital organs.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Dual function of CTLA-4 in regulatory T cells and conventional T cells to prevent multiorgan autoimmunity.</str>
    <str name="id">20080649</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>CD4+ T cell priming under T helper type I (T(H)1) or T(H)2 conditions gives rise to polarized cytokine gene expression. We found that in these conditions human naive T cells acquired stable histone hyperacetylation at either the Ifng or Il4 promoter. Effector memory T cells showed polarized cytokine gene acetylation patterns in vivo, whereas central memory T cells had hypoacetylated cytokine genes but acquired polarized acetylation and expression after appropriate stimulation. However, hypoacetylation of the nonexpressed cytokine gene did not lead to irreversible silencing because most T(H)1 and T(H)2 cells acetylated and expressed the alternative gene when stimulated under opposite T(H) conditions. Such cytokine flexibility was absent in a subset of T(H)2 cells that failed to up-regulate T-bet and to express interferon-gamma when stimulated under T(H)1 conditions. Thus, most human CD4+ T cells retain both memory and flexibility of cytokine gene expression.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Nature immunology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Memory and flexibility of cytokine gene expression as separable properties of human T(H)1 and T(H)2 lymphocytes.</str>
    <str name="id">12447360</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The peripheral blood lymphocytes of patients with recurrent aphthous ulcers (RAU) were studied during various stages of their disease by two-color immunofluorescence with the use of monoclonal antibodies directed against human T cells (CD3), T helper cells (CD4), T suppressor cells (CD8), T helper/inducer cells (CDw29), and T suppressor/inducer cells (CD45R). All patients with severe RAU showed increased numbers of T helper/inducer cells (CDw29) and decreased numbers of T suppressor/inducer cells (CD45R). One of six patients with RAU showed a decreased T helper/T suppressor ratio (CD4/CD8). These findings suggest that patients with RAU may possess primary immunologic abnormalities.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Oral surgery, oral medicine, and oral pathology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Alterations of T helper/inducer and T suppressor/inducer cells in patients with recurrent aphthous ulcers.</str>
    <str name="id">1689479</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Ag-experienced or memory T cells have increased reactivity to recall Ag, and can be distinguished from naive T cells by altered expression of surface markers such as CD44. Memory T cells have a high turnover rate, and CD8(+) memory T cells proliferate upon viral infection, in the presence of IFN-alphabeta and/or IL-15. In this study, we extend these findings by showing that activated NKT cells and superantigen-activated T cells induce extensive bystander proliferation of both CD8(+) and CD4(+) memory T cells. Moreover, proliferation of memory T cells can be induced by an IFN-alphabeta-independent, but IFN-gamma- or IL-12-dependent pathway. In these conditions of bystander activation, proliferating memory (CD44(high)) T cells do not derive from activation of naive (CD44(low)) T cells, but rather from bona fide memory CD44(high) T cells. Together, these data demonstrate that distinct pathways can induce bystander proliferation of memory T cells.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Journal of immunology (Baltimore, Md. : 1950)</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Selective bystander proliferation of memory CD4+ and CD8+ T cells upon NK T or T cell activation.</str>
    <str name="id">11035065</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>This study determined whether Heligmosomoides polygyrus induces intestinal regulatory T cells. Splenic T cells proliferate strongly when cultured with anti-CD3 and antigen-presenting cells (APC). Lamina propria T cells from mice with H. polygyrus mixed with normal splenic T cells from uninfected mice inhibited proliferation over 90%. Lamina propria T cells from mice without H. polygyrus only modestly affected T cell proliferation. The worm-induced regulatory T cell was CD8+ and required splenic T cell contact to inhibit proliferation. The regulation also was IL-10 independent, but TAP-dependent, suggesting that it requires major histocompatibility complex (MHC) class I interaction. Additional studies employed mice with transgenic T cells that did not express functional TGF-beta receptors. The lamina propria T regulator inhibited proliferation of these transgenic T cells nearly 100%, suggesting that TGF-beta signaling via the T cell was not required. CD8+ T cells were needed for worms to reverse piroxicam-induced colitis in Rag mice (T and B cell deficient) reconstituted with IL-10-/- T cells. Thus H. polygyrus induces a regulatory CD8+ lamina propria T cell that inhibits T cell proliferation and that appears to have a role in control of colitis.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">American journal of physiology. Gastrointestinal and liver physiology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Induction of CD8+ regulatory T cells in the intestine by Heligmosomoides polygyrus infection.</str>
    <str name="id">16825660</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The in vivo mechanism of regulatory T cell (T(reg) cell) function in controlling autoimmunity remains controversial. Here we have used two-photon laser-scanning microscopy to analyze lymph node priming of diabetogenic T cells and to delineate the mechanisms of T(reg) cell control of autoimmunity in vivo. Islet antigen-specific CD4(+)CD25(-) T helper cells (T(H) cells) and T(reg) cells swarmed and arrested in the presence of autoantigens. These T(H) cell activities were progressively inhibited in the presence of increasing numbers of T(reg) cells. There were no detectable stable associations between T(reg) and T(H) cells during active suppression. In contrast, T(reg) cells directly interacted with dendritic cells bearing islet antigen. Such persistent T(reg) cell-dendritic cell contacts preceded the inhibition of T(H) cell activation by dendritic cells, supporting the idea that dendritic cells are central to T(reg) cell function in vivo.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Nature immunology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Visualizing regulatory T cell control of autoimmune responses in nonobese diabetic mice.</str>
    <str name="id">16311599</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>It has been previously shown that autoreactive T cells appear during mercury-induced autoimmunity in Brown-Norway (BN) rats. In the present work, it is shown that: 1) T cells and T helper cells from HgCl2-injected BN rats are able to actively transfer autoimmunity in normal BN rats; the disease transferred is exacerbated when recipients are treated with the antisuppressor/cytotoxic T cell monoclonal antibody (OX8); 2) normal T cells preincubated with HgCl2 are also able to transfer the disease in OX8-treated but not in T cell-depleted rats; and 3) T cells from HgCl2-injected BN rats also transferred the disease in both normal and T cell depleted rats. It is concluded that: 1) autoreactive T cells, and presumably anti-Ia T cells are involved in the pathogenesis of mercury-induced autoimmunity; 2) these autoreactive T cells induce suppressor/cytotoxic T cells to proliferate in normal syngeneic recipients; the fact that this T cell subset did not proliferate in HgCl2-injected BN rats suggests that HgCl2 also affects T suppressor cells; and 3) mercury-induced autoimmunity could result from the additive effect of the emergence of autoreactive T cells and of a defect at the T suppressor level.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Journal of immunology (Baltimore, Md. : 1950)</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Autoreactive T cells in mercury-induced autoimmunity. Ability to induce the autoimmune disease.</str>
    <str name="id">3257501</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>We investigated whether epigenetic modification agents can convert naïve T cells to regulatory T cells (T(regs)) which are responsible for limiting immune responses and maintaining self-tolerance. We treated splenic CD4(+)/CD25(-) naïve T cells from BALB/c mice with the DNA-methyltransferase inhibitor 5-aza-2'-deoxycytidine (5AzaD) or the histone protein deacetylase (HDAC) inhibitor Trichostatin A (TSA), and measured the effects on the expression of FOXP3, which encodes a transcription factor (FOXP3) that regulates T(reg) development. FOXP3 expression in naïve T cells was increased by 5AzaD or TSA treatment, administered 72 hours after T-cell receptor (TCR) stimulation with anti-CD3 plus anti-CD28. The T(regs) induced by 5AzaD or TSA expressed greater amounts of the FOXP3 protein than the control and the natural T(regs). The analysis of T(reg)-associated markers also showed T(reg) phenotypes (CD25(+)/CTLA4(+)/GITR(+)/CD127(-)). Finally, the induced T(reg) population also displayed T-cell suppression. These data suggested that epigenetic modification agents can induce FOXP3 expression, promoting the conversion of naïve T cells to T(regs).</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Transplantation proceedings</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Use of epigenetic modification to induce FOXP3 expression in naïve T cells.</str>
    <str name="id">19545742</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The T-colony-forming capacity of different T lymphocyte subsets was studied in normal peripheral blood. Unfractionated lymphocytes (after 'Lymphoprep' separation) gave rise to a mean of 150 +/- 27 . 7 s.d. T colonies per 1 x 10(5) cells, while purified T lymphocytes by sheep RBC rosetting formed 110 +/- 32 . 2 colonies. Two subpopulations of T lymphocytes were further isolated according to the presence of Fc receptors for IgG (T gamma) or IgM (T mu) by ox RBC rosetting. T gamma cells were found to have a very low or absent T colony-forming capacity (23 +/- 26 . 2), while T mu cells produced normal colony numbers (106 +/- 28 . 4). Co-culture experiments showed that T gamma cells do not inhibit the T colony growth of normal T cells in our system. Our findings indicate that in human peripheral blood not all T lymphocytes are capable of forming T colonies and that this property is confined to the T mu (helper) lymphocyte subset.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Clinical and experimental immunology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Evidence that T colony formation is a property of T mu (helper) lymphocytes.</str>
    <str name="id">6970096</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>In the few years since their discovery, T helper 17 cells (T(H)17) have been shown to play an important role in host defense against infections, and in tissue inflammation during autoimmunity. T(H)17 cells produce IL-17, IL-21, IL-10, and IL-22 cytokines, and thus have broad effects on a variety of tissues. Notably, the requirement for the immunosuppressive cytokine TGF-beta along with the pro-inflammatory cytokine IL-6 for T(H)17 differentiation supports the intimate relationship between the T(H)17 subset and FOXP3(+) regulatory T cells. Here, we discuss current knowledge on effector functions and differentiation of the T(H)17 lineage. Furthermore, we now know of a physiological stimulus for T(H)17 differentiation: innate immune recognition of cells undergoing apoptosis as a direct result of infection induces unique development of this subset. As our knowledge of T(H)17 and T regulatory cells grows, we are building on a new framework for the understanding of effector T cell differentiation and the biology of CD4(+) T cell adaptive immune responses.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Cellular and molecular life sciences : CMLS</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">T helper 17 cells: discovery, function, and physiological trigger.</str>
    <str name="id">20054607</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>We previously reported that the beta gamma-subunit of transducin (T beta gamma) is composed of two components, T beta gamma-1 and T beta gamma-2 with distinctive gamma-subunits, T gamma-1 and T gamma-2, respectively. T beta gamma-2 enhances GTP binding to the alpha-subunit of transducin (T alpha) in the presence of a photobleaching intermediate of rhodopsin, while T beta gamma-1 is an inactive component with little enhancement ability (Fukada, Y., Ohguro, H., Saito, T., Yoshizawa, T., and Akino, T. (1989) J. Biol. Chem. 264: 5937-5943). To further elucidate the functional differences between T beta gamma-1 and T beta gamma-2, we examined the association of T beta gamma s with Ca(2+)-calmodulin, and the effect of Ca2+ on binding of GTP to T alpha in the presence of either T beta gamma-1 or T beta gamma-2. Ca2+ had no effect on the GTP binding activity of transducin and T beta gamma s could not associate with Ca(2+)-calmodulin, indicating that the relationship of T beta gamma with Ca(2+)-calmodulin of is different from that of the brain G protein.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Biochemistry international</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Lack of association of Ca(2+)-calmodulin with the beta gamma-subunits of the photo-receptor G protein (transducin).</str>
    <str name="id">1616497</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Macrophages are capable of destroying T cells with which they form cellular conjugates. The deletion can be prevented by the simultaneous transmission of costimulatory signals. We show here that T cells with elevated major histocompatibility complex (MHC) class I expression are resistant against macrophage-mediated cytotoxicity. T cells that express the CD45RO isotype, considered memory T cells, exhibit MHC class I antigen at higher density than naive CD45RA T cells and upregulate MHC class I expression promptly when they form cellular conjugates with macrophages. We confirm previous observations that CD45RA T cells are more susceptible to antibody- and macrophage-mediated deletion than memory CD45RO T cells. When MHC class I molecules are masked by specific monoclonal antibody or antibody Fab fragments, CD45RA T cells and CD45RO T cells exhibit equal susceptibility to macrophage cytotoxicity, demonstrating that the difference between CD45RA and CD45RO T cells in their sensitivity to macrophage cytotoxicity is determined by their MHC I expression. Separation of CD4 T cells from CD8 T cells deprives memory CD4 T cells of their resistance against macrophage cytotoxicity, suggesting that memory T cells' resistance against destruction by macrophages is controlled by regulatory T cells.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Immunology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Elevated major histocompatibility complex class I expression protects T cells from antibody- and macrophage-mediated deletion.</str>
    <str name="id">9824508</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>It is well established that the thymus is an essential organ for the support of T-cell differentiation. However, some T cells, termed extrathymic T cells, have been found to differentiate without such support by the thymus. The major sites of these T cells are the intestine and liver. Subsequent studies have revealed that extrathymic T cells are also present in the uterus and exocrine glands (e.g., the salivary gland). Depending on the sites, extrathymic T cells have some distinct properties as well as some common properties. For example, all extrathymic T cells have a TCR-CD3 complex similar to thymus-derived T cells. Extrathymic T cells comprise both alpha beta T cells and gamma delta T cells. Although extrathymic T cells are very few in number at any extrathymic sites in youth, they increase in number as a function of age. This phenomenon seems to occur in parallel with thymic involution. Even in youth, extrathymic T cells are activated in number and function by stress, in autoimmune diseases, and during pregnancy. Acute thymic atrophy always accompanies this activation. Therefore, reciprocal regulation between extrathymic T cells and thymus-derived T cells might be present. We hypothesize that extrathymic T cells are intimately associated with innate immunity and that the mechanisms underlying autoimmune diseases and intracellular infection (e.g., malaria) cannot be properly understood without introducing the concept of extrathymic T cells.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">International immunopharmacology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Extrathymic pathways of T-cell differentiation and immunomodulation.</str>
    <str name="id">11460307</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>CD4(+)CD25(+) regulatory T cells inhibit organ-specific autoimmune diseases induced by CD4(+)CD25(-) T cells and are potent suppressors of CD4(+)CD25(-) T cell activation in vitro. We demonstrate that CD4(+)CD25(+) T cells also suppress both proliferation and IFN-gamma production by CD8(+) T cells induced either by polyclonal or Ag-specific stimuli. CD4(+)CD25(+) T cells inhibit the activation of CD8(+) responders by inhibiting both IL-2 production and up-regulation of IL-2Ralpha-chain (CD25) expression. Suppression is mediated via a T-T interaction as activated CD4(+)CD25(+) T cells suppress the responses of TCR-transgenic CD8(+) T cells stimulated with soluble peptide-MHC class I tetramers in the complete absence of APC. These results broaden the immunoregulatory role played by CD4(+)CD25(+) T cells in the prevention of autoimmune diseases, but also raise the possibility that they may hinder the induction of effector CD8(+) T cells to tumor or foreign Ags.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Journal of immunology (Baltimore, Md. : 1950)</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Cutting edge: control of CD8+ T cell activation by CD4+CD25+ immunoregulatory cells.</str>
    <str name="id">11466326</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The differentiation of activated CD4(+) T cells into the T helper type 1 (T(H)1) or T(H)2 fate is regulated by cytokines and the transcription factors T-bet and GATA-3. Whereas interleukin 12 (IL-12) produced by antigen-presenting cells initiates the T(H)1 fate, signals that initiate the T(H)2 fate are not completely characterized. Here we show that early GATA-3 expression, required for T(H)2 differentiation, was induced by T cell factor 1 (TCF-1) and its cofactor beta-catenin, mainly from the proximal Gata3 promoter upstream of exon 1b. This activity was induced after T cell antigen receptor (TCR) stimulation and was independent of IL-4 receptor signaling through the transcription factor STAT6. Furthermore, TCF-1 blocked T(H)1 fate by negatively regulating interferon-gamma (IFN-gamma) expression independently of beta-catenin. Thus, TCF-1 initiates T(H)2 differentiation of activated CD4(+) T cells by promoting GATA-3 expression and suppressing IFN-gamma expression.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Nature immunology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">T cell factor 1 initiates the T helper type 2 fate by inducing the transcription factor GATA-3 and repressing interferon-gamma.</str>
    <str name="id">19648923</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>T cell responses are highly specific and T cell receptors (TCRs) can recognise subtle differences in major histocompatibility complex (MHC)-peptide complexes. While nominal peptide antigens usually act as full agonists that trigger the whole spectrum of T cell responses, some peptides exhibiting mutations at the TCR-MHC/peptide contact site stimulate only a fraction of T cell responses (partial agonists) or may even inhibit T cell activation by full agonists (antagonist). The present study analyses mathematically the role of TCR-dimerization for T cell antagonism and T cell specificity in general. It demonstrates that T cell antagonists can effectively inhibit TCR-dimerization and that this mechanism can sufficiently explain all aspects of T cell antagonism. The kinetic model of T cell activation proposes that increasing the time required for effective TCR-signaling is the most effective mechanism to increase the discriminatory capacity of TCRs. Our results indicate that TCR-oligomerization is an alternative and efficient mechanism to ensure T cell specificity.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Molecular immunology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The role of T cell receptor dimerization for T cell antagonism and T cell specificity.</str>
    <str name="id">9747887</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Molt-3 and Molt-4 are T-cell lines originally derived in 1971 from a patient with T-cell acute lymphoblastic leukemia. An unusual T-cell antigen receptor gamma-chain gene (T-gamma) rearrangement detected by Southern blot analysis of Molt-4 prompted an in-depth study of the immunophenotype and karyotype of both cell lines. Molt-3 and Molt-4 had immunophenotypic characteristics of thymocytes with expression of CD1 and CD5. Both cell lines had a hypertetraploid karyotype with two rearranged no. 7 chromosomes: 2der(7)t(7;7)(p15;q11). The presence of a break in chromosome band 7p15 suggested the involvement of T gamma. We cloned the rearranged BamHI fragments spanning the known T-gamma constant and joining regions. Comparison with germline clones of T gamma did not suggest any of the clones included a breakpoint region. Thus the 7p15 chromosomal abnormality in Molt-3 and Molt-4 is not associated with the currently described joining and constant regions of T gamma.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Blood</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Immunophenotypic and cytogenetic analysis of Molt-3 and Molt-4: human T-lymphoid cell lines with rearrangement of chromosome 7.</str>
    <str name="id">2846092</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Chromosomes of the four species of Tapirus were 2n = 52 in T. indicus, 2n = 76 in T. pinchaque, 2n = 80 in T. bairdii, and 2n = 80 in T. terrestris. The number of autosomal arms was 80-94. G-banded karyotypes indicated that a heterochromatic addition/deletion distinguished chromosomes 2 and 3 of T. bairdii and T. pinchaque, respectively. There were at least 13 conserved autosomes between the karyotypes of T. bairdii and T. terrestris, and at least 15 were conserved between T. bairdii and T. pinchaque. In G- and C-banded preparations, the X chromosomes of T. bairdii, T. indicus, and T. terrestris were identical, whereas the X chromosome of T. pinchaque differed from the X of the other species by a heterochromatic addition/deletion. The Y chromosome was a medium-sized to small acrocentric in T. bairdii, T. indicus, and T. pinchaque, but it was not positively identified in T. terrestris. There appeared to be fewer homologies between T. indicus and the three species occurring in Central and South America. Future cytogenetic studies of tapirs from the entire range of each of the four species might provide additional insight into their evolutionary biology and aid wildlife conservation efforts aimed at these threatened mammals.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Cytogenetics and cell genetics</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Comparative cytogenetics of tapirs, genus tapirus (Perissodactyla, tapiridae).</str>
    <str name="id">10894950</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Cutaneous T-cell lymphomas with panniculitis-like histologic features have different clinical courses depending on whether they are composed of alphabeta T cells or gammadelta T cells, necessitating their distinction for proper prognostication. However, unlike alphabeta T cells, gammadelta T cells cannot be reliably detected in formalin-fixed, paraffin-embedded sections. We demonstrated that a commercially available antibody can detect gammadelta T cells and examined 2 cases of flow cytometry-proven gammadelta T-cell lymphomas and 15 control cases of nonneoplastic panniculitis. In both lymphomas, the atypical lymphocytes were gammadelta T cells, whereas the reactive lymphocytes were alphabeta T cells. In contrast, nonneoplastic panniculitis had predominantly alphabeta T cells with many fewer and individually scattered gammadelta T cells. The detection of gammadelta T cells in paraffin sections provides a powerful new tool to characterize T cells in lymphomas and inflammation.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">American journal of clinical pathology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Percentage of {gamma}{delta} T cells in panniculitis by paraffin immunohistochemical analysis.</str>
    <str name="id">19461088</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>T cell chemotaxis to sphingosine 1-phosphate (S1P) and the chemokines CCL21 and CCL5 was studied in ten adults with T lymphocytopenia, other immunological abnormalities (nine of ten), and frequent bacterial infections (seven of ten). Mean chemotactic responses to S1P of CD4 T cells from CD4 T lymphocytopenic patients and of CD8 T cells from CD8 T lymphocytopenic patients were significantly lower than those of healthy matched controls. Chemotaxis to CCL21 was lower than that of controls for CD4 T cells of three CD4 T lymphocytopenic patients and for CD8 T cells of three CD8 T lymphocytopenic patients, but none of the T cells of patients had diminished chemotaxis to CCL5. Defective T cell chemotactic responses to S1P and some chemokines may lead to subset-selective abnormal T cell trafficking and chronic T cell lymphocytopenia.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Journal of clinical immunology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Defective T cell chemotaxis to sphingosine 1-phosphate and chemokine CCL21 in idiopathic T lymphocytopenia.</str>
    <str name="id">21671128</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Trisopterus is demonstrated to be monophyletic, including four distinct species: T. capelanus, T. esmarkii, T. luscus and T. minutus. The capelan T. capelanus is resurrected from the synonymy of poor cod T. minutus, and is shown to be morphologically more similar to T. luscus, to which species it is also more closely related, indicated by a phylogenetic analysis presented here. A lectotype is designated for T. luscus. Trisopterus fasciatus, the type species of Trisopterus, is a junior synonym of T. luscus, and the lectotype of T. luscus is designated as the neotype of T. fasciatus. The lectotype of T. luscus is also designated as the neotype of Gadus barbatus. Gadus barbatus has priority over T. luscus but the name is suppressed by prevailing usage of T. luscus. A neotype is designated also for T. minutus. A phylogenetic analysis using mitochondrial cytochrome b, and a fragment of the nuclear rhodopsin gene, shows that T. capelanus and T. luscus are sister species, and in turn sister to a clade formed by T. minutus and T. esmarkii.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Journal of fish biology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Taxonomic review of the genus Trisopterus(Teleostei: Gadidae) with recognition of the capelan Trisopterus capelanus as a valid species.</str>
    <str name="id">22026604</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>CD8(+)CD62L(+) T cells have been shown to play pivotal roles in anti-viral immunity, chronic myeloid leukemia and renal cell carcinoma. Recently, CD8(+)CD62L(+) T cells from naïve mice (nCD8(+)CD62L(+) T cells) have shown superior anti-tumor properties in melanoma-bearing mice. Considering that antigen-specific memory T cells have shown to possess more potent immunity than non-specific memory T cells, we hypothesized that CD8(+)CD62L(+) T cells from tumor-bearing individuals (mCD8(+)CD62L(+) T cells) might have superior anti-tumor effect than nCD8(+)CD62L(+) T cells. Therefore, we investigated phenotypes, functions and the in vivo distribution of mCD8(+)CD62L(+) T cells in tumor-bearing mice. We found that, while keeping the features of central memory T cells, the frequency of mCD8(+)CD62L(+) T cell in the spleen of tumor-bearing mice was significantly higher than that the one of nCD8(+)CD62L(+) T cell in naive mice. Moreover, we demonstrated that mCD8(+)CD62L(+) T cells had higher proliferation rate and IFN-γ production than nCD8(+)CD62L(+) T cells, in vitro. We performed adoptive transfer of mCD8(+)CD62L(+) T cells into melanoma-bearing mice and tracked them in spleen, lymph nodes and in melanoma tissues. Our results show that mCD8(+)CD62L(+) T cells had stronger in vivo anti-tumoral activity than nCD8(+)CD62L(+) T cells. This study highlights the therapeutic potential of mCD8(+)CD62L(+) T cells in the immunotherapy of melanoma and possibly other tumors. </str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Immunological investigations</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Marked anti-tumor effects of CD8(+)CD62L(+) T cells from melanoma-bearing mice.</str>
    <str name="id">25122543</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>T cells presenting antigens in the context of MHC class II can induce anergy. In rat CD4+ T cell clones we have shown that depending on the depth of anergy other T cell responses can be inhibited in the presence of professional antigen presenting cells (APCs). This inhibition is cell-contact dependent, and APCs recovered from co-cultures with suppressive anergic T cells are modulated in their capacity to activate T cells. No changes in cell surface expression of MHC molecules, B7-1/B7-2, and OX40L were detected. Remarkably cell clusters formed by anergic T cells appeared to be more tight than clusters of activated T cells, and after fluorescent cell surface labelling of T cells, transfer of label was more profound in co-cultures of anergic T cells and APCs compared to activated T cells and APCs. Previously, it has been shown that activated T cells can absorb molecules from APCs in a unidirectional process. We now have evidence that also APCs can absorb cell surface molecules from T cells during APC-T cell co-cultures. We speculate that the quantity and quality of molecule reshuffling during cross-talk between T cells and APCs play a role in the regulation of the T cell response.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Novartis Foundation symposium</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Modulation of T cell responses after cross-talk between antigen presenting cells and T cells: a give-and-take relationship.</str>
    <str name="id">14609221</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The rapid troponin T assay CARDIAC T Quantitative was recalibrated using Elecsys Troponin T 3rd Generation as a new reference method. This paper presents the method comparisons at six centres using the new reference method. Method comparison between CARDIAC T Quantitative versus Elecsys Troponin T 3rd Generation were performed using 319 samples from patients with acute coronary syndromes. The quality of the CARDIAC T Quantitative was controlled by a daily single determination of CARDIAC Control Troponin T, and for the Elecsys Troponin T 3rd Generation, the Elecsys controls were included in each run. The results for the control materials for the CARDIAC T Quantitative were between 93% and 107% of the target values. The CV ranged from 7% to 16%. From the regression analysis, according to Bablok and Passing (y=1.07x) and the Bland and Altman plot, the bias between CARDIAC T Quantitative and Elecsys Troponin T 3rd Generation is from +6% to +7%. The correlation coefficient is 0.93, and a 3x3 comparison of the clinical efficiency yielded 92% clinical concordance between CARDIAC T Quantitative and Elecsys Troponin T 3rd Generation. In conclusion, CARDIAC T Quantitative was in good agreement with the reference and calibration method Elecsys Troponin T 3rd Generation.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Clinica chimica acta; international journal of clinical chemistry</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Recalibration of the point-of-care test for CARDIAC T Quantitative with Elecsys Troponin T 3rd generation.</str>
    <str name="id">11369358</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The objective of this paper is to correct an error in analyses of quasielastic scattering spectra. The error invokes a valid calculation under conditions in which its primary assumptions are incorrect, which results in misleading interpretations of spectra. Quasielastic scattering from dilute probes yields the incoherent structure factor g((1s))(q, t) = &lt;exp (iqΔx(t))&gt;, with q being the magnitude of the scattering vector q and Δx(t) being the probe displacement parallel to q during a time interval t. The error is a claim that g((1s))(q, t) ~ exp (-q(2)&lt;(Δx(t))(2)&gt;∕2) for probes in an arbitrary solution, leading to the incorrect belief that &lt;(Δx(t))(2)&gt; of probes in complex fluids can be inferred from quasielastic scattering. The actual theoretical result refers only to monodisperse probes in simple Newtonian liquids. In general, g((1s))(q, t) is determined by all even moments &lt;(Δx(t))(2n)&gt;, n = 1, 2, 3, ... of the displacement distribution function P(Δx, t). Correspondingly, &lt;(Δx(t))(2)&gt; cannot in general be inferred from g((1s)) (q, t). The theoretical model that ties g((1s))(q, t) to &lt;(Δx(t))(2)&gt; also quantitatively determines exactly how &lt;(Δx(t))(2)&gt;∕2) must behave, namely, &lt;(Δx(t))(2)&gt; must increase linearly with t. If the spectrum is not a single exponential in time, g((1s))(q, t) does not determine &lt;(Δx(t))(2)&gt;.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">The Journal of chemical physics</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Interpretation of quasielastic scattering spectra of probe species in complex fluids.</str>
    <str name="id">23883052</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Rearrangement of the T gamma gene, which encodes one chain of the second T-cell receptor, is an early event in the development of T lymphocytes. In contrast to the T-cell receptor beta chain gene, the T gamma gene contains a very limited V region gene repertoire, accounting for only 8 to 10 rearranging V gamma genes. As a consequence of the limited number of V gamma genes, only seven or eight nongermline restriction fragments are displayed, even by highly polyclonal T cells. Here, we demonstrate that T gamma gene analysis produces a picture of pseudoclonality among polyclonal T lymphocytes accompanying B-cell lymphoma, T-cell lymphoma, and Hodgkin's disease. As little as 10% contamination by polyclonal T lymphocytes is sufficient to detect rearrangements in both clinical samples and in a controlled sensitivity assay. Conversely, polyclonal T cells were found to obscure T-cell clones when polyclonal T cells represented as little as 30% of total cells. We conclude that, due to the unusual genomic structure of the T gamma gene, rearrangement analysis of the T gamma gene carries a significant limitation as a marker of clonality and lineage.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Hematologic pathology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Diagnostic interpretation of T gamma gene rearrangement: effect of polyclonal T cells.</str>
    <str name="id">2853152</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To describe recent advances in the understanding of virus-specific CD4 T cell dysfunction in chronic viral infections, with an emphasis on HIV disease. We highlight features that are distinctive for CD4 T cells, as opposed to their CD8 T cell counterparts.</str>
      <str>CD4 T cell activation and differentiation are tightly controlled. Regulation of these processes depends on the context of initial encounter of the naïve CD4 T cell with the cognate antigen and on ongoing external cues to the antigen-experienced CD4 T cell, in particular the inflammatory environment, which is prominent in HIV infection. Virus-specific CD4 T cell dysfunction results from a combination of an exhaustion program and skewing in T helper lineage differentiation which impact function. The CD4 and CD8 T cell exhaustion programs present similarities and distinct features. The sets of inhibitory coreceptors expression differ, although programmed-death 1 (PD-1) and T cell immunoglobulin mucin-3 (Tim-3) are upregulated on both HIV-specific CD4 and CD8 T cells, cytotoxic T-lymphocyte antigen 4 (CTLA-4) is largely specific to CD4 T cells, whereas 2B4 and CD160 are biased toward CD8 T cells.</str>
      <str>Understanding the molecular basis of HIV-specific CD4 T cell exhaustion and identifying key differences with CD8 T cell impairment will be critical to design effective therapeutic and preventive immunotherapies against HIV.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Current opinion in HIV and AIDS</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Distinctive features of CD4+ T cell dysfunction in chronic viral infections.</str>
    <str name="id">25023623</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Rearrangements of the T cell gamma (T gamma) gene were studied in primary neoplastic cells from 75 patients with leukemia or lymphoma. T gamma gene rearrangements were observed in 19 of 21 T cell neoplasms; 14 of 21 immature B cell leukemias, including 4 out of 5 patients with rearrangements of both immunoglobulin heavy-chain (JH) and T cell receptor beta chain (T beta) genes; none out of 16 nonlymphoid leukemias. Thus, T gamma gene rearrangement is frequently found in immature B cells and is not always found in T cells showing T beta gene rearrangement, but it is not detected in nonlymphoid cells. Furthermore, T gamma gene rearrangement in cells with the germline configuration of the JH and T beta genes was observed. These results indicate that the detection of T gamma gene rearrangement does not allow a clear assignment to a particular lineage. However, an analysis of T gamma gene rearrangement provides a further potential tool to establish the lymphoid cellular origin and clonality of hematologic neoplasms and identify the normal stages of lymphocyte differentiation.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Blood</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">T cell gamma gene rearrangements in hematologic neoplasms.</str>
    <str name="id">2949786</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>A series of 11 mouse monoclonal antibodies reactive with human T lymphoid cells at different stages of differentiation was used for immunological classification of leukaemic cells of 16 patients with T cell lymphoproliferative disorders by using a fluorescence assay. The majority of T-ALL cells had an immature or early thymic phenotype and T lymphoblastic lymphoma had phenotypes corresponding to different levels of more mature stages of T cell differentiation, Two cases of T-CLL and one adult patient with mycosis fungoides had mature T cell phenotypes being T-3+, T-4-, T-8+, cytotoxic/suppressor cell types and one case of T-CLL had T-3+, T-4+, T-8-, "helper/inducer" cell type, too. These results suggested that surface marker analysis in T cell lymphoproliferative disorders may be used as a highly reproducible immunological classification system that will provide additional information about phenotypes of leukaemic cells in connection with morphological analysis and clinical diagnosis.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Folia haematologica (Leipzig, Germany : 1928)</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Immunologic characterization of T-lymphoproliferative disorders by monoclonal antibodies.</str>
    <str name="id">2416641</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Human T cell subpopulations have been defined on the basis of differential expression of either Fc receptors or specific cell-surface antigens. In this study, we utilized a series of monoclonal antibodies reactive with T cells, monocytes, and Ia antigens to characterize isolated subpopulations of T cells bearing receptors for the Fc portion of IgG (T gamma) and subpopulations of T cells bearing receptors for the Fc portion of IgM T mu. The results showed that the T mu population contained both inducer (OKT4+) and cytotoxic/suppressor (OKT5+) populations and was similar to the unfractionated T cell population, whereas the T gamma subset contained few T lymphocytes (OKT3+) and was not enriched for either T cell subset defined by these monoclonal antibodies. Rather, the T gamma population was comprised largely of Ia- cells possessing a monocyte antigen (OKM1+). In reciprocal studies, it was found that both isolated OKT4+ and OKT5+ T cell subsets contained few T gamma cells, whereas both subsets were mainly comprised of T mu cells. We conclude that there is little correlation between T cell subsets defined by these monoclonal antibodies and those defined by Fc receptors.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">The Journal of experimental medicine</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Human T lymphocyte subpopulations defined by Fc receptors and monoclonal antibodies. A comparison.</str>
    <str name="id">6445397</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>T cell receptor (TCR)-derived peptides have been used to induce regulatory T cells which recognize T cells of specific elements and downregulate the autoimmune response. Consistent with these observations, priming of peptides corresponding to V beta 8 complementarity-determining region 2 (CDR2) was found to specifically suppress the proliferation of V beta 8+ T cells in the draining lymph nodes. Similarly, the generation of V beta 8-dominant T cell responses was prevented locally by vaccination with V beta 8 CDR2 peptides. There was a good correlation between the downregulation of V beta 8+ T cells and the inhibition of the corresponding T cell responses in different lymphoid tissues. No systemic inhibition could be detected even after an interval which would allow the redistribution of the "regulatory T cells." T cells specific for V beta 8 CDR2 peptides was generated following peptide immunization. However, the appearance of these TCR peptide-specific T cells was independent of the downregulation of V beta 8+ T cells. The transient and localized inhibitory effects of TCR-derived peptides indicate that these peptides have very limited use in regulating specific T cell response.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Cellular immunology</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Limited regulatory effect of T cell receptor-derived peptides.</str>
    <str name="id">7697733</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Studies were performed to determine whether CTL against Toxoplasma gondii-infected cells could be induced in a murine model of T. gondii infection in which CD8+ T lymphocytes have been shown to play a major role in resistance against this parasite. In 51Cr release assays, nylon wool nonadherent spleen cells from BALB/c (H-2d) mice immunized with the temperature-sensitive (ts-4) mutant strain of T. gondii were cytotoxic for T. gondii-infected P815 (H-2d) mastocytoma cells but not for uninfected cells. This cytotoxic activity was remarkably increased after in vitro stimulation with T. gondii-infected syngeneic spleen cells. The effector cells were shown to be CD8+ T lymphocytes, because the cytotoxicity was significantly inhibited by depletion of CD8+ T lymphocytes but not by depletion of CD4+ T lymphocytes. This cytotoxic activity was genetically restricted. Spleen cells from T. gondii-immune BALB/c mice were not cytotoxic for T. gondii-infected EL4 (H-2b) thymoma cells, whereas spleen cells from T. gondii-immune C57B1/6 (H-2b) mice were cytotoxic for T. gondii-infected EL4 cells but not for T. gondii-infected P815 cells. The cytolytic activity of CD8+ T lymphocytes against T. gondii-infected cells might be a mechanism whereby these cells confer resistance against T. gondii.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_journal_title">Journal of immunology (Baltimore, Md. : 1950)</str>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Murine CD8+ cytotoxic T lymphocytes lyse Toxoplasma gondii-infected cells.</str>
    <str name="id">1940378</str></doc>
</result>
</response>
