<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<response>

<lst name="responseHeader">
  <int name="status">0</int>
  <int name="QTime">0</int>
  <lst name="params">
    <str name="q">
11897834
1516477
19801981
8963900
21220197
26015544
23965741
23913553
22833560
21632880
23456319
21171078
24253444
22611028
24990759
24554551
24815864
22538805
18466071
8733136</str>
    <str name="indent">true</str>
    <str name="fl">id, medline_abstract_text, medline_article_title</str>
    <str name="rows">100</str>
    <str name="wt">xml</str>
  </lst>
</lst>
<result name="response" numFound="20" start="0">
  <doc>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Human T and risk for neural tube defects.</str>
    <str name="id">11897834</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The murine developmental mutation T identifies a gene required in mesoderm formation. T/T mutant embryos develop normally to the primitive streak stage; during early organogenesis they show insufficient mesoderm and absence of the notochord. The mutants die at around 10 days of gestation because of the lack of the allantois. We have localized the T mutation relative to DNA markers and used a combination of genetic and molecular techniques to clone the T gene. Expression of the T gene is restricted to nascent mesoderm and to the notochord, the tissues most strongly affected by the mutation. Recent results suggest that the T gene encodes a nuclear factor involved in establishing notochord cell identity and differentiation, and is directly or indirectly involved in the organization of axial development.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Action of the Brachyury gene in mouse embryogenesis.</str>
    <str name="id">1516477</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Using high-resolution array-CGH, we identified unique duplications of a region on 6q27 in four multiplex families with at least three cases of chordoma, a cancer of presumed notochordal origin. The duplicated region contains only the T (brachyury) gene, which is important in notochord development and is expressed in most sporadic chordomas. Our findings highlight the value of screening for complex genomic rearrangements in searches for cancer-susceptibility genes.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">T (brachyury) gene duplication confers major susceptibility to familial chordoma.</str>
    <str name="id">19801981</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>We have cloned the human gene encoding the transcription factor T. T protein is vital for the formation of posterior mesoderm and axial development in all vertebrates. Brachyury mutant mice, which lack T protein, die in utero with abnormal notochord, posterior somites, and allantois. We have identified human T genomic clones and derived the mRNA sequence and gene structure. There is 91% amino acid identity between human and mouse T proteins overall and complete identity across 77 amino acids of the T-box motif within the DNA-binding domain. Human T expression is very similar to that found for T in other vertebrate species and is confined to cells derived from the notochord. The human T gene maps to chromosome 6q27 and is only the second human member of the T-box gene family to be described.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The human homolog T of the mouse T(Brachyury) gene; gene structure, cDNA sequence, and assignment to chromosome 6q27.</str>
    <str name="id">8963900</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Although survival rates of colon cancer patients diagnosed at an early stage (T1-2N0M0; Dukes A) vary considerably according to the studies cited, several studies indicate development of distant metastases already occurring in a considerable percentage of these patients leading to the death of the patients. This particular high risk group cannot be identified properly as no marker exists to identify these patients. As the Wnt/Win pathway plays a crucial role in metastasis formation in colorectal carcinoma, we analysed whether the transcription factor brachyury critically involved in this pathway may predict metastasis formation in these patients. The expression of brachyury-homologous (T) was immunohistochemically analysed in 748 patients and the data were correlated with classical and newer prognostic markers in colorectal cancer. Early stages colorectal cancer patients (T1-2N0M0, Dukes A) showed a significantly decreased survival when brachyury was expressed in the tumour tissue while no correlation was observed in later tumour stages. Hence a subset of colorectal cancers exists in which the ability to metastasise is already present at early stages of tumour growth and this high risk group can now be detected by immunohistochemistry.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Brachyury expression predicts poor prognosis at early stages of colorectal cancer.</str>
    <str name="id">21220197</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The transcription factor brachyury (T, BRA) is one of the first markers of gastrulation and lineage specification in vertebrates. Despite its wide use and importance in stem cell and developmental biology, its functional genomic targets in human cells are largely unknown. Here, we use differentiating human embryonic stem cells to study the role of BRA in activin A-induced endoderm and BMP4-induced mesoderm progenitors. We show that BRA has distinct genome-wide binding landscapes in these two cell populations, and that BRA interacts and collaborates with SMAD1 or SMAD2/3 signalling to regulate the expression of its target genes in a cell-specific manner. Importantly, by manipulating the levels of BRA in cells exposed to different signalling environments, we demonstrate that BRA is essential for mesoderm but not for endoderm formation. Together, our data illuminate the function of BRA in the context of human embryonic development and show that the regulatory role of BRA is context dependent. Our study reinforces the importance of analysing the functions of a transcription factor in different cellular and signalling environments. </str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Brachyury and SMAD signalling collaboratively orchestrate distinct mesoderm and endoderm gene regulatory networks in differentiating human embryonic stem cells.</str>
    <str name="id">26015544</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Chordomas are invasive tumors that develop from notochordal remnants and frequently occur in the skull base. The T gene and its product (brachyury) have recently been suggested to play an important role in chordoma progression. To date, few studies have investigated the relationship between the molecular/genetic characteristics of chordoma and patient prognosis. We analyzed 37 skull base chordomas for chromosomal copy number aberrations using comparative genomic hybridization, brachyury expression by immunohistochemistry, and T gene copy number by fluorescence in situ hybridization. The results of these molecular analyses and clinical parameters were compared with the patients' clinical courses. Univariate analyses using the log-rank test demonstrated that losses on chromosome 1p and gains on 1q and 2p were negatively correlated with progression-free survival, as were factors such as female sex, partial tumor removal, lack of postoperative irradiation, and high MIB-1 index. Expression of brachyury and copy number gain of the T gene were also significantly associated with shorter progression-free survival. Multivariate analysis using the Cox hazards model showed that lack of irradiation, gain on chromosome 2p, and expression of brachyury were independently associated with a poor prognosis. Our results suggest that brachyury-negative chordomas arebiologically distinct from brachyury-positive chordomas and that T/brachyury might be an appropriate molecular therapeutic target for chordoma. </str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Molecular and clinical risk factors for recurrence of skull base chordomas: gain on chromosome 2p, expression of brachyury, and lack of irradiation negatively correlate with patient prognosis.</str>
    <str name="id">23965741</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Based on studies in animals and humans, PAX3 and T (brachyury) are candidate genes for spina bifida. However, neither gene has been definitively identified as a risk factor for this condition.</str>
      <str>Sanger sequencing was used to identify variants in all PAX3 and T exons and promoter regions in 114 spina bifida cases. For known variants, allele frequencies in cases were compared with those from public databases using unadjusted odds ratios. Novel variants were genotyped in parents and assessed for predicted functional impact.</str>
      <str>We identified common variants in PAX3 (n = 2) and T (n = 3) for which the allele frequencies in cases were significantly different from those reported in at least one public database. We also identified novel variants in both PAX3 (n = 11) and T (n = 1) in spina bifida cases. Several of the novel PAX3 variants are predicted to be highly conserved and/or impact gene function or expression.</str>
      <str>These studies provide some evidence that common variants of PAX3 and T are associated with spina bifida. Rare and novel variants in these genes were also identified in affected individuals. However, additional studies will be required to determine whether these variants influence the risk of spina bifida.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Exon sequencing of PAX3 and T (brachyury) in cases with spina bifida.</str>
    <str name="id">23913553</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Cellular differentiation and lineage commitment are considered to be robust and irreversible processes during development. Recent work has shown that mouse and human fibroblasts can be reprogrammed to a pluripotent state with a combination of four transcription factors. We hypothesized that combinatorial expression of chondrocyte-specific transcription factors could directly convert human placental cells into chondrocytes. Starting from a pool of candidate genes, we identified a combination of only five genes (5F pool)-BCL6, T (also called BRACHYURY), c-MYC, MITF, and BAF60C (also called SMARCD3)-that rapidly and efficiently convert postnatal human chorion and decidual cells into chondrocytes. The cells generated expressed multiple cartilage-specific genes, such as Collagen type II α1, LINK PROTEIN-1, and AGGRECAN, and exhibited characteristics of cartilage both in vivo and in vitro. Expression of the endogenous genes for T and MITF was initiated, implying that the cell conversion is due to not only the forced expression of the transgenes, but also to cellular reprogramming by the transgenes. This direct conversion system from noncartilage tissue to cartilaginous tissue is a substantial advance toward understanding cartilage development, cell-based therapy, and oncogenesis of chondrocytes.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Placenta to cartilage: direct conversion of human placenta to chondrocytes with transformation by defined factors.</str>
    <str name="id">22833560</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Our recent work demonstrated that common cardiovascular progenitor cells are characterized and induced by the expression of the transcription factor mesoderm posterior1 (MesP1) in vertebrate embryos and murine embryonic stem cells. As the proliferative potential of stem cell-derived cardiomyocytes is limited, it is crucial to understand how MesP1 expression is mediated in order to achieve reasonable and reliable yields for novel stem cell-based therapeutic options. As potential upstream regulators of MesP1, we therefore analysed Eomes and Brachyury(T), which had been controversially discussed as being crucial for cardiovasculogenic lineage formation.</str>
      <str>Wild-type and transgenic murine embryonic stem cell lines, mRNA analyses, embryoid body formation, and cell sorting revealed that the MesP1 positive population emerges from the Brachyury(T) positive fraction. In situ hybridizations using wild-type mouse embryos confirmed that Brachyury(T) colocalises with MesP1 in vivo. Likewise, shRNA-based loss of Brachyury(T) causes a dramatic decrease in MesP1 expression accompanied by reduced cardiac markers in differentiating embryonic stem cells, which is reflected in vivo via in situ hybridizations using Brachyury(T) knock-out embryos where MesP1 mRNA is greatly abolished. We finally defined a 3.4 kb proximal MesP1-promoter fragment which is directly bound and activated by Brachyury(T) via a T responsive element as shown via bandshift, chromatin immuneprecipitation, and reporter assays.</str>
      <str>Our work contributes to the understanding of the earliest cardiovasculogenic events and may become an important prerequisite for cell therapy, tissue engineering, and pharmacological testing in the culture dish using pluripotent stem cell-derived as well as directly reprogrammed cardiovascular cell types.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Induction of MesP1 by Brachyury(T) generates the common multipotent cardiovascular stem cell.</str>
    <str name="id">21632880</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The clinical significance of Brachyury expression and its relationship to epithelial-mesenchymal transition in primary lung carcinoma is unclear.</str>
      <str>Expression of Brachyury mRNA was investigated in 104 surgically resected primary lung carcinoma tissues. Immunohistochemical analysis of Brachyury transcription factor, Slug, E-cadherin, IL-8, N-cadherin, and Ki67 was performed in 67 of 104 cases, and their expression was correlated to prognoses and clinicopathological factors.</str>
      <str>Brachyury mRNA expression in primary lung carcinoma tissues was a significant predictor of poor prognosis for 5-year disease-free survival and overall survival rates and was significantly correlated to vascular invasion, lymphatic permeation, histological grade, pathologic T stage, and pathologic N stage (P &lt; 0.05). Brachyury mRNA expression was significantly inversely correlated to E-cadherin expression (P = 0.0252) and positively correlated to IL-8 protein (P = 0.0241) and to Slug protein (P = 0.0243) in adenocarcinoma tissues.</str>
      <str>A positive association between Brachyury and Slug and IL-8, and a negative association with E-cadherin may lead to invasiveness and metastasis in primary lung carcinoma. Brachyury mRNA expression is a significant predictor of poor prognosis in primary lung carcinoma.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Expression of Brachyury gene is a significant prognostic factor for primary lung carcinoma.</str>
    <str name="id">23456319</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>A variety of analyses, including fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH), quantitative PCR (qPCR) and array CGH (aCGH), have been performed on a series of chordomas from 181 patients. Twelve of 181 (7%) tumours displayed amplification of the T locus and an additional two cases showed focal amplification; 70/181 (39%) tumours were polysomic for chromosome 6, and 8/181 (4.5%) primary tumours showed a minor allelic gain of T as assessed by FISH. No germline alteration of the T locus was identified in non-neoplastic tissue from 40 patients. Copy number gain of T was seen in a similar percentage of sacrococcygeal, mobile spine and base of skull tumours. Knockdown of T in the cell line, U-CH1, which showed polysomy of chromosome 6 involving 6q27, resulted in a marked decrease in cell proliferation and morphological features consistent with a senescence-like phenotype. The U-CH1 cell line was validated as representing chordoma by the generation of xenografts, which showed typical chordoma morphology and immunohistochemistry in the NOD/SCID/interleukin 2 receptor [IL2r]gammanull mouse model. In conclusion, chromosomal aberrations resulting in gain of the T locus are common in sporadic chordomas and expression of this gene is critical for proliferation of chordoma cells in vitro.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Role of the transcription factor T (brachyury) in the pathogenesis of sporadic chordoma: a genetic and functional-based study.</str>
    <str name="id">21171078</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The T gene (brachyury gene) is the founding member of the T-box family of transcription factors and is vital for the formation and differentiation of the mesoderm and the axial development of all vertebrates.</str>
      <str>We report here on four patients from three consanguineous families exhibiting sacral agenesis, a persistent notochordal canal and abnormal ossification of the vertebral bodies, and the identification and characterisation of their underlying genetic defect. Given the consanguineous nature and the similarity of the phenotypes between the three families, we performed homozygosity mapping and identified a common 4.1 Mb homozygous region on chromosome 6q27, containing T, brachyury homologue (mouse) or T. Sequencing of T in the affected individuals led to the identification of a homozygous missense mutation, p.H171R, in the highly conserved T-box. The homozygous mutation results in diminished DNA binding, increased cell growth, and interferes with the normal expression of genes involved in ossification, notochord maintenance and axial mesoderm development.</str>
      <str>We have identified a shared homozygous mutation in three families in T and linked it to a novel syndrome consisting of sacral agenesis, a persistent notochordal canal and abnormal ossification of the vertebral bodies. We suggest that screening for the ossification of the vertebrae is warranted in patients with sacral agenesis to evaluate the possible causal involvement of T.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Mutations in the T (brachyury) gene cause a novel syndrome consisting of sacral agenesis, abnormal ossification of the vertebral bodies and a persistent notochordal canal.</str>
    <str name="id">24253444</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The epithelial-mesenchymal transition (EMT) is emerging as a critical factor for the progression and metastasis of carcinomas, as well as drug resistance. The T-box transcription factor Brachyury has been recently characterized as a driver of EMT in human carcinoma cells. The purpose of this study was to characterize Brachyury as a potential target for lung cancer therapy.</str>
      <str>The expression of Brachyury was evaluated by PCR and by immunohistochemistry in human lung tumors and adult normal tissues. Brachyury gene copy number and promoter methylation status were analyzed in tumor tissues with various levels of Brachyury expression. Lung carcinoma cells' susceptibility to T-cell lysis and EGF receptor (EGFR) kinase inhibition were also evaluated relative to the levels of Brachyury.</str>
      <str>Our results showed Brachyury protein expression in 41% of primary lung carcinomas, including 48% of adenocarcinomas and 25% of squamous cell carcinomas. With the exception of normal testis and some thyroid tissues, the majority of normal tissues evaluated in this study were negative for the expression of Brachyury protein. Brachyury-specific T cells could lyse Brachyury-positive tumors and the level of Brachyury corresponded to resistance of tumor cells to EGFR kinase inhibition.</str>
      <str>We hypothesize that the elimination of Brachyury-positive tumor cells may be able to prevent and/or diminish tumor dissemination and the establishment of metastases. The ability of Brachyury-specific T-cell lines to lyse Brachyury-positive tumor cells, in vitro, supports the development of Brachyury-based immunotherapeutic approaches for the treatment of lung cancer.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Brachyury, a driver of the epithelial-mesenchymal transition, is overexpressed in human lung tumors: an opportunity for novel interventions against lung cancer.</str>
    <str name="id">22611028</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Chordoma is a rare bone cancer that is believed to originate from notochordal remnants. We previously identified germline T duplication as a major susceptibility mechanism in several chordoma families. Recently, a common genetic variant in T (rs2305089) was significantly associated with the risk of sporadic chordoma. We sequenced all T exons in 24 familial cases and 54 unaffected family members from eight chordoma families (three with T duplications), 103 sporadic cases, and 160 unrelated controls. We also measured T copy number variation in all sporadic cases. We confirmed the association between the previously reported variant rs2305089 and risk of familial [odds ratio (OR) = 2.6, 95% confidence interval (CI) = 0.93, 7.25, P = 0.067] and sporadic chordoma (OR = 2.85, 95% CI = 1.89, 4.29, P &lt; 0.0001). We also identified a second common variant, rs1056048, that was strongly associated with chordoma in families (OR = 4.14, 95% CI = 1.43, 11.92, P = 0.0086). Among sporadic cases, another common variant (rs3816300) was significantly associated with risk when jointly analyzed with rs2305089. The association with rs3816300 was significantly stronger in cases with early age onset. In addition, we identified three rare variants that were only observed among sporadic chordoma cases, all of which have potential functional relevance based on in silico predictions. Finally, we did not observe T duplication in any sporadic chordoma case. Our findings further highlight the importance of the T gene in the pathogenesis of both familial and sporadic chordoma and suggest a complex susceptibility related to T.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Characterization of T gene sequence variants and germline duplications in familial and sporadic chordoma.</str>
    <str name="id">24990759</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Chordoma is a neoplasm of notochordal differentiation that typically occurs in the axial skeleton. Accurate diagnosis is therapeutically important but can be challenging, especially in fine-needle aspiration (FNA) and core needle biopsy (CNB). Immunohistochemistry for the transcription factor brachyury (T) has recently proven diagnostically useful in whole-tissue sections. Our aim was to compare brachyury performance with conventional markers (S-100, EMA, keratin) and to evaluate its utility in distinguishing chordoma from cytomorphologic mimics. Brachyury immunohistochemistry was performed on chordoma (8 FNA, 12 CNB), chondrosarcoma (10 FNA), and metastatic mucinous adenocarcinoma (12 FNA). Immunohistochemistry performed at the time of diagnosis was also reviewed. Brachyury was positive in 17 (85%) cases of chordoma and typically showed moderate-to-strong nuclear staining. Of five sets of concurrent FNA and CNB, four pairs were positive for brachyury in both samples and one pair was positive for brachyury in the CNB and negative in the cell block. S-100, EMA, and keratin stains were available for 13 chordomas: 9 (69%) cases (including the 3 negative for brachyury) were positive for S-100 and keratin or EMA; 4 cases were keratin positive but S-100 negative. No nuclear brachyury staining was seen in chondrosarcoma or adenocarcinoma, though two adenocarcinomas showed cytoplasmic staining. Brachyury separates chordoma from cytomorphologic mimics with high sensitivity and specificity in small biopsies. As a single test, brachyury has higher sensitivity than a combined panel of S-100 and epithelial markers. When added to the conventional panel, brachyury increases sensitivity to 100% without sacrificing specificity.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Utility of brachyury in distinction of chordoma from cytomorphologic mimics in fine-needle aspiration and core needle biopsy.</str>
    <str name="id">24554551</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The epithelial-mesenchymal transition (EMT) has been implicated as an important process in tumor cell invasion, metastasis, and drug resistance. The transcription factor brachyury has recently been described as a driver of EMT of human carcinoma cells.</str>
      <str>Brachyury mRNA and protein expression was analyzed in human breast carcinomas and benign tissues. The role of brachyury in breast tumor prognosis and drug resistance and the ability of brachyury-specific T cells to lyse human breast carcinoma cells were also evaluated. Kaplan-Meier analyses were used to evaluate the association between brachyury expression and survival. All statistical tests were two-sided.</str>
      <str>The level of brachyury expression in breast cancer cells was positively associated with their ability to invade the extracellular matrix, efficiently form mammospheres in vitro, and resist the cytotoxic effect of docetaxel. A comparison of survival among breast cancer patients treated with tamoxifen in the adjuvant setting who had tumors with high vs low brachyury mRNA expression demonstrated that high expression of brachyury is associated as an independent variable with higher risk of recurrence (hazard ratio [HR] = 7.5; 95% confidence interval [CI] = 2.4 to 23.5; P = 5.14×10(-4)) and distant metastasis (HR = 15.2; 95% CI = 3.5 to 66.3; P = 3.01×10(-4)). We also demonstrated that brachyury-specific T cells can lyse human breast carcinoma cells.</str>
      <str>The studies reported here provide the rationale for the use of a vaccine targeting brachyury for the therapy of human breast cancer, either as a monotherapy or in combination therapies.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Overexpression of the EMT driver brachyury in breast carcinomas: association with poor prognosis.</str>
    <str name="id">24815864</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To date, most studies aimed at discovering genetic factors influencing treatment response in asthma have focused on biologic candidate genes. Genome-wide association studies (GWAS) can rapidly identify novel pharmacogenetic loci.</str>
      <str>To investigate if GWAS can identify novel pharmacogenetic loci in asthma.</str>
      <str>Using phenotypic and GWAS genotype data available through the NHLBI-funded Single-nucleotide polymorphism Health association-Asthma Resource Project, we analyzed differences in FEV(1) in response to inhaled corticosteroids in 418 white subjects with asthma. Of the 444,088 single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) analyzed, the lowest 50 SNPs by P value were genotyped in an independent clinical trial population of 407 subjects with asthma.</str>
      <str>The lowest P value for the GWAS analysis was 2.09 × 10(-6). Of the 47 SNPs successfully genotyped in the replication population, three were associated under the same genetic model in the same direction, including two of the top four SNPs ranked by P value. Combined P values for these SNPs were 1.06 × 10(-5) for rs3127412 and 6.13 × 10(-6) for rs6456042. Although these two were not located within a gene, they were tightly correlated with three variants mapping to potentially functional regions within the T gene. After genotyping, each T gene variant was also associated with lung function response to inhaled corticosteroids in each of the trials associated with rs3127412 and rs6456042 in the initial GWAS analysis. On average, there was a twofold to threefold difference in FEV(1) response for those subjects homozygous for the wild-type versus mutant alleles for each T gene SNP.</str>
      <str>Genome-wide association has identified the T gene as a novel pharmacogenetic locus for inhaled corticosteroid response in asthma.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Genome-wide association identifies the T gene as a novel asthma pharmacogenetic locus.</str>
    <str name="id">22538805</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>No major susceptibility genes for sporadically occurring congenital vertebral malformations (CVM) in humans have been identified to date. Body patterning genes whose mutants cause axial skeletal anomalies in mice are candidates for human CVM susceptibility. T (also known as Brachyury) and TBX6 are critical genes needed to establish mesodermal identity. We hypothesized that mutations in T and/or TBX6 contribute to the pathogenesis of human CVMs. The complete T and TBX6 coding regions, splice junctions, and proximal 500 bp of the promoters were sequenced in 50 phenotyped patients with CVM. Three unrelated patients with sacral agenesis, Klippel-Feil syndrome, and multiple cervical and thoracic vertebral malformations were heterozygous for a c.1013C&gt;T substitution, resulting in a predicted Ala338Val missense alteration in exon 8. A clinically unaffected parent of each patient also harbored the substitution, but the variant did not occur in an ethnically diverse, 443-person reference population. The c.1013C&gt;T variant is significantly associated with CVM (p &lt; 0.001). Alanine 338 shows moderate conservation across species, and valine at this position has not been reported in any species. A fourth patient harbored a c.908-8C&gt;T variant in intron 7. This previously unreported variant was tested in 347 normal control subjects, and 11 heterozygotes and 2 T/T individuals were found. No TBX6 variants were identified. We infer that the c.1013C&gt;T substitution is pathogenic and represents the first report of an association between a missense mutation in the T gene and the occurrence of sporadic CVMs in humans. It is uncertain whether the splice junction variant increases CVM risk. TBX6 mutations do not seem to be associated with CVM. We hypothesize that epistatic interactions between T and other developmental genes and the environment modulate the phenotypic consequences of T variants.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">A missense T (Brachyury) mutation contributes to vertebral malformations.</str>
    <str name="id">18466071</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>We describe a genetic analysis of the human homologue (T) of the mouse T (Brachyury) gene; human T was recently cloned in our laboratory. The protein product of the T gene is a transcription factor crucial in vertebrates for the formation of normal mesoderm. T mutant Brachyury mice die in midgestation with severe defects in posterior mesodermal tissues; heterozygous mice are viable but have posterior axial malformations. In addition to its importance in development, T has intrigued geneticists because of its association with the mouse t-haplotype; this haplotype is a variant form of the t-complex and is characterized by transmission ratio distortion, male sterility and recombination suppression. We have identified a common polymorphism of human T by single strand conformation polymorphism (SSCP) and used this in mapping studies and to re-investigate the idea that human T is involved in susceptibility to the multifactorial, neural tube defect, spina bifida. Our mapping data show that human T maps to 6q27 and lies between two other genes of the t-complex, TCP1 and TCP10. These data add to the evidence that in man the genes of the t-complex are split into two main locations on the short and long arms of chromosome 6. We have used an allele association test which is independent of mode of inheritance and penetrance to analyse data from the spina bifida families. Using this test we find evidence for a significant (p = 0.02) association between transmission of the TIVS7-2 allele of the human T gene and spina bifida.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Genetic mapping of the human homologue (T) of mouse T(Brachyury) and a search for allele association between human T and spina bifida.</str>
    <str name="id">8733136</str></doc>
</result>
</response>
