<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<response>

<lst name="responseHeader">
  <int name="status">0</int>
  <int name="QTime">0</int>
  <lst name="params">
    <str name="q">
9259203
7874125
12713581
7762554
11601658
7601462
18563784
10671067
12876664
12163334
18528436
7920637
11179026
25119903
12727022
20628086
23824587
19626598
19625176
22561518
18839200
12469324
8302318
17767372
18650849
19320733
10987646
18683857
8875191
17960121
8421497
17619204
18326704
15712365
11310796
20861488
18676680
19170196
22133426
12028586
20629734
12579416
20806075
16453125
17236130
10649493
23548203
20308648</str>
    <str name="indent">true</str>
    <str name="fl">id, medline_abstract_text, medline_article_title</str>
    <str name="rows">100</str>
    <str name="wt">xml</str>
  </lst>
</lst>
<result name="response" numFound="48" start="0">
  <doc>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Novel mutations of the P gene in type II oculocutaneous albinism (OCA2).</str>
    <str name="id">9259203</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Type II (tyrosinase-positive) oculocutaneous albinism (OCA2) is an autosomal recessive disorder in which the biosynthesis of melanin pigment is reduced in the skin, hair, and eyes. OCA2, which we have shown results from mutations of the P gene in Caucasians, is the most prevalent type of oculocutaneous albinism in African and African-American patients with OCA. We have identified abnormalities of the P gene in seven unrelated African-American patients with OCA2, including three large deletions, two small in-frame deletions, and six different point mutations. None of these appears to be predominant among African-American patients with OCA2.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Diverse mutations of the P gene among African-Americans with type II (tyrosinase-positive) oculocutaneous albinism (OCA2).</str>
    <str name="id">7874125</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Type 2 oculocutaneous albinism (OCA2) is an autosomal recessive disorder that results from mutations in the P gene that codes one of the melanosomal proteins, the function of which remains unknown. In this paper, we report the frequency of OCA2, 8%, among the Japanese albino population, six novel mutations containing four missense substitutions (P198L, P211L, R10W, M398I), and two splice site mutations (IVS15+1 G&gt;A, IVS24-1 G&gt;C). One of them, R10W, was within the putative signal peptide at the N-terminal of the P protein. This is the first report on the frequency of OCA2 in the Japanese albino population.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Six novel P gene mutations and oculocutaneous albinism type 2 frequency in Japanese albino patients.</str>
    <str name="id">12713581</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Type II oculocutaneous albinism (OCA2) is an autosomal recessive disorder in which the biosynthesis of melanin pigment is reduced in the skin, hair, and eyes. OCA2, which results from mutations of the P gene, is the most frequent type of albinism in African and African-American patients. OCA2 is especially frequent in Tanzania, where it occurs with an incidence of approximately 1/1,400. We have identified abnormalities of the P gene in each of 13 unrelated patients with OCA2 from Tanzania. One of these, a deletion of exon 7, is strongly predominant, accounting for approximately 77% of mutant alleles in this group of patients.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Frequent intragenic deletion of the P gene in Tanzanian patients with type II oculocutaneous albinism (OCA2).</str>
    <str name="id">7762554</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The pink-eyed dilution protein (p) plays a pivotal role in the synthesis of eumelanin. In its absence, critical melanosomal proteins fail to traffic to the melanosome. Pink-eyed dilution gene (P) mutations are the most common cause of tyrosinase-positive oculocutaneous albinism worldwide. Thus, reports that bafilomycin A1 was able to induce synthesis of melanin in tyrosinase-positive melanomas led us to test the drug on p-null murine melanocytes. We found that in melanocytes lacking p, bafilomycin A1 was able to induce melanin synthesis. These cells, once transfected with an expression vector encoding an epitope-tagged p transcript, failed to respond to the drug. The increase in melanin synthesis is accompanied by a reduction in tyrosinase protein cleavage and secretion with subsequent accumulation within the melanocyte. Bafilomycin A1 has also been reported to induce pigmentation of normal Caucasian melanocytes. Based on these data we hypothesize that p may serve as a key control point at which ethnic skin color variation is determined.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Inverse correlation between pink-eyed dilution protein expression and induction of melanogenesis by bafilomycin A1.</str>
    <str name="id">11601658</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>We have determined the structure, nucleotide sequence, and polymorphisms of the human P gene. Mutations of the P gene result in type II oculocutaneous albinism (OCA2) in humans and pink-eyed dilution (p) in mice. We find that the human P gene is quite large, consisting of 25 exons spanning 250 to 600 kb in chromosome segment 15q11-q13. The P polypeptide appears to define a novel family of small molecule transporters and may be involved in transport of tyrosine, the precursor to melanin synthesis, within the melanocyte. These results provide the basis for analyses of patients with OCA2 and may point toward eventual pharmacologic treatment of this and related disorders of pigmentation.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Organization and sequence of the human P gene and identification of a new family of transport proteins.</str>
    <str name="id">7601462</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Human pigmentation appears to be one of the strongest risk factors for malignant melanoma (MM). In humans, there is a long list of genes known to be involved in rare pigmentary disorders such as albinism. These genes explain most of the variation in pigmentation phenotypes seen in human populations, and they do this by regulating the level of synthesis, chemical composition, packaging, and distribution of melanin. This Spanish case-control study included 131 consecutive melanoma patients and 245 control subjects frequency-matched for sex and age. A total of 23 SNPs in six candidate genes (ASP, OCA2, TYR, TYRP1, SILV, and SLC45A) belonging to the pigmentation pathway were genotyped. We found that the variant allele of c.1122C&gt;G, p.Phe374Leu (NCBI dbSNP rs16891982) in SLC45A2 (membrane associated transporter previously known as MATP) was associated with protection from MM (OR, 0.41; 95% CI, 0.24-0.70; P=0.008 after adjustment for multiple testing). This association was validated by the consistent link observed with dark hair, dark skin, dark eye color, and the presence of solar lentigins and childhood sunburns. This is the first time SLC45A2 has been described as a melanoma susceptibility gene in a light-skinned population.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">SLC45A2: a novel malignant melanoma-associated gene.</str>
    <str name="id">18563784</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Mutations in the human P gene lead to oculocutaneous albinism type 2 (OCA2, MIM #203200), the most common type of albinism in humans. The P gene encodes a 110 kDa protein that is associated with melonosomal membranes and contains 12 potential membrane spanning domains. The specific function of the P protein is currently unknown. We report 7 new mutations in the P gene associated with OCA2. This includes 6 missense mutations (S86R, C112F, A368V, T592I, A724P and A787V) and one frameshift mutation (1047del7). We also report 8 polymorphisms including one amino acid substitution, D/A257. We and others have found many polymorphisms of the P gene in the coding region, several of which result in amino acid substitutions, making molecular diagnosis problematic. In contrast to this is the tyrosinase gene associated with OCA1, with a limited number of polymorphic variations in the coding region. There is also no apparent clustering of P gene missense mutations in contrast to the clustering observed by the tyrosinase gene missense mutations that define functional domains of the protein. Further mutational analysis is needed to help define the critical functional domains of the P protein and to allow a definitive diagnosis of OCA2.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Mutations of the human P gene associated with Type II oculocutaneous albinism (OCA2). Mutations in brief no. 205. Online.</str>
    <str name="id">10671067</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The heterogeneous group of disorders known as oculocutaneous albinism (OCA) shares cutaneous and ocular hypopigmentation associated with common developmental abnormalities of the eye. Mutations of at least 11 loci produce this phenotype. The majority of affected individuals develop some cutaneous melanin; this is predominantly seen as yellow/blond hair, whereas fewer have brown hair. The OCA phenotype is dependent on the constitutional pigmentation background of the family, with more OCA pigmentation found in families with darker constitutional pigmentation, which indicates that other genes may modify the OCA phenotype. Sequence variation in the melanocortin-1 receptor (MC1R) gene is associated with red hair in the normal population, but red hair is unusual in OCA. We identified eight probands with OCA who had red hair at birth. Mutations in the P gene were responsible for classic phenotype of oculocutaneous albinism type 2 (OCA2) in all eight, and mutations in the MC1R gene were responsible for the red (rather than yellow/blond) hair in the six of eight who continued to have red hair after birth. This is the first demonstration of a gene modifying the OCA phenotype in humans.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">MC1R mutations modify the classic phenotype of oculocutaneous albinism type 2 (OCA2).</str>
    <str name="id">12876664</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Human pigmentation, including eye color, has been associated with skin cancer risk. The P gene is the human homologue to the mouse pink-eye dilution locus and is responsible for oculocutaneous albinism type 2 and other phenotypes that confer eye hypopigmentation. The P gene is located on chromosome 15q11.2-q12, which is also the location of a putative eye pigmentation gene (EYCL3) inferred to exist by linkage analysis. Therefore, the P gene is a strong candidate for determination of human eye color. Using a sample of 629 normally pigmented individuals, we found that individuals were less likely to have blue or gray eyes if they had P gene variants Arg305Trp (P = 0.002), Arg419Gln (P = 0.001), or the combination of both variants (P = 0.003). These results suggest that P gene, in part, determines normal phenotypic variation in human eye color and may therefore represent an inherited biomarker of cutaneous cancer risk.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">P gene as an inherited biomarker of human eye color.</str>
    <str name="id">12163334</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Genetic studies of pigmentation have benefited from spectrophotometric measures of light-dark hair color. Here we use one of those measures, absorbance at 650 nm, to look for chromosomal regions that harbor genes affecting hair pigmentation. At 7p15.1, marker D7S1808 was suggestive of linkage to light-dark hair color (LOD approximately 2.99). Marker D1S235 at 1q42.3 was suggestive of linkage to hair color (light-dark or blonde-black continuum) (LOD approximately 2.14). However, the most consistent linkage peak was over the gene oculocutaneous albinism type II (OCA2) on chromosome 15. Linkage analysis of both spectrophotometrically quantified and ordered ratings of hair color had LOD scores about 1.2, significant because of the almost perfect concordance. A quantitative transmission disequilibrium test between light-dark hair color and 58 single nucleotide polymorphisms in OCA2 showed that the SNPs rs4778138 (also called rs11855019) and rs1375164 were associated with significantly darker hair color (P approximately 3 x 10(-4) and P approximately 0.03 after correction for multiple testing, respectively). These two SNPs explain 1.54 and 0.85% of variation in the A650t index, respectively.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Linkage and association analysis of spectrophotometrically quantified hair color in Australian adolescents: the effect of OCA2 and HERC2.</str>
    <str name="id">18528436</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Oculocutaneous albinism (OCA) is a genetically heterogeneous hypopigmentation disorder. One of the two major autosomal recessive forms involves the tyrosinase gene (OCA1), while the other form (OCA2) has recently been associated with alterations of the P gene on chromosome 15. OCA2 is about twice as common as OCA1 in African and African-American populations. We now describe an interstitial deletion that removes a single exon of the P gene. In a large family from an inbred population of tri-racial origin, all individuals with OCA2 were found to be homozygous for this allele. Moreover, the same mutant P allele was detected in several unrelated African American individuals with OCA2, but not in Caucasians with OCA2. The detection of the same allele in two unrelated Africans with OCA2 indicates an African origin for this allele.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">African origin of an intragenic deletion of the human P gene in tyrosinase positive oculocutaneous albinism.</str>
    <str name="id">7920637</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>In southern Africa, brown oculocutaneous albinism (BOCA) is a distinct pigmentation phenotype. In at least two cases, it has occurred in the same families as tyrosinase-positive oculocutaneous albinism (OCA2), suggesting that it may be allelic, despite the fact that this phenotype was attributed to mutations in the TYRP1 gene in an American individual of mixed ancestry. Linkage analysis in five families mapped the BOCA locus to the same region as the OCA2 locus (maximum LOD 3.07; theta=0 using a six-marker haplotype). Mutation analysis of the human homologue of the mouse pink-eyed dilution gene (P), in 10 unrelated individuals with BOCA revealed that 9 had one copy of the 2.7-kb deletion. No other mutations were identified. Additional haplotype studies, based on closely linked markers (telomere to centromere: D15S1048, D15S1019, D15S1533, P-gene 2.7-kb deletion, D15S219, and D15S156) revealed several BOCA-associated P haplotypes. These could be divided into two core haplotypes, suggesting that a limited number of P-gene mutations give rise to this phenotype.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">In Southern Africa, brown oculocutaneous albinism (BOCA) maps to the OCA2 locus on chromosome 15q: P-gene mutations identified.</str>
    <str name="id">11179026</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To perform genotyping analysis and subsequent prenatal genetic diagnosis for two families affected with oculocutaneous albinism (OCA).</str>
      <str>Direct sequencing of TYR and P genes was performed in two albino probands. Family members were screened for corresponding mutant alleles. Prenatal genetic diagnoses were performed at early pregnancy by chorionic villus sampling (CVS) at mid-pregnancy through amniocentesis.</str>
      <str>No mutations were detected in the TYR gene in either probands, whereas 4 heterozygous mutations of the P gene were found, namely c.406C&gt;T, c.535A&gt;G, c.808-2A&gt;G and c.2180T&gt;C, among which c.535A&gt;G and c.808-2A&gt;G were novel. In the first round prenatal genetic testing, both fetuses were found to have the same genotypes as the probands. Both families had decided to terminate the pregnancy after genetic counseling. In the second round testing, neither of the fetuses was found to be affected by genotyping. The pregnancies continued and two healthy fetuses were born.</str>
      <str>OCA can be classified by genotyping, with which reliable prenatal diagnosis and feasible genetic counseling may be provided.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">[Prenatal genetic diagnosis for two Chinese families affected with oculocutaneous albinism type Ⅱ].</str>
    <str name="id">25119903</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Oculocutaneous albinism type II (OCA2) is an autosomal recessively inherited disorder, characterized by white hair and skin, and loss of pigment in the eyes. Mutations in P gene have been shown to result in OCA2. So far, two cases have been reported from Japan.</str>
      <str>We had an opportunity to examine a case of albinism, and screened the mutations of tyrosinase and P gene.</str>
      <str>Genomic DNA was prepared from peripheral leukocytes. All of the exons and flanking introns of tyrosinase and P gene were PCR-direct-sequenced.</str>
      <str>Although no mutations were found in tyrosinase, we found two missense substitutions, A481T and Q799H in P gene. The A481T has previously been shown to result in partial function of the P protein.</str>
      <str>The Q799H mutation is not a common polymorphism among normal Japanese, seems most likely to be a pathological OCA2 mutation among Japanese with this form of albinism.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">A novel P gene missense mutation in a Japanese patient with oculocutaneous albinism type II (OCA2).</str>
    <str name="id">12727022</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Thiazolidinediones are used to treat type 2 diabetes. Their use has been associated with peripheral edema and congestive heart failure-outcomes that may have a genetic etiology.</str>
      <str>We genotyped 4,197 participants of the multiethnic DREAM (Diabetes REduction Assessment with ramipril and rosiglitazone Medication) trial with a 50k single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNP) array, which captures ∼2000 cardiovascular, inflammatory, and metabolic genes. We tested 32,088 SNPs for an association with edema among Europeans who received rosiglitazone (n = 965).</str>
      <str>One SNP, rs6123045, in NFATC2 was significantly associated with edema (odds ratio 1.89 [95% CI 1.47-2.42]; P = 5.32 × 10(-7), corrected P = 0.017). Homozygous individuals had the highest edema rate (hazard ratio 2.89, P = 4.22 × 10(-4)) when compared with individuals homozygous for the protective allele, with heterozygous individuals having an intermediate risk. The interaction between the SNP and rosiglitazone for edema was significant (P = 7.68 × 10(-3)). Six SNPs in NFATC2 were significant in both Europeans and Latin Americans (P &lt; 0.05).</str>
      <str>Genetic variation at the NFATC2 locus contributes to edema among individuals who receive rosiglitazone.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Variation at the NFATC2 locus increases the risk of thiazolidinedione-induced edema in the Diabetes REduction Assessment with ramipril and rosiglitazone Medication (DREAM) study.</str>
    <str name="id">20628086</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Oculocutaneous albinism type 2 (OCA2), caused by mutations of OCA2 gene, is an autosomal recessive disorder characterized by reduced biosynthesis of melanin pigment in the skin, hair, and eyes. The OCA2 gene encodes instructions for making a protein called the P protein. This protein plays a crucial role in melanosome biogenesis, and controls the eumelanin content in melanocytes in part via the processing and trafficking of tyrosinase which is the rate-limiting enzyme in melanin synthesis. In this study we analyzed the pathogenic effect of 95 non-synonymous single nucleotide polymorphisms reported in OCA2 gene using computational methods. We found R305W mutation as most deleterious and disease associated using SIFT, PolyPhen, PANTHER, PhD-SNP, Pmut, and MutPred tools. To understand the atomic arrangement in 3D space, the native and mutant (R305W) structures were modeled. Molecular dynamics simulation was conducted to observe the structural significance of computationally prioritized disease-associated mutation (R305W). Root-mean-square deviation, root-mean-square fluctuation, radius of gyration, solvent accessibility surface area, hydrogen bond (NH bond), trace of covariance matrix, eigenvector projection analysis, and density analysis results showed prominent loss of stability and rise in mutant flexibility values in 3D space. This study presents a well designed computational methodology to examine the albinism-associated SNPs.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Computational screening of disease-associated mutations in OCA2 gene.</str>
    <str name="id">23824587</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To present our accumulated data on prenatal molecular diagnosis of oculocutaneous albinism (OCA) in a large cohort of Israeli albino families.</str>
      <str>Albinism consists of variable phenotypes, but only families with predicted severely handicapped albino offspring, who declared their wish to terminate a pregnancy of such a fetus, are eligible for prenatal testing. Prenatal testing is not offered otherwise. Following detailed genetic investigation and counseling, molecular prenatal testing was performed using the combination of mutation screening, direct sequencing, and haplotype analysis.</str>
      <str>A total of 55 prenatal tests were performed in 37 families; in 26 families the propositus was the child, and in 11, a parent or a close relative. In 32 families tyrosinase (TYR) mutations were diagnosed. In 5 families a P gene mutation was detected. Twelve albino fetuses were diagnosed. Following further genetic counseling, all couples elected to terminate the pregnancy. Three additional pregnancies were terminated for other reasons.</str>
      <str>Families with increased risk for an albino child with severe visual handicap, seek premarital and prenatal genetic counseling and testing, for the prevention of affected offspring. Our combined methods of molecular genetic testing enable a nationwide approach for prevention of albinism. The same paradigm can be applied to other populations affected with albinism.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Prenatal molecular diagnosis of oculocutaneous albinism (OCA) in a large cohort of Israeli families.</str>
    <str name="id">19626598</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Common genetic variation may play an important role in altering chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) risk. In Xuanwei, China, the COPD rate is more than twice the Chinese national average, and COPD is strongly associated with in-home coal use. To identify genetic variation that may be associated with COPD in a population with substantial in-home coal smoke exposures, we evaluated 1261 single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) in 380 candidate genes potentially relevant for cancer and other human diseases in a population-based case-control study in Xuanwei (53 cases; 107 controls). PTEN was the most significantly associated gene with COPD in a minP analysis using 20,000 permutations (P=0.00005). SNP-based analyses found that homozygote variant carriers of PTEN rs701848 (OR(TT)=0.12, 95% CI=0.03-0.47) had a significant decreased risk of COPD. PTEN, or phosphatase and tensin homolog, is an important regulator of cell cycle progression and cellular survival via the AKT signaling pathway. Our exploratory analysis suggests that genetic variation in PTEN may be an important risk factor of COPD in Xuanwei. However, due to the small sample size, additional studies are needed to evaluate these associations within Xuanwei and other populations with coal smoke exposures.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">PTEN identified as important risk factor of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease.</str>
    <str name="id">19625176</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>We previously reported a genome-wide association study (GWAS) identifying 14 susceptibility loci for generalized vitiligo. We report here a second GWAS (450 individuals with vitiligo (cases) and 3,182 controls), an independent replication study (1,440 cases and 1,316 controls) and a meta-analysis (3,187 cases and 6,723 controls) identifying 13 additional vitiligo-associated loci. These include OCA2-HERC2 (combined P = 3.80 × 10(-8)), MC1R (P = 1.82 × 10(-13)), a region near TYR (P = 1.57 × 10(-13)), IFIH1 (P = 4.91 × 10(-15)), CD80 (P = 3.78 × 10(-10)), CLNK (P = 1.56 × 10(-8)), BACH2 (P = 2.53 × 10(-8)), SLA (P = 1.58 × 10(-8)), CASP7 (P = 3.56 × 10(-8)), CD44 (P = 1.78 × 10(-9)), IKZF4 (P = 2.75 × 10(-14)), SH2B3 (P = 3.54 × 10(-18)) and TOB2 (P = 6.81 × 10(-10)). Most vitiligo susceptibility loci encode immunoregulatory proteins or melanocyte components that likely mediate immune targeting and the relationships among vitiligo, melanoma, and eye, skin and hair coloration.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Genome-wide association analyses identify 13 new susceptibility loci for generalized vitiligo.</str>
    <str name="id">22561518</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The population origin of an individual is often requested to be determined from specimens left at a crime scene for identifying a suspect and individual identity. The melanocortin 1 receptor gene (MC1R) and P gene are associated with human pigmentation. Although several studies have reported that these genes are highly polymorphic in human populations, it is unclear if the allele variants can be used to determine the population origin of an individual. We aimed to determine the ethnic origin of an individual by using single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs). Eighteen SNPs in the MC1R gene and P genes were genotyped in 52 individuals by the direct sequencing method, and 4 SNPs (MC1R gene: R163Q and P gene: IVS5 + 1001, IVS13 + 113, and H615R) were selected on the basis of differences in frequencies. Subsequently, we genotyped these four SNPs in 422 volunteers from six ethnically defined populations using a polymerase chain reaction-based assay. The results revealed that the allele variants were present with high frequencies in Asian populations but were low in European and African populations. On the basis of these results, we defined a specific combination of a genotype (R163Q) and a diplotype group (IVS5 + 1001, IVS13 + 113, and H615R). This study indicates that the specific combination of a genotype and a diplotype group would be effective in estimating the population origin of an individual from a list of population groups.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Variants of the melanocortin 1 receptor gene (MC1R) and P gene as indicators of the population origin of an individual.</str>
    <str name="id">18839200</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Oculocutaneous albinism (OCA) is a genetically heterogeneous disorder. There are four known types of OCA: OCA1-OCA4. The clinical manifestations of all types of OCA include skin and hair hypopigmentation and visual impairment. Although there are a few documented observations of high frequency of albinism among Native Americans, including the Hopi, Zuni, Kuna, Jemez, Laguna, San Juan, and Navajo, no causative molecular defect has been previously reported. In the present study, we show that albinism in one Native American population, the Navajo, is caused by a LINE-mediated 122.5-kilobase deletion of the P gene, thus demonstrating that albinism in this population is OCA2. This deletion appears to be Navajo specific, because this allele was not detected in 34 other individuals with albinism who listed other Native American origins, nor has it been reported in any other ethnic group. The molecular characterization of this deletion allele allowed us to design a three-primer polymerase chain reaction system to estimate the carrier frequency in the Navajo population by screening 134 unrelated normally pigmented Navajos. The carrier frequency was found to be approximately 4.5%. The estimated prevalence of OCA2 in Navajos is between approximately 1 per 1,500 and 1 per 2,000. We further estimate that this mutation originated 400-1,000 years ago from a single founder.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">A 122.5-kilobase deletion of the P gene underlies the high prevalence of oculocutaneous albinism type 2 in the Navajo population.</str>
    <str name="id">12469324</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Type II (tyrosinase-positive) oculocutaneous albinism is an autosomal recessive disorder that has recently been mapped to chromosome segment 15q11-q13. The frequency of this disorder is greatly increased in patients with Prader-Willi or Angelman syndrome, both of which involve deletions of chromosome 15q. The P protein is a transmembrane polypeptide that may transport small molecules such as tyrosine, the precursor of melanin. The P gene is located in chromosome segment 15q11-q13.</str>
      <str>We studied the tyrosinase and P genes in three patients with type II oculocutaneous albinism, one of whom also had Prader-Willi syndrome, and in one patient with a milder syndrome known as autosomal recessive ocular albinism. Individual exons of these genes were amplified from the DNA of each patient by the polymerase chain reaction and screened for mutations by simultaneous analyses of single-stranded conformation polymorphisms and heteroduplexes and subsequent DNA sequencing.</str>
      <str>Mutations of the P gene were identified in all four patients. These included one frame shift, three missense mutations that result in amino acid substitutions, and one mutation that affects RNA splicing. The patient with Prader-Willi syndrome plus albinism had a typical deletion of the paternal chromosome 15, rendering him hemizygous for a maternally inherited mutant allele of the P gene. The child with ocular albinism was heterozygous for two different mutations in the P gene.</str>
      <str>Abnormalities of the P gene are associated with a wide range of clinical phenotypes, including type II oculocutaneous albinism, albinism associated with the Prader-Willi syndrome, and at least some cases of autosomal recessive ocular albinism.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Mutations of the P gene in oculocutaneous albinism, ocular albinism, and Prader-Willi syndrome plus albinism.</str>
    <str name="id">8302318</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>In this study, we report on a Cameroonian family from the Ewondo ethnic group, presenting with three oculocutaneous albinism type 2 (OCA2) patients homozygous for the 2.7-kb deletion of the P gene. In one of these patients OCA2 was associated with sickle cell anaemia and in two with the sickle cell trait. We took this opportunity to determine single nucleotide polymorphism (SNP) haplotypes within the P gene in this family in comparison with a group of 53 OCA2 patients homozygous for the same mutation and with a matched unrelated full-coloured control group of 49 subjects, originating from seven different ethnic groups of Southern Cameroon including Ewondo. A combination of five exonic and intronic SNPs in the OCA2 gene was genotyped by sequencing PCR products. We found 3 different haplotypes (TAGCT, TAGTT and TAGCC with frequencies of 0.66, 0.28 and 0.06, respectively) associated with the mutation in the 53 OCA2 patients, while 11 different haplotypes were observed in the control group. These observations suggest that the mutation appeared on the relatively frequent haplotype TAGCT, and that the two other haplotypes are derived from two independent recombination events. These haplotypic data, associated with a value of 1/15,000 for the prevalence of the 2.7-kb mutation, a present effective population size of 10,000,000 for Cameroon and a recombination rate of 0.0031, allowed us to estimate that this mutation originated 4,100-5,645 years ago.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Oculocutaneous albinism type 2 (OCA2) with homozygous 2.7-kb deletion of the P gene and sickle cell disease in a Cameroonian family. Identification of a common TAG haplotype in the mutated P gene.</str>
    <str name="id">17767372</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) within the SLC45A2/MATP, SLC24A5/NCKX5, and OCA2/P genes have been associated with natural variation of pigmentation traits in human populations. Here, we describe the characterization of human primary melanocytic cells genotyped for polymorphisms within the MATP, NCKX5, or OCA2 loci. On the basis of genotype, these cultured cells reflect the phenotypes observed by others in terms of both melanin content and tyrosinase (TYR) activity when comparing skin designated as either "White" or "Black". We found a statistically significant association of MATP-374L (darker skin) with higher TYR protein abundance that was not observed for any NCKX5-111 or OCA2 rs12913832 allele. MATP-374L/L homozygous strains displayed significantly lower MATP transcript levels compared to MATP-374F/F homozygous cells, but this did not reach statistical significance based on NCKX5 or OCA2 genotype. Similarly, we observed significantly increased levels of OCA2 mRNA in rs12913832-T (brown eye) homozygotes compared to rs12913832-C (blue eye) homozygous strains, which was not observed for MATP or NCKX5 gene transcripts. In genotype-phenotype associations performed on a collection of 226 southern European individuals using these same SNPs, we were able to show strong correlations in MATP-L374F, OCA2, and melanocortin-1 receptor with skin, eye, and hair color variation, respectively.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Analysis of cultured human melanocytes based on polymorphisms within the SLC45A2/MATP, SLC24A5/NCKX5, and OCA2/P loci.</str>
    <str name="id">18650849</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Human pigmentation appears to be one of the main modulators of individual risk of developing malignant melanoma (MM). A large number of genes are known to be involved in rare pigmentary disorders and explain most of the variation in pigmentation phenotypes seen in human populations. This Spanish case-control study included 205 patients with melanoma and 245 control subjects. Thirty-one single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) in genes that had been mainly associated with congenital pigmentation syndromes (ADTB3A, ATRN, CHS1, EDNRB, HPS, KIT, MGRN1, MITF, MLANA, MYO5A, MYO7A, OA1, OCA2, PAX3 and SOX10) were selected. We found that the variant allele of OCA2 R419Q (rs1800407) was associated with increased risk of MM (OR 1.55, 95% CI 1.04-2.31, P = 0.03). This effect on melanoma risk appeared to be stronger among individuals with solar lentigines, or at least 50 nevi. We also describe, for the first time, an association with the variant S1666C (rs2276288) in the MYO7A gene (OR 1.35; 95% CI 1.04-1.76; P = 0.03). Again, this association appeared to be stronger in several phenotypic groups such as individuals with fair skin and those with childhood sunburns. We also found that several variants in the pigmentation genes considered were associated with intermediate phenotypic characteristics. Our findings highlight the potential importance of pigmentation genes in sporadic MM susceptibility.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Pigmentation-related genes and their implication in malignant melanoma susceptibility.</str>
    <str name="id">19320733</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Albinism is a heterogeneous group of genetic disorders resulting from deficiencies in pigmentation. Clinically, it is divided into ocular (OA) and oculocutaneous albinism (OCA). OCA involves lack of pigment in the skin, hair, and eyes and results from mutations in the tyrosinase gene or in the P gene. OA mainly affects pigmentation in the visual system and may be a mild form of OCA or may be caused by other genetic defects. Clinical diagnosis of albinism type is difficult, because of the observed range of phenotypic variation. Thus, genetic analysis may be helpful with respect to a more accurate diagnosis. Here, we report the mutational profile, determined by genetic analysis of the tyrosinase and P genes, of a large German albino population. We have revealed a total of 42 distinct mutations, 19 of which are novel. Of the 74 unrelated patients screened, 32 (43%) had mutations in the tyrosinase gene, 16 (22%) had P gene mutations, and 26 (35%) patients had no detectable genetic abnormalities. This defines a population of albino patients who are tyrosinase-gene- and P-gene-negative and who thus may represent a good study group for searching for additional genes associated with albinism.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Novel and recurrent mutations in the tyrosinase gene and the P gene in the German albino population.</str>
    <str name="id">10987646</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>In this study, we investigated whether variants in three key pigmentation genes-MC1R, MATP/SLC45A2, and OCA2--were involved in melanoma predisposition. A cohort comprising 1,019 melanoma patients (MelanCohort) and 1,466 Caucasian controls without skin cancers were studied. A total of 10 polymorphisms, including five functional MC1R alleles (p.Asp84Glu, p.Arg142His, p.Arg151Cys, p.Arg160Trp, and p.Asp294His), two nonsynonymous SLC45A2 variants (p.Phe374Leu and p.Glu272Lys), and three intronic OCA2 variants previously shown to be strongly associated with eye color (rs7495174 T&gt;C, rs4778241 G&gt;T, and rs4778138 T&gt;C) were genotyped. As expected, MC1R variants were closely associated with melanoma risk (P value &lt;2.20.10(-16); odds ratio [OR]=2.29 [95% confidence interval, CI=1.85-2.82 and OR=3.3 [95% CI=2.00-5.45], for the presence of one or two variants, respectively). Interestingly, the SLC45A2 variant p.Phe374Leu was significantly and strongly protective for melanoma (P-value=2.12.10(-15); OR=0.35 [95% CI=0.26-0.46] and OR=0.32 [95% CI=0.24-0.43], considering the genotypes Phe/Leu and Leu/Leu, respectively). MC1R and SLC45A2 variants had additive effects on melanoma risk, and after adjusting for pigmentation characteristics, the risk was persistent, even though both genes had a strong impact on pigmentation. Future studies may show whether genetic information could provide a useful complement to physical examination in predicting melanoma risk.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Variants of the MATP/SLC45A2 gene are protective for melanoma in the French population.</str>
    <str name="id">18683857</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Brown eye colour (BEY), or total brown iris pigmentation is one of the most common phenotypes of iris colour. Data of eye colour as well as hair colour were obtained for linkage analysis through an enquiry in our family material of 832 families from Copenhagen area. By exclusion mapping with 80 markers in 120 segregating families and 290 markers in 5 segregating families, we obtained some indication of a locus BEY2 for brown eye colour on chromosome 15. For possible confirmation, we selected a total of 45 families from our DNA bank segregating for BEY. All these were tested for chromosome 15 markers in the area between D15S11 and CYP19. We found a strong indication of tight linkage with the DNA polymorphism D15S165 (Z = 24.25; theta M = F = 0.010) and with the flanking markers D15S156 (Z = 14.04; theta M = F = 0.0.029) and D15S144 (Z = 12.99; theta M = F = 0.060). BEY2 is assigned to the region 15q11-15q21 by physically localized markers. A new locus for brown hair colour (HCL3) was localized by indication of linkage to BEY2 in our 45 families segregating for BEY (Z = 9.93; theta M = F = 0.10). The gene (DN10 or P) homologous to the pink-eye-dilution gene (p) in mice could be a candidate gene for BEY2 or for HCL3.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Assignment of genes coding for brown eye colour (BEY2) and brown hair colour (HCL3) on chromosome 15q.</str>
    <str name="id">8875191</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>To elucidate the molecular basis of oculocutaneous albinism with variable expressivity in a family from The Netherlands in which no consanguinity was reported.</str>
      <str>Three affected family members were screened for mutations in tyrosinase (TYR) and the pink-eye-dilution gene (P) by using SSCP. The melanocortin receptor gene (MC1R) and amplimers of P showing an aberrant banding pattern in SSCP were analyzed by direct sequencing. All participants underwent ophthalmologic examination including funduscopy, and visually evoked potentials were recorded in two cases.</str>
      <str>The pedigree had three branches A, B, and C. We identified three mutations in P (V443I, N476S, C793F) that cause a compound heterozygous situation in cases from branch A (N476S/C793F) and B (V443I/C793F), who showed oculocutaneous albinism. Hair and skin color followed the light Nordic complexion that was also present in other affected and unaffected members of this family. Descendants of branches A and B showed light complexion with iris translucency and peripheral fundus hypopigmentation independent from the genotype identified. A single descendant had red hair, carrying a well known compound MC1R mutation combination for red hair color and a single heterozygous P mutation.</str>
      <str>P mutations underlie oculocutaneous albinism in this family. Two known mutations in MC1R caused red hair color in one family member. No modifier effect of MC1R on P mutations could be deduced from the results of this study.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Mutation analysis in a family with oculocutaneous albinism manifesting in the same generation of three branches.</str>
    <str name="id">17960121</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The mouse pink-eyed dilution (p) locus on chromosome 7 is associated with defects of skin, eye and coat pigmentation. Mutations at p cause a reduction of eumelanin (black-brown) pigment and altered morphology of black pigment granules (eumelanosomes), but have little effect on pheomelanin (yellow-red) pigment. We show here that the human complementary DNA DN10, linked to the p locus in mice, identifies the human homologue (P) of the mouse p gene, and appears to encode an integral membrane transporter protein. The expression pattern of this gene in various p mutant mice correlates with the pigmentation phenotype; moreover, an abnormally sized messenger RNA is detected in one mutant, p(un), which reverts to the normal size in p(un) revertants. The human P gene corresponds to the D15S12 locus within the chromosome segment 15q11-q13, which is typically deleted in patients with Prader-Willi and Angelman syndrome (see ref. 5 for review). These disorders are phenotypically distinct, depending on the parent of origin of the deleted chromosome, but both syndromes are often associated with hypopigmentation of the skin, hair and eyes (see ref. 8 for review), and deletion of the P gene may be responsible for this hypopigmentation. In addition, we report a mutation in both copies of the human P gene in one case of tyrosinase-positive (type II) oculocutaneous albinism, recently linked to 15q11-q13 (ref. 9).</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">A gene for the mouse pink-eyed dilution locus and for human type II oculocutaneous albinism.</str>
    <str name="id">8421497</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Human iris color is a quantitative, multifactorial phenotype that exhibits quasi-Mendelian inheritance. Recent studies have shown that OCA2 polymorphism underlies most of the natural variability in human iris pigmentation but to date, only a few associated polymorphisms in this gene have been described. Herein, we describe an iris color score (C) for quantifying iris melanin content in-silico and undertake a more detailed survey of the OCA2 locus (n = 271 SNPs). In 1,317 subjects, we confirmed six previously described associations and identified another 27 strongly associated with C that were not explained by continental population stratification (OR 1.5-17.9, P = 0.03 to &lt;0.001). Haplotype analysis with respect to these 33 SNPs revealed six haplotype blocks and 11 hap-tags within these blocks. To identify genetic features for best-predicting iris color, we selected sets of SNPs by parsing P values among possible combinations and identified four discontinuous and non-overlapping sets across the LD blocks (p-Selected SNP sets). In a second, partially overlapping sample of 1,072, samples with matching diplotypes comprised of these p-Selected OCA2 SNPs exhibited a rate of C concordance of 96.3% (n = 82), which was significantly greater than that obtained from randomly selected samples (62.6%, n = 246, P&lt;0.0001). In contrast, the rate of C concordance using diplotypes comprised of the 11 identified hap-tags was only 83.7%, and that obtained using diplotypes comprised of all 33 SNPs organized as contiguous sets along the locus (defined by the LD block structure) was only 93.3%. These results confirm that OCA2 is the major human iris color gene and suggest that using an empirical database-driven system, genotypes from a modest number of SNPs within this gene can be used to accurately predict iris melanin content from DNA.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Multilocus OCA2 genotypes specify human iris colors.</str>
    <str name="id">17619204</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Autosomal recessive ocular albinism (AROA) is a group of genetic disorders in which reduced pigmentation of the eye is associated with decreased visual acuity, nystagmus, strabismus, and photophobia, although pigmentation of skin and hair is relatively normal. Previous studies have shown that AROA in some cases constitutes a clinically mild presentation of oculocutaneous albinism (OCA), due to mutations in either the TYR (OCA1) or OCA2 (P) genes. The purpose of this study was to characterize the relative prevalence of different genetic forms of AROA, and to characterize a sample repertoire of gene mutations in a large series of Caucasian patients with AROA.</str>
      <str>Thirty-six unrelated Caucasian patients carrying the clinical diagnosis of AROA were studied by DNA sequence analysis of the four classic OCA genes: TYR, OCA2 (P), TYRP1, and SLC45A2 (MATP), as appropriate. In all patients with no apparent pathologic mutations in these genes, DNA sequence analysis was performed of a candidate OCA gene, SILV, and the two genes most often involved in Hermansky-Pudlak syndrome, HPS1 and HPS4, the most frequent syndromic form of OCA.</str>
      <str>TYR gene mutations were identified in 20 (56%) patients, OCA2 mutations in 3 (8%), mutations in both TYR and OCA2 in 2 (6%), and possible TYRP1 mutations in 2 (6%). In at least nine patients, no mutations were found in any of the genes studied. Almost all patients with OCA1-related AROA were compound heterozygous for severe OCA1 mutant alleles and the common R402Q variant.</str>
      <str>Most patients with AROA represent phenotypically mild variants of OCA, well over half of which is OCA1.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">A comprehensive genetic study of autosomal recessive ocular albinism in Caucasian patients.</str>
    <str name="id">18326704</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Oculocutaneous albinism type II (OCA2) is the most common form of albinism in humans. OCA2 has been previously associated with mutations of the P gene, the human homologue to the murine pink-eyed dilution gene. The P gene encodes a 110 kDa protein containing 12 potential membrane spanning domains and is associated with melanosomal membranes. The specific function of the P protein is currently unknown but is thought to be involved in tyrosinase processing and transport. We report nine novel mutations in the P gene associated with OCA2. These include two missense mutations, c.1938A&gt;C (p.Ile646Val) and c.1556T&gt;C (p.Val519Ala); one nonsense mutation c.612G&gt;A (p.Trp204X); five frameshift mutations: c.2372_2373delTC, c.1555delG, c.1938_1939insC, c.2050delT, and c.1045_1046delAT; and a splice site mutation c.1951+1G&gt;A. We also report 12 novel polymorphisms including one amino acid substitution, c.2365_2366GC&gt;CA (p.Ala789Glu). At present, there is no functional assay to determine if a mutation is truly pathogenic. The presence of numerous polymorphisms of the P gene in the coding region, several of which result in amino acid substitutions, makes molecular diagnosis problematic. To ensure accurate molecular diagnosis, further mutational analysis will be necessary to produce a comprehensive list of mutations associated with OCA2. This information will also help define the critical functional domains of the P protein. Mutations associated with OCA2 can be found in the Albinism Database (http://albinismdb.med.umn.edu).</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">P gene mutations associated with oculocutaneous albinism type II (OCA2).</str>
    <str name="id">15712365</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Recessive mutations of the mouse p (pink-eyed dilution) gene lead to hypopigmentation of the eyes, skin, and fur. Mice lacking a functional p protein have pink eyes and light gray fur (if non-agouti) or cream-colored fur (if agouti). The human orthologue is the P protein. Humans lacking a functional P protein have oculocutaneous albinism type 2 (OCA2). Melanocytes from p-deficient mice or OCA2 individuals contain small, minimally pigmented melanosomes. The mouse and human proteins are predicted to have 12 membrane spanning domains and possess significant sequence homology to a number of membrane transport proteins, some of which are involved in the transport of anions. The p protein has been localized to the melanosome membrane. Recently, it has been shown that melanosomes from p protein-deficient melanocytes have an abnormal pH. Melanosomes in cultured melanocytes derived from wild-type mice are typically acidic, whereas melanosomes from p protein-deficient mice are non-acidic. Melanosomes and related endosome-derived organelles (i.e., lysosomes) are thought to have an adenosine triphosphate (ATP)-driven proton pump that helps to generate an acidic lumen. To compensate for the charge of these protons, anions must also be transported to the lumen of the melanosome. In light of these observations, a model of p protein function is presented in which the p protein, together with the ATP-driven proton pump, regulates the pH of the melanosome.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The mouse p (pink-eyed dilution) and human P genes, oculocutaneous albinism type 2 (OCA2), and melanosomal pH.</str>
    <str name="id">11310796</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The purpose of this study was to identify the molecular basis of albinism in a large cohort of Italian patients showing typical ocular landmarks of the disease and to provide a full characterization of the clinical ophthalmic manifestations.</str>
      <str>DNA samples from 45 patients with ocular manifestations of albinism were analyzed by direct sequencing analysis of five genes responsible for albinism: TYR, P, TYRP1, SLC45A2 (MATP), and OA1. All patients studied showed a variable degree of skin and hair hypopigmentation. Eighteen patients with distinct mutations in each gene associated with OCA were evaluated by detailed ophthalmic analysis, optical coherence tomography (OCT), and fundus autofluorescence.</str>
      <str>Disease-causing mutations were identified in more than 95% of analyzed patients with OCA (28/45 [62.2%] cases with two or more mutations; 15/45 [33.3%] cases with one mutation). Thirty-five different mutant alleles were identified of which 15 were novel. Mutations in TYR were the most frequent (73.3%), whereas mutations in P occurred more rarely (13.3%) than previously reported. Novel mutations were also identified in rare loci such as TYRP1 and MATP. Mutations in the OA1 gene were not detected. Clinical assessment revealed that patients with iris and macular pigmentation had significantly higher visual acuity than did severe hypopigmented phenotypes.</str>
      <str>TYR gene mutations represent a relevant cause of oculocutaneous albinism in Italy, whereas mutations in P present a lower frequency than that found in other populations. Clinical analysis revealed that the severity of the ocular manifestations depends on the degree of retinal pigmentation.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Molecular and clinical characterization of albinism in a large cohort of Italian patients.</str>
    <str name="id">20861488</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Common genetic variation may play an important role in altering lung cancer risk. We conducted a pathway-based candidate gene evaluation to identify genetic variations that may be associated with lung cancer in a population-based case-control study in Xuan Wei, China (122 cases and 111 controls). A total of 1260 single-nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) in 380 candidate genes for lung cancer were successfully genotyped and assigned to one of 10 pathways based on gene ontology. Logistic regression was used to assess the marginal effect of each SNP on lung cancer susceptibility. The minP test was used to identify statistically significant associations at the gene level. Important pathways were identified using a test of proportions and the rank truncated product methods. The cell cycle pathway was found as the most important pathway (P = 0.044) with four genes significantly associated with lung cancer (PLA2G6 minP = 0.001, CCNA2 minP = 0.006, GSK3 beta minP = 0.007 and EGF minP = 0.013), after adjusting for multiple comparisons. Interestingly, most cell cycle genes that were associated with lung cancer in this analysis were concentrated in the AKT signaling pathway, which is essential for regulation of cell cycle progression and cellular survival, and may be important in lung cancer etiology in Xuan Wei. These results should be viewed as exploratory until they are replicated in a larger study.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Pathway-based evaluation of 380 candidate genes and lung cancer susceptibility suggests the importance of the cell cycle pathway.</str>
    <str name="id">18676680</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The high incidence of lung cancer in Xuanwei County, China has been attributed to exposure to indoor smoky coal emissions that contain polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs). The inflammatory response induced by coal smoke components may promote lung tumor development. We studied the association between single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) in genes involved in innate immunity and lung cancer risk in a population-based case-control study (122 cases and 122 controls) in Xuanwei. A total of 1,360 tag SNPs in 149 gene regions were included in the analysis. FCER2 rs7249320 was the most significant SNP (OR: 0.30; 95% CI: 0.16-0.55; P: 0.0001; false discovery rate value, 0.13) for variant carriers. The gene regions ALOX12B/ALOX15B and KLK2 were associated with increased lung cancer risk globally (false discovery rate value &lt;0.15). In addition, there were positive interactions between KLK15 rs3745523 and smoky coal use (OR: 9.40; P-interaction = 0.07) and between FCER2 rs7249320 and KLK2 rs2739476 (OR: 10.77; P-interaction = 0.003). Our results suggest that genetic polymorphisms in innate immunity genes may play a role in the genesis of lung cancer caused by PAH-containing coal smoke. Integrin/receptor and complement pathways as well as IgE regulation are particularly noteworthy.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Polymorphisms in innate immunity genes and lung cancer risk in Xuanwei, China.</str>
    <str name="id">19170196</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Numerous genome-wide scans conducted by genotyping previously ascertained single-nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) have provided candidate signatures for positive selection in various regions of the human genome, including in genes involved in pigmentation traits. However, it is unclear how well the signatures discovered by such haplotype-based test statistics can be reproduced in tests based on full resequencing data. Four genes (oculocutaneous albinism II (OCA2), tyrosinase-related protein 1 (TYRP1), dopachrome tautomerase (DCT), and KIT ligand (KITLG)) implicated in human skin-color variation, have shown evidence for positive selection in Europeans and East Asians in previous SNP-scan data. In the current study, we resequenced 4.7 to 6.7 kb of DNA from each of these genes in Africans, Europeans, East Asians, and South Asians.</str>
      <str>Applying all commonly used neutrality-test statistics for allele frequency distribution to the newly generated sequence data provided conflicting results regarding evidence for positive selection. Previous haplotype-based findings could not be clearly confirmed. Although some tests were marginally significant for some populations and genes, none of them were significant after multiple-testing correction. Combined P values for each gene-population pair did not improve these results. Application of Approximate Bayesian Computation Markov chain Monte Carlo based to these sequence data using a simple forward simulator revealed broad posterior distributions of the selective parameters for all four genes, providing no support for positive selection. However, when we applied this approach to published sequence data on SLC45A2, another human pigmentation candidate gene, we could readily confirm evidence for positive selection, as previously detected with sequence-based and some haplotype-based tests.</str>
      <str>Overall, our data indicate that even genes that are strong biological candidates for positive selection and show reproducible signatures of positive selection in SNP scans do not always show the same replicability of selection signals in other tests, which should be considered in future studies on detecting positive selection in genetic data.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Contrasting signals of positive selection in genes involved in human skin-color variation from tests based on SNP scans and resequencing.</str>
    <str name="id">22133426</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Oculocutaneous albinism (OCA) is caused by reduced or deficient melanin pigmentation in the skin, hair, and eyes. OCA has different phenotypes resulting from mutations in distinct pigmentation genes involved in melanogenesis. OCA type 2 (OCA2), the most common form of OCA, is an autosomal recessive disorder caused by mutations in the P gene, the function(s) of which is controversial. In order to elucidate the mechanism(s) involved in OCA2, our group used several antibodies specific for various melanosomal proteins (tyrosinase, Tyrp1, Dct, Pmel17 and HMB45), including a specific set of polyclonal antibodies against the p protein. We used confocal immunohistochemistry to compare the processing and distribution of those melanosomal proteins in wild type (melan-a) and in p mutant (melan-p1) melanocytes. Our results indicate that the melanin content of melan-p1 melanocytes was less than 50% that of wild type melan-a melanocytes. In contrast, the tyrosinase activities were similar in extracts of wild type and p mutant melanocytes. Confocal microscopy studies and pulse-chase analyses showed altered processing and sorting of tyrosinase, which is released from melan-p1 cells to the medium. Processing and sorting of Tyrp1 was also altered to some extent. However, Dct and Pmel17 expression and subcellular localization were similar in melan-a and in melan-p1 melanocytes. In melan-a cells, the p protein showed mainly a perinuclear pattern with some staining in the cytoplasm where some co-localization with HMB45 antibody was observed. These findings suggest that the p protein plays a major role in modulating the intracellular transport of tyrosinase and a minor role for Tyrp1, but is not critically involved in the transport of Dct and Pmel17. This study provides a basis to understand the relationship of the p protein with tyrosinase function and melanin synthesis, and also provides a rational approach to unveil the consequences of P gene mutations in the pathogenesis of OCA2.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The etiology of oculocutaneous albinism (OCA) type II: the pink protein modulates the processing and transport of tyrosinase.</str>
    <str name="id">12028586</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The CDKN2A gene is regarded as the major familial malignant melanoma (MM) susceptibility gene. Human pigmentation is one of the main modulators of individual risk of developing MM. Therefore, the genes involved in the determination of skin colour and tanning response are potentially implicated in MM predisposition and may be useful predictors of MM risk in the general population. The human melanocortin-1 receptor gene (MC1R) plays a crucial role in pigmentation and also appears to be important in MM. The OCA2 gene has emerged as a new and significant determinant of human iris colour variation. We present a case-control study in Spanish population including 390 consecutive patients with melanoma and 254 control subjects. Sequence analysis of the entire coding region and genotyping of 5 tag-SNPs in the genomic region of MC1R was performed. We identified 27 variants, two reaching statistical significance [R160W (OR: 4.18, 95% CI: 1.24-14.04, P = 0.02) and D294H (OR: 3.10, 95% CI: 1.37-7.01, P = 0.01)] and we detected two novel non-synonymous changes: V92L and T308M. Odds ratio for carrying two functional variants was 4.25 (95% CI: 2.30-7.84, P = 3.63 x 10(-6)). Haplotypes of the entire MC1R region have been established, and we observed an enrichment of a rare European haplotype similar to African values carrying variants V92M and I155T. In addition, three potentially functional SNPs were selected in p16/CDKN2A and in the promoter region of OCA2/HERC2. Our data for CDKN2A gene did not reach statistically significant results for any of the two studied alleles. We found that the variant allele A &gt; G of OCA2/HERC2 (rs12913832) was associated with pigmentation features: eye, hair and skin colour; P-values = 1.8 x 10(-29), 9.2 x 10(-16), 1.1 x 10(-3), respectively, validating previous results.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Genetic analysis of three important genes in pigmentation and melanoma susceptibility: CDKN2A, MC1R and HERC2/OCA2.</str>
    <str name="id">20629734</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Ancestry informative markers (AIMs) are genetic loci showing alleles with large frequency differences between populations. AIMs can be used to estimate biogeographical ancestry at the level of the population, subgroup (e.g. cases and controls) and individual. Ancestry estimates at both the subgroup and individual level can be directly instructive regarding the genetics of the phenotypes that differ qualitatively or in frequency between populations. These estimates can provide a compelling foundation for the use of admixture mapping (AM) methods to identify the genes underlying these traits. We present details of a panel of 34 AIMs and demonstrate how such studies can proceed, by using skin pigmentation as a model phenotype. We have genotyped these markers in two population samples with primarily African ancestry, viz. African Americans from Washington D.C. and an African Caribbean sample from Britain, and in a sample of European Americans from Pennsylvania. In the two African population samples, we observed significant correlations between estimates of individual ancestry and skin pigmentation as measured by reflectometry (R(2)=0.21, P&lt;0.0001 for the African-American sample and R(2)=0.16, P&lt;0.0001 for the British African-Caribbean sample). These correlations confirm the validity of the ancestry estimates and also indicate the high level of population structure related to admixture, a level that characterizes these populations and that is detectable by using other tests to identify genetic structure. We have also applied two methods of admixture mapping to test for the effects of three candidate genes (TYR, OCA2, MC1R) on pigmentation. We show that TYR and OCA2 have measurable effects on skin pigmentation differences between the west African and west European parental populations. This work indicates that it is possible to estimate the individual ancestry of a person based on DNA analysis with a reasonable number of well-defined genetic markers. The implications and applications of ancestry estimates in biomedical research are discussed.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Skin pigmentation, biogeographical ancestry and admixture mapping.</str>
    <str name="id">12579416</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Albinism is a group of genetic disorders, showing a broad spectrum of different phenotypes. The purpose of this study was to screen known candidate genes for oculocutaneous albinism (OCA) and ocular albinism (OA) mutations in Indian patients.</str>
      <str>Blood samples were collected from 23 probands and 13 affected family members from 23 genetically unrelated Indian families (22 diagnosed as OCA and 1 diagnosed as OA) and analyzed by bidirectional DNA sequencing of the classic OCA genes--tyrosinase (TYR, or oculocutaneous albinism IA), pink eyed dilution (P; or oculocutaneous albinism II (OCA2]), tyrosinase-related protein 1 (TYRP1), solute carrier family 45, member 2 (SLC45A2; or membrane-associated transporter protein [MATP])--and the OA1 gene, G protein-coupled receptor 143 (GPR143).</str>
      <str>Three missense mutations, c. 715 C&gt;T (R239W), c. 896 G&gt;A (R299H), c.1255 G&gt;A (G419R), and one termination c. 832 C&gt;T (R278X), were identified in TYR, as well as one novel mutation, c.1453 G&gt;A (G485R) in P. One novel single nucleotide polymorphism (SNP) was identified in both TYR and P; few reported SNPs were identified. The G&gt;A base substitution caused relatively conservative amino acid changes, which altered glycine to arginine residues within the topological domain. The novel OCA2 mutation was not present in 100 control samples. This study identified two probands carrying mutations alone, 16 probands carrying SNPs alone, 4 probands carrying both mutations and SNPs and only one proband carrying neither mutations nor SNPs.</str>
      <str>Although sequence analysis was performed with all five candidate genes, only four (17.39%) of the 23 probands showed mutations in TYR and 2 probands (8.69%) showed an unreported novel mutation in P. Genetic counseling for phenotypical diagnosis and genetic mutation screening of these genes will help to minimize the incidence of OCA and OA in future generations.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Spectrum of candidate gene mutations associated with Indian familial oculocutaneous and ocular albinism.</str>
    <str name="id">20806075</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>An isolated form of congenital cataract associated with macular hypoplasia and a generally hypopigmented fundus in infancy was observed in a German family. To test the hypothesis that a de-novo mutation had occurred in one of the parental germ lines, a functional candidate gene approach was applied.</str>
      <str>The family was carefully examined by a senior paediatric ophthalmologist according to routine procedures (slit lamp, funduscopy, ERG). Blood was taken from the proband and his parents, genomic DNA was isolated and some candidate genes for cataract (CRYAA, CRYBB2, GJA8) or macular hypoplasia (OA1, P) or both (PAX6) were analyzed.</str>
      <str>The proband showed bilateral cataracts at the age of 4 months; the fundus appeared pale, the optic disc grayish, and macular reflexes were absent. After cataract surgery, the nystagmus persisted, and a control ERG at age 9 years showed essentially normal scotopic and photopic wave forms. An infectious aetiology as well as galactosemia were excluded. However, a heterozygous mutation was found in the proband in exon 1 of CRYAA (62 C--&gt;T), which leads to an exchange from Arg to Leu at amino acid position 21 (R21L). This sequence alteration was not found in the parents and in 96 randomly selected DNA samples from ophthalmologically normal individuals of the KORA S4 study population. In addition, two heterozygous mutations in P were identified (R419Q and A481T); one of both was present in each of the unaffected parents.</str>
      <str>Based upon the unique finding of the mutation and the expression of CRYAA in the lens, this R21L mutation in the CRYAA is considered to be causative for the dominant cataract phenotype. Moreover, the macular hypoplasia has to be considered a concerted interaction with compound heterozygous mutations in the P gene manifesting a mild form of oculocutaneous albinism. Nevertheless, this combination is rare and future studies will focus on identifying similar phenotypes.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Congenital cataract and macular hypoplasia in humans associated with a de novo mutation in CRYAA and compound heterozygous mutations in P.</str>
    <str name="id">16453125</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>We have previously shown that a quantitative-trait locus linked to the OCA2 region of 15q accounts for 74% of variation in human eye color. We conducted additional genotyping to clarify the role of the OCA2 locus in the inheritance of eye color and other pigmentary traits associated with skin-cancer risk in white populations. Fifty-eight synonymous and nonsynonymous exonic single-nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) and tagging SNPs were typed in a collection of 3,839 adolescent twins, their siblings, and their parents. The highest association for blue/nonblue eye color was found with three OCA2 SNPs: rs7495174 T/C, rs6497268 G/T, and rs11855019 T/C (P values of 1.02x10(-61), 1.57x10(-96), and 4.45x10(-54), respectively) in intron 1. These three SNPs are in one major haplotype block, with TGT representing 78.4% of alleles. The TGT/TGT diplotype found in 62.2% of samples was the major genotype seen to modify eye color, with a frequency of 0.905 in blue or green compared with only 0.095 in brown eye color. This genotype was also at highest frequency in subjects with light brown hair and was more frequent in fair and medium skin types, consistent with the TGT haplotype acting as a recessive modifier of lighter pigmentary phenotypes. Homozygotes for rs11855019 C/C were predominantly without freckles and had lower mole counts. The minor population impact of the nonsynonymous coding-region polymorphisms Arg305Trp and Arg419Gln associated with nonblue eyes and the tight linkage of the major TGT haplotype within the intron 1 of OCA2 with blue eye color and lighter hair and skin tones suggest that differences within the 5' proximal regulatory control region of the OCA2 gene alter expression or messenger RNA-transcript levels and may be responsible for these associations.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">A three-single-nucleotide polymorphism haplotype in intron 1 of OCA2 explains most human eye-color variation.</str>
    <str name="id">17236130</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Oculocutaneous albinism (OCA) is an inherited disorder resulting in hypopigmentation of the skin, hair, and eyes. OCA type 2 (tyrosinase-positive) is the most common recessively inherited disorder among southern African Blacks. OCA2 is also seen in southern African Caucasoids, but is less frequent. The gene responsible for this type of albinism, P, is the human homolog of the mouse pink-eyed dilution gene. Mutations at this locus are also responsible for the milder hypopigmentation phenotype seen in individuals with brown oculocutaneous albinism (BOCA). A common African P mutation was identified in Black OCA2 individuals, and has since been shown to occur in Black individuals with brown OCA as well. This mutation is a 2.7 kb interstitial deletion. In this study, we undertook to screen the coding region of the P gene for mutations in the non-2.7 kb deletion alleles of OCA2 patients who did not carry the deletion allele in either one or both of their P genes. We identified four mutations (A334V, 614delA, 683insG [corrected], 727insG) in a group of 39 unrelated Black OCA2 patients with a total of 52 non-2.7 kb deletion OCA2 genes. When taking all OCA2 cases into consideration, including those homozygous for the 2.7 kb deletion mutation, these account for a further 1.7% of OCA2 mutations in southern African Blacks, increasing the overall mutation detection rate to 78.7%. Three mutations (E678K, L688F, I370T) were identified in a group of 15 Black patients with an initially unclassified type of OCA and another three mutations (IVS 14-2 (a--&gt;g), V350M, P743L) were identified in nine Caucasoid OCA patients. Relatively few mutations, all with low frequency, were identified in the non-2.7 kb deletion OCA genes. We propose that other mutations may lie either within intronic sequence or within the promoter region of the gene.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Identification of P gene mutations in individuals with oculocutaneous albinism in sub-Saharan Africa.</str>
    <str name="id">10649493</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Aiming to identify novel genetic loci for pigmentation and skin cancer, we conducted a series of genome-wide association studies on hair color, eye color, number of sunburns, tanning ability and number of non-melanoma skin cancers (NMSCs) among 10 183 European Americans in the discovery stage and 4504 European Americans in the replication stage (for eye color, 3871 males in the discovery stage and 2496 males in the replication stage). We targeted novel chromosome regions besides the known ones for replication. As a result, we identified a new region downstream of the EDNRB gene on 13q22 associated with hair color and the strongest association was the single-nucleotide polymorphism (SNP) rs975739 (P = 2.4 × 10(-14); P = 5.4 × 10(-9) in the discovery set and P = 1.2 × 10(-6) in the replication set). Using blue, intermediate (including green) and brown eye colors as co-dominant outcomes, we identified the SNP rs3002288 in VASH2 on 1q32.3 associated with brown eye (P = 7.0 × 10(-8); P = 5.3 × 10(-5) in the discovery set and P = 0.02 in the replication set). Additionally, we identified a significant interaction between the SNPs rs7173419 and rs12913832 in the OCA2 gene region on brown eye color (P-value for interaction = 3.8 × 10(-3)). As for the number of NMSCs, we identified two independent SNPs on chr6 and one SNP on chromosome 14: rs12203592 in IRF4 (P = 7.2 × 10(-14); P = 1.8 × 10(-8) in the discovery set and P = 6.7 × 10(-7) in the replication set), rs12202284 between IRF4 and EXOC2 (P = 5.0 × 10(-8); P = 6.6 × 10(-7) in the discovery set and P = 3.0 × 10(-3) in the replication set) and rs8015138 upstream of GNG2 (P = 6.6 × 10(-8); P = 5.3 × 10(-7) in the discovery set and P = 0.01 in the replication set). </str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Genome-wide association studies identify several new loci associated with pigmentation traits and skin cancer risk in European Americans.</str>
    <str name="id">23548203</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Traditional prognostic factors for survival and treatment response of patients with breast cancer do not fully account for observed survival variation. We used available genotype data from a previously conducted two-stage, breast cancer susceptibility genome-wide association study (ie, Studies of Epidemiology and Risk factors in Cancer Heredity [SEARCH]) to investigate associations between variation in germline DNA and overall survival.</str>
      <str>We evaluated possible associations between overall survival after a breast cancer diagnosis and 10 621 germline single-nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) from up to 3761 patients with invasive breast cancer (including 647 deaths and 26 978 person-years at risk) that were genotyped previously in the SEARCH study with high-density oligonucleotide microarrays (ie, hypothesis-generating set). Associations with all-cause mortality were assessed for each SNP by use of Cox regression analysis, generating a per rare allele hazard ratio (HR). To validate putative associations, we used patient genotype information that had been obtained with 5' nuclease assay or mass spectrometry and overall survival information for up to 14 096 patients with invasive breast cancer (including 2303 deaths and 70 019 person-years at risk) from 15 international case-control studies (ie, validation set). Fixed-effects meta-analysis was used to generate an overall effect estimate in the validation dataset and in combined SEARCH and validation datasets. All statistical tests were two-sided.</str>
      <str>In the hypothesis-generating dataset, SNP rs4778137 (C&gt;G) of the OCA2 gene at 15q13.1 was statistically significantly associated with overall survival among patients with estrogen receptor-negative tumors, with the rare G allele being associated with increased overall survival (HR of death per rare allele carried = 0.56, 95% confidence interval [CI] = 0.41 to 0.75, P = 9.2 x 10(-5)). This association was also observed in the validation dataset (HR of death per rare allele carried = 0.88, 95% CI = 0.78 to 0.99, P = .03) and in the combined dataset (HR of death per rare allele carried = 0.82, 95% CI = 0.73 to 0.92, P = 5 x 10(-4)).</str>
      <str>The rare G allele of the OCA2 polymorphism, rs4778137, may be associated with improved overall survival among patients with estrogen receptor-negative breast cancer.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Association between a germline OCA2 polymorphism at chromosome 15q13.1 and estrogen receptor-negative breast cancer survival.</str>
    <str name="id">20308648</str></doc>
</result>
</response>
