<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<response>

<lst name="responseHeader">
  <int name="status">0</int>
  <int name="QTime">0</int>
  <lst name="params">
    <str name="q">8066462
7820546
12388758
2306472
1888762
23018640
22659184
11745344
14733938
12376572
9311996
11205743
7811265
15887188
17948026
21320693
8811196
14550573
12419264
10893419
9079628
14614829
12920286
12914693
12840737
12830140
12750511
12719574
9846577
9811770
14557625
14528301
14528300
14527406
12970355
12809610
12808466
12808465
18922472
12167863
17323924
14564014
12859895
12791267
19013454
15029244
19193609
11285280
23503661
21987572
22505724
18457437
24816145
22119785
21963094
21906983
21890473
21139048
18854154
16196087
21319273
21630459
22190034
22623428
20458337
21565611
19738201
19615732
19056867
22863883
16169070
21145461
23376485
22939629
26344197
26186194
15489334
12477932
</str>
    <str name="indent">true</str>
    <str name="fl">id, medline_article_title, medline_abstract_text</str>
    <str name="rows">105</str>
    <str name="wt">xml</str>
  </lst>
</lst>
<result name="response" numFound="78" start="0">
  <doc>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Good to CU.</str>
    <str name="id">12840737</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <str name="medline_article_title">DNA deamination: not just a trigger for antibody diversification but also a mechanism for defense against retroviruses.</str>
    <str name="id">12830140</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Virology. Weapons of mutational destruction.</str>
    <str name="id">12920286</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Hypermutation of HIV-1 DNA in the absence of the Vif protein.</str>
    <str name="id">12750511</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>A human gene with potent antiretroviral activity has recently been found to encode a new member of the family of cytidine deaminases, previously known to be involved in mRNA editing, immunoglobulin gene class switching, and immunoglobulin gene hypermutation. The enzyme attacks viral DNA as it is synthesized in infected cells and prevents the formation of functional proviruses. The Vif gene of HIV-1 blocks this host restriction and so allows virus replication.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Death by deamination: a novel host restriction system for HIV-1.</str>
    <str name="id">12914693</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Interactomes are often measured using affinity purification-mass spectrometry (AP-MS) or yeast two-hybrid approaches, but these methods do not provide stoichiometric or temporal information. We combine quantitative proteomics and size-exclusion chromatography to map 291 coeluting complexes. This method allows mapping of an interactome to the same depth and accuracy as AP-MS with less work and without overexpression or tagging. The use of triplex labeling enables monitoring of interactome rearrangements.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">A high-throughput approach for measuring temporal changes in the interactome.</str>
    <str name="id">22863883</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Human proteasomes consist of 14 major subunits which can be resolved by two-dimensional polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis. Tryptic peptides from the subunits were sequenced. This allowed identification of all proteins in two-dimensional electrophoresis gels with proteasome subunits whose sequences are known from cDNA. The results also precisely define the specificity of a panel of subunit-specific monoclonal antibodies. A new proteasome subunit (Z) was discovered. In contrast, the putative subunit MECL-1 could not be detected in human placenta proteasomes.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Human proteasome subunits from 2-dimensional gels identified by partial sequencing.</str>
    <str name="id">7811265</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Macromolecular complexes are essential to conserved biological processes, but their prevalence across animals is unclear. By combining extensive biochemical fractionation with quantitative mass spectrometry, here we directly examined the composition of soluble multiprotein complexes among diverse metazoan models. Using an integrative approach, we generated a draft conservation map consisting of more than one million putative high-confidence co-complex interactions for species with fully sequenced genomes that encompasses functional modules present broadly across all extant animals. Clustering reveals a spectrum of conservation, ranging from ancient eukaryotic assemblies that have probably served cellular housekeeping roles for at least one billion years, ancestral complexes that have accrued contemporary components, and rarer metazoan innovations linked to multicellularity. We validated these projections by independent co-fractionation experiments in evolutionarily distant species, affinity purification and functional analyses. The comprehensiveness, centrality and modularity of these reconstructed interactomes reflect their fundamental mechanistic importance and adaptive value to animal cell systems. </str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Panorama of ancient metazoan macromolecular complexes.</str>
    <str name="id">26344197</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The National Institutes of Health Mammalian Gene Collection (MGC) Program is a multiinstitutional effort to identify and sequence a cDNA clone containing a complete ORF for each human and mouse gene. ESTs were generated from libraries enriched for full-length cDNAs and analyzed to identify candidate full-ORF clones, which then were sequenced to high accuracy. The MGC has currently sequenced and verified the full ORF for a nonredundant set of &gt;9,000 human and &gt;6,000 mouse genes. Candidate full-ORF clones for an additional 7,800 human and 3,500 mouse genes also have been identified. All MGC sequences and clones are available without restriction through public databases and clone distribution networks (see http:mgc.nci.nih.gov).</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Generation and initial analysis of more than 15,000 full-length human and mouse cDNA sequences.</str>
    <str name="id">12477932</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Protein ubiquitylation contributes to the regulation of many cellular processes including protein degradation, receptor internalization, and repair of DNA damage. We now present a comprehensive characterization of ubiquitin-conjugated and ubiquitin-associated proteins in human cells. The proteins were purified by immunoaffinity chromatography under denaturing or native conditions. They were then digested with trypsin, and the resulting peptides were analyzed by 2-D LC and MS/MS. A total of 670 distinct proteins were identified; 345 proteins (51%) were classified as Urp-D (ubiquitin-related proteome under the denaturing condition) and comprised ubiquitin-conjugated molecules, whereas 325 proteins (49%) were classified as Urp-N (ubiquitin-related proteome only under the native condition) and included molecules that associated with ubiquitylated proteins. The proportions of proteins in various functional categories differed substantially between Urp-D and Urp-N. Many ribosomal subunits were detected in the Urp-D group of proteins and several of these subunits were directly shown to be ubiquitylated by mass spectrometric analysis, suggesting that ubiquitylation might play an important role in the regulation and/or quality control of ribosomal proteins. Our results demonstrate the potential of proteomics analysis of protein ubiquitylation to provide important insight into the regulation of protein stability and other ubiquitin-related cellular functions.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Large-scale analysis of the human ubiquitin-related proteome.</str>
    <str name="id">16196087</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Generating a catalogue of sperm nuclear proteins is an important first step towards the clarification of the function of the paternal chromatin transmitted to the oocyte upon fertilization. With this goal, sperm nuclei were obtained through CTAB treatment and isolated to over 99.9% purity without any tail fragments, acrosome or mitochondria as assessed by optical microscopy and transmission electron microscopy. The nuclear proteins were extracted and separated in 2-D and 1-D gels and the 2-D spots and 1-D bands were excised and analysed to identify the proteins through LC-MS/MS. With this approach, 403 different proteins have been identified from the isolated sperm nuclei. The most abundant family of proteins identified are the histones, for which several novel members had not been reported previously as present in the spermatogenic cell line or in the human mature spermatozoa. More than half (52.6%) of the proteins had not been detected in the previous human whole sperm cell proteome reports. Of relevance, several chromatin-related proteins, such as zinc fingers and transcription factors, so far not known to be associated with the sperm chromatin, have also been detected. This provides additional information about the nuclear proteins that are potentially relevant for epigenetic marking, proper fertilization and embryo development.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Proteomic characterization of the human sperm nucleus.</str>
    <str name="id">21630459</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The human immunodeficiency virus-1 (HIV-1) Tat protein was previously reported to compete the association of PA28 regulator with the alpha rings of the 20S proteasome and to inhibit its peptidase activity. However, the distinct interaction sites within the proteasome complex remained to be determined. Here we show that HIV-1 Tat binds to alpha4 and alpha7, six beta subunits of the constitutive 20S proteasome and the interferon-gamma-inducible subunits beta2i and beta5i. A Tat-proteasome interaction can also be demonstrated in vivo and leads to inhibition of proteasomal activity. This indicates that Tat can modulate or interfere with cellular proteasome function by specific interaction with distinct proteasomal subunits.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Human immunodeficiency virus-1 Tat protein interacts with distinct proteasomal alpha and beta subunits.</str>
    <str name="id">14550573</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Cullin-RING ligases (CRLs) represent the largest E3 ubiquitin ligase family in eukaryotes, and the identification of their substrates is critical to understanding regulation of the proteome. Using genetic and pharmacologic Cullin inactivation coupled with genetic (GPS) and proteomic (QUAINT) assays, we have identified hundreds of proteins whose stabilities or ubiquitylation status are regulated by CRLs. Together, these approaches yielded many known CRL substrates as well as a multitude of previously unknown putative substrates. We demonstrate that one substrate, NUSAP1, is an SCF(Cyclin F) substrate during S and G2 phases of the cell cycle and is also degraded in response to DNA damage. This collection of regulated substrates is highly enriched for nodes in protein interaction networks, representing critical connections between regulatory pathways. This demonstrates the broad role of CRL ubiquitylation in all aspects of cellular biology and provides a set of proteins likely to be key indicators of cellular physiology.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Global identification of modular cullin-RING ligase substrates.</str>
    <str name="id">21963094</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Urine results from a coordinated activity of glomerular and tubular compartments of the kidney. As a footprint of these cellular functional processes, urinary exosomes, and 40-80 nm membrane vesicles released after fusion with the plasma membrane into the extracellular environment by renal epithelial cells, are a source for identification of proteins and investigation of their role in the kidney. The aim of the present study was the identification of podocyte exosome proteins based on urine immunoabsorption using podocyte-specific CR1-immunocoated beads followed by proteomic analysis using LC MS/MS techniques. This methodology allowed the identification of 1195 proteins. By using a bioinformatic approach, 27 brain-expressed proteins were identified, in which 14 out of them were newly demonstrated to be expressed in the kidney at a mRNA level, and, one of them, the COMT protein, was demonstrated to be expressed in podocytes at a protein level. These results, attesting the reliability of the methodology to identify podocyte proteins, need now to be completed by further experiments to analyze more precisely their biological function(s) in the podocytes.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Proteomic analysis of podocyte exosome-enriched fraction from normal human urine.</str>
    <str name="id">23376485</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Macropain (proteasome) is a high-molecular-weight proteinase complex composed of at least 13 electrophoretically distinct subunits. Previous work, including peptide mapping and limited amino acid sequencing, suggested that most of the subunits belong to an evolutionarily related group of different gene products (Lee et al. (1990) Biochim. Biophys. Acta. 1037, 178-185). In order to define the extent and pattern of subunit relatedness, and to determine the structural basis for possible similarities and differences in subunit functions, we are deducing the primary structures of macropain subunits by cDNA cloning and DNA sequence analysis. We report here the primary structures of four subunits. The data clearly demonstrate that the proteins represent different, but homologous gene products. Surprisingly, no evidence for homology with any other protein, including proteinases, was obtained. These results suggest that macropain is comprised of a previously unidentified family of evolutionarily related polypeptides. Because biochemical data indicate that macropain contains several different proteinase activities, the current results raise the possibility that the macropain complex is composed of a group of novel proteinases, distinct from those of other structurally identifiable proteinase families.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The primary structures of four subunits of the human, high-molecular-weight proteinase, macropain (proteasome), are distinct but homologous.</str>
    <str name="id">1888762</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Deubiquitinating enzymes (Dubs) function to remove covalently attached ubiquitin from proteins, thereby controlling substrate activity and/or abundance. For most Dubs, their functions, targets, and regulation are poorly understood. To systematically investigate Dub function, we initiated a global proteomic analysis of Dubs and their associated protein complexes. This was accomplished through the development of a software platform called CompPASS, which uses unbiased metrics to assign confidence measurements to interactions from parallel nonreciprocal proteomic data sets. We identified 774 candidate interacting proteins associated with 75 Dubs. Using Gene Ontology, interactome topology classification, subcellular localization, and functional studies, we link Dubs to diverse processes, including protein turnover, transcription, RNA processing, DNA damage, and endoplasmic reticulum-associated degradation. This work provides the first glimpse into the Dub interaction landscape, places previously unstudied Dubs within putative biological pathways, and identifies previously unknown interactions and protein complexes involved in this increasingly important arm of the ubiquitin-proteasome pathway.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Defining the human deubiquitinating enzyme interaction landscape.</str>
    <str name="id">19615732</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The quality control of proteins mediated by the plasticity of the proteasome system is regulated by the timely and flexible formation of this multisubunit proteolytic enzyme complex. Adaptable biogenesis of the 20S proteasome core complex is therefore of vital importance for adjusting to changing proteolytic requirements. However, the molecular mechanism and the cellular sites of mammalian proteasome formation are still unresolved. By using precursor complex-specific antibodies, we now show that the main steps in 20S core complex formation take place at the endoplasmic reticulum (ER). Thereby, the proteasome maturation protein (POMP)--an essential factor of mammalian proteasome biogenesis--interacts with ER membranes, binds to alpha1-7 rings, recruits beta-subunits stepwise and mediates the association of mammalian precursor complexes with the ER. Thus, POMP facilitates the main steps in 20S core complex formation at the ER to coordinate the assembly process and to provide cells with freshly formed proteasomes at their site of function.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The proteasome maturation protein POMP facilitates major steps of 20S proteasome formation at the endoplasmic reticulum.</str>
    <str name="id">17948026</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Integrin adhesion receptors mediate cell-cell and cell-extracellular matrix interactions, which control cell morphology and migration, differentiation, and tissue integrity. Integrins recruit multimolecular adhesion complexes to their cytoplasmic domains, which provide structural and mechanosensitive signaling connections between the extracellular and intracellular milieux. The different functions of specific integrin heterodimers, such as α4β1 and α5β1, have been attributed to distinct signal transduction mechanisms that are initiated by selective recruitment of adhesion complex components to integrin cytoplasmic tails. Here, we report the isolation of ligand-induced adhesion complexes associated with wild-type α4β1 integrin, an activated α4β1 variant in the absence of the α cytoplasmic domain (X4C0), and a chimeric α4β1 variant with α5 leg and cytoplasmic domains (α4Pα5L), and the cataloguing of their proteomes by MS. Using hierarchical clustering and interaction network analyses, we detail the differential recruitment of proteins and highlight enrichment patterns of proteins to distinct adhesion complexes. We identify previously unreported components of integrin adhesion complexes and observe receptor-specific enrichment of molecules with previously reported links to cell migration and cell signaling processes. Furthermore, we demonstrate colocalization of MYO18A with active integrin in migrating cells. These datasets provide a resource for future studies of integrin receptor-specific signaling events.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Proteomic analysis of α4β1 integrin adhesion complexes reveals α-subunit-dependent protein recruitment.</str>
    <str name="id">22623428</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Human immunodeficiency virus type-1 (HIV-1) integrase catalyzes the irreversible insertion of the viral genome into host chromosomal DNA. We have developed a mammalian expression system for the synthesis of authentic HIV-1 integrase in the absence of other viral proteins. Integrase, which bears a N-terminal phenylalanine, was found to be a short-lived protein in human embryo kidney 293T cells. The degradation of integrase could be suppressed by proteasome inhibitors. N-terminal phenylalanine is recognized as a degradation signal by a ubiquitin-proteasome proteolytic system known as the N-end rule pathway. The replacement of N-terminal phenylalanine with methionine, valine, or glycine, which are stabilizing residues in the N-end rule, resulted in metabolically stabilized integrase proteins (half-life of N-terminal Met-integrase was at least 3 h). Conversely, the substitution of N-terminal phenylalanine with other destabilizing residues retained the metabolic instability of integrase. These findings indicate that the HIV-1 integrase is a physiological substrate of the N-end rule. We discuss a possible functional similarity to the better understood turnover of the bacteriophage Mu transposase and functions of integrase instability to the maintenance and integrity of the host cell genome.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Degradation of HIV-1 integrase by the N-end rule pathway.</str>
    <str name="id">10893419</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The proteasomal system consists of a proteolytic core, the 20 S proteasome, which associates in an ATP-dependent reaction with the 19 S regulatory complex to form the functional 26 S proteasome. In the absence of ATP, the 20 S proteasome forms a complex with the gamma-interferon-inducible 11 S regulator. Both the 20 S proteasome and the 11 S regulator have been implied in the generation of antigenic peptides. The human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)-1 Tat protein causes a number of different effects during acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS). Here we show that HIV-1 Tat protein strongly inhibits the peptidase activity of the 20 S proteasome and that it interferes with formation of the 20 S proteasome-11 S regulator complex. In addition, it slightly increases the activity of purified 26 S proteasome. These results may explain the mechanism by which HIV-1-infected cells escape cytotoxic T lymphocyte response and at least in part immunodeficiency in AIDS patients.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">HIV-1 tat inhibits the 20 S proteasome and its 11 S regulator-mediated activation.</str>
    <str name="id">9079628</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The Anaphase-Promoting Complex/Cyclosome (APC/C) ubiquitin ligase mediates degradation of cell cycle proteins during mitosis and G1. Cdc20/Fzy and Cdh1/Fzr are substrate-specific APC/C activators. The level of mammalian Cdh1 is high in mitosis, but it is inactive and does not bind the APC/C. We show that when Cdh1 is active in G1 and G0, its levels are considerably lower and almost all of it is APC/C associated. We demonstrate that Cdh1 is subject to APC/C-specific degradation in G1 and G0, and that this degradation depends upon two RXXL-type destruction boxes. We further demonstrate that addition of Cdh1 to Xenopus interphase extracts, which have an inactive APC/C, activates it to degrade Cdh1. These observations indicate that Cdh1 mediates its own degradation by activating the APC/C to degrade itself. Elevated levels of Cdh1 are deleterious for cell cycle progression in various organisms. This auto-regulation of Cdh1 could thus play a role in ensuring that the level of Cdh1 is reduced during G1 and G0, allowing it to be switched off at the correct time.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Mammalian Cdh1/Fzr mediates its own degradation.</str>
    <str name="id">15029244</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Protein-protein interaction maps provide a valuable framework for a better understanding of the functional organization of the proteome. To detect interacting pairs of human proteins systematically, a protein matrix of 4456 baits and 5632 preys was screened by automated yeast two-hybrid (Y2H) interaction mating. We identified 3186 mostly novel interactions among 1705 proteins, resulting in a large, highly connected network. Independent pull-down and co-immunoprecipitation assays validated the overall quality of the Y2H interactions. Using topological and GO criteria, a scoring system was developed to define 911 high-confidence interactions among 401 proteins. Furthermore, the network was searched for interactions linking uncharacterized gene products and human disease proteins to regulatory cellular pathways. Two novel Axin-1 interactions were validated experimentally, characterizing ANP32A and CRMP1 as modulators of Wnt signaling. Systematic human protein interaction screens can lead to a more comprehensive understanding of protein function and cellular processes.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">A human protein-protein interaction network: a resource for annotating the proteome.</str>
    <str name="id">16169070</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The proteasome is an essential component of the ATP-dependent proteolytic pathway in eukaryotic cells and is responsible for the degradation of most cellular proteins. The 20S (700-kDa) proteasome contains multiple peptidase activities that function through a new type of proteolytic mechanism involving a threonine active site. The 26S (2000-kDa) complex, which degrades ubiquitinated proteins, contains in addition to the 20S proteasome a 19S regulatory complex composed of multiple ATPases and components necessary for binding protein substrates. The proteasome has been highly conserved during eukaryotic evolution, and simpler forms are even found in archaebacteria and eubacteria. Major advances have been achieved recently in our knowledge about the molecular organization of the 20S and 19S particles, their subunits, the proteasome's role in MHC-class 1 antigen presentation, and regulators of its activities. This article focuses on recent progress concerning the biochemical mechanisms and intracellular functions of the 20S and 26S proteasomes.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Structure and functions of the 20S and 26S proteasomes.</str>
    <str name="id">8811196</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Viruses have developed diverse non-immune strategies to counteract host-mediated mechanisms that confer resistance to infection. The Vif (virion infectivity factor) proteins are encoded by primate immunodeficiency viruses, most notably human immunodeficiency virus-1 (HIV-1). These proteins are potent regulators of virus infection and replication and are consequently essential for pathogenic infections in vivo. HIV-1 Vif seems to be required during the late stages of virus production for the suppression of an innate antiviral phenotype that resides in human T lymphocytes. Thus, in the absence of Vif, expression of this phenotype renders progeny virions non-infectious. Here, we describe a unique cellular gene, CEM15, whose transient or stable expression in cells that do not normally express CEM15 recreates this phenotype, but whose antiviral action is overcome by the presence of Vif. Because the Vif:CEM15 regulatory circuit is critical for HIV-1 replication, perturbing the circuit may be a promising target for future HIV/AIDS therapies.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Isolation of a human gene that inhibits HIV-1 infection and is suppressed by the viral Vif protein.</str>
    <str name="id">12167863</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The polo-like kinase (Plk) has been shown to be associated with the anaphase-promoting complex at the transition from metaphase to anaphase and to regulate ubiquitination, the process that targets proteins for degradation by proteasomes. In this study, we have identified proteasomal proteins interacting with Plk by mass spectrometry and found that Plk and 20S proteasome subunits could be reversibly immunoprecipitated from both human CA46 cells and HEK 293 cells transfected with HA-Plk. Furthermore, both coprecipitated Plk and baculovirus-expressed Plk were able to phosphorylate proteasome subunits, and metabolic labeling studies indicate that Plk is partially responsible for the phosphorylation of 20S proteasome subunits C9 and C8 in vivo. In addition, phosphorylation of proteasomes by Plk enhanced proteolytic activity toward an artificial substrate Suc-L-L-V-Y-AMC in vitro and in vivo. Finally, we were also able to detect Plk associated with 26S proteasomes under certain conditions. Together our results suggest that Plk is an important mitotic regulator of proteasome activity.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Polo-like kinase interacts with proteasomes and regulates their activity.</str>
    <str name="id">11205743</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Animal cells have developed many ways to suppress viral replication, and viruses have evolved diverse strategies to resist these. Here we provide evidence that the virion infectivity factor protein of human immunodeficiency virus type 1 (HIV-1) functions to counteract a newly discovered activity in human cells that otherwise inhibits virus replication. This anti-viral phenotype is shown by human T cells, the principal in vivo targets for HIV-1, and, based on our present understanding of virion infectivity factor action, is presumed to act by interfering with a late step(s) in the virus life cycle. These observations indicate that the inhibition of virion infectivity factor function in vivo may prevent HIV-1 replication by 'unmasking' an innate anti-viral phenotype.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Evidence for a newly discovered cellular anti-HIV-1 phenotype.</str>
    <str name="id">9846577</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The HIV-1 accessory protein Vif (virion infectivity factor) is required for the production of infectious virions by CD4(+) lymphocytes. Vif facilitates particle infectivity by blocking the inhibitory activity of APOBEC3G (CEM15), a virion-encapsidated cellular protein that deaminates minus-strand reverse transcript cytosines to uracils. We report that HIV-1 Vif forms a complex with human APOBEC3G that prevents its virion encapsidation. HIV-1 Vif did not efficiently form a complex with mouse APOBEC3G. Vif dramatically reduced the amount of human APOBEC3G encapsidated in HIV-1 virions but did not prevent encapsidation of mouse or AGM APOBEC3G. As a result, these enzymes are potent inhibitors of wild-type HIV-1 replication. The species-specificity of this interaction may play a role in restricting HIV-1 infection to humans. Together these findings suggest that therapeutic intervention that either induced APOBEC3G or blocked its interaction with Vif could be clinically beneficial.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Species-specific exclusion of APOBEC3G from HIV-1 virions by Vif.</str>
    <str name="id">12859895</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Human Immunodeficiency Viruses (HIV-1 and HIV-2) rely upon host-encoded proteins to facilitate their replication. Here, we combined genome-wide siRNA analyses with interrogation of human interactome databases to assemble a host-pathogen biochemical network containing 213 confirmed host cellular factors and 11 HIV-1-encoded proteins. Protein complexes that regulate ubiquitin conjugation, proteolysis, DNA-damage response, and RNA splicing were identified as important modulators of early-stage HIV-1 infection. Additionally, over 40 new factors were shown to specifically influence the initiation and/or kinetics of HIV-1 DNA synthesis, including cytoskeletal regulatory proteins, modulators of posttranslational modification, and nucleic acid-binding proteins. Finally, 15 proteins with diverse functional roles, including nuclear transport, prostaglandin synthesis, ubiquitination, and transcription, were found to influence nuclear import or viral DNA integration. Taken together, the multiscale approach described here has uncovered multiprotein virus-host interactions that likely act in concert to facilitate the early steps of HIV-1 infection.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Global analysis of host-pathogen interactions that regulate early-stage HIV-1 replication.</str>
    <str name="id">18854154</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Deubiquitinating enzymes (DUBs) are proteases that can antagonize ubiquitin-mediated signaling by disassembling ubiquitin-protein conjugates. How DUBs are regulated in vivo and how their substrate specificities are achieved are largely unknown. The conserved DUB Uch37 is found on proteasomes in organisms ranging from fission yeast to humans. Deubiquitination by Uch37 is activated by proteasomal binding, which enables Uch37 to process polyubiquitin chains. Here we show that in the nucleus Uch37 is also associated with the human Ino80 chromatin-remodeling complex (hINO80). In hINO80, Uch37 is held in an inactive state; however, it can be activated by transient interaction of the Ino80 complex with the proteasome. Thus, DUB activities can be modulated both positively and negatively via dynamic interactions with partner proteins. In addition, our findings suggest that the proteasome and the hINO80 chromatin-remodeling complex may cooperate to regulate transcription or DNA repair, processes in which both complexes have been implicated.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Distinct modes of regulation of the Uch37 deubiquitinating enzyme in the proteasome and in the Ino80 chromatin-remodeling complex.</str>
    <str name="id">18922472</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The covalent attachment of ubiquitin to proteins regulates numerous processes in eukaryotic cells. Here we report the identification of 753 unique lysine ubiquitylation sites on 471 proteins using higher-energy collisional dissociation on the LTQ Orbitrap Velos. In total 5756 putative ubiquitin substrates were identified. Lysine residues targeted by the ubiquitin-ligase system show no unique sequence feature. Surface accessible lysine residues located in ordered secondary regions, surrounded by smaller and positively charged amino acids are preferred sites of ubiquitylation. Lysine ubiquitylation shows promiscuity at the site level, as evidenced by low evolutionary conservation of ubiquitylation sites across eukaryotic species. Among lysine modifications a significant overlap (20%) between ubiquitylation and acetylation at site level highlights extensive competitive crosstalk among these modifications. This site-specific crosstalk is not prevalent among cell cycle ubiquitylations. Between SUMOylation and ubiquitylation the preferred interaction is through mixed-chain conjugation. Overall these data provide novel insights into the site-specific selection and regulatory function of lysine ubiquitylation.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Mass spectrometric analysis of lysine ubiquitylation reveals promiscuity at site level.</str>
    <str name="id">21139048</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>CEM15/APOBEC3G is a cellular protein required for resistance to infection by virion infectivity factor (Vif)-deficient human immunodeficiency virus (HIV). Here, using a murine leukemia virus (MLV)-based system, we provide evidence that CEM15/APOBEC3G is a DNA deaminase that is incorporated into virions during viral production and subsequently triggers massive deamination of deoxycytidine to deoxyuridine within the retroviral minus (first)-strand cDNA, thus providing a probable trigger for viral destruction. Furthermore, HIV Vif can protect MLV from this CEM15/APOBEC3G-dependent restriction. These findings imply that targeted DNA deamination is a major strategy of innate immunity to retroviruses and likely also contributes to the sequence variation observed in many viruses (including HIV).</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">DNA deamination mediates innate immunity to retroviral infection.</str>
    <str name="id">12809610</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>APOBEC3G is a human cellular enzyme that is incorporated into retroviral particles and acts to restrict retroviral replication in infected cells by deaminating dC to dU in the first (minus)-strand cDNA replication intermediate. HIV, however, encodes a protein (virion infectivity factor, Vif ), which overcomes APOBEC3G-mediated restriction but by an unknown mechanism. Here, we show that Vif triggers APOBEC3G degradation by a proteasome-dependent pathway and that an 80 amino acid region of APOBEC3G surrounding its first zinc coordination motif is sufficient to confer the ability to partake in an interaction involving Vif. Inhibitors of this interaction might therefore prove therapeutically useful in blocking Vif-mediated APOBEC3G destruction.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The Vif protein of HIV triggers degradation of the human antiretroviral DNA deaminase APOBEC3G.</str>
    <str name="id">14614829</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Despite the diverse biological pathways known to be regulated by ubiquitylation, global identification of substrates that are targeted for ubiquitylation has remained a challenge. To globally characterize the human ubiquitin-modified proteome (ubiquitinome), we utilized a monoclonal antibody that recognizes diglycine (diGly)-containing isopeptides following trypsin digestion. We identify ~19,000 diGly-modified lysine residues within ~5000 proteins. Using quantitative proteomics we monitored temporal changes in diGly site abundance in response to both proteasomal and translational inhibition, indicating both a dependence on ongoing translation to observe alterations in site abundance and distinct dynamics of individual modified lysines in response to proteasome inhibition. Further, we demonstrate that quantitative diGly proteomics can be utilized to identify substrates for cullin-RING ubiquitin ligases. Interrogation of the ubiquitinome allows for not only a quantitative assessment of alterations in protein homeostasis fidelity, but also identification of substrates for individual ubiquitin pathway enzymes.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Systematic and quantitative assessment of the ubiquitin-modified proteome.</str>
    <str name="id">21906983</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The exact role of the central acidic domain of Mdm2 in p53 degradation remains unclear. We therefore performed a systematic and comprehensive analysis of the acidic domain using a series of short deletions and found that only a minor part of the domain was indispensable for Mdm2-mediated p53 ubiquitylation. Moreover, we identified a short stretch of acidic amino acids required for p53 degradation but not ubiquitylation, indicating that, in addition to p53 ubiquitylation, the acidic domain might be involved in a critical post-ubiquitylation step in p53 degradation. Rather than representing a single functional domain, different parts of the acidic region perform separate functions in p53 degradation, suggesting that it might be possible to therapeutically target them independently.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Mutational analysis reveals a dual role of Mdm2 acidic domain in the regulation of p53 stability.</str>
    <str name="id">22659184</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The human protein apolipoprotein B mRNA-editing enzyme-catalytic polypeptide-like-3G (APOBEC3G), also known as CEM-15, mediates a newly described form of innate resistance to retroviral infection by catalyzing the deamination of deoxycytidine to deoxyuridine in viral cDNA replication intermediates. Because DNA deamination takes place after virus entry into target cells, APOBEC3G function is dependent on its association with the viral nucleoprotein complexes that synthesize cDNA and must therefore be incorporated into virions as they assemble in infected cells. Here we show that the HIV-1 virion infectivity factor (Vif) protein protects the virus from APOBEC3G-mediated inactivation by preventing its incorporation into progeny virions, thus allowing the ensuing infection to proceed without DNA deamination. In addition to helping exclude APOBEC3G from nascent virions, Vif also removes APOBEC3G from virus-producing cells by inducing its ubiquitination and subsequent degradation by the proteasome. Our findings indicate that pharmacologic strategies aimed at stabilizing APOBEC3G in HIV-1 infected cells should be explored as potential HIV/AIDS therapeutics.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The antiretroviral enzyme APOBEC3G is degraded by the proteasome in response to HIV-1 Vif.</str>
    <str name="id">14528300</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The viral infectivity factor (Vif) encoded by HIV-1 neutralizes a potent antiviral pathway that occurs in human T lymphocytes and several leukemic T-cell lines termed nonpermissive, but not in other cells termed permissive. In the absence of Vif, this antiviral pathway efficiently inactivates HIV-1. It was recently reported that APOBEC3G (also known as CEM-15), a cytidine deaminase nucleic acid-editing enzyme, confers this antiviral phenotype on permissive cells. Here we describe evidence that Vif binds APOBEC3G and induces its rapid degradation, thus eliminating it from cells and preventing its incorporation into HIV-1 virions. Studies of Vif mutants imply that it contains two domains, one that binds APOBEC3G and another with a conserved SLQ(Y/F)LA motif that mediates APOBEC3G degradation by a proteasome-dependent pathway. These results provide promising approaches for drug discovery.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">HIV-1 Vif protein binds the editing enzyme APOBEC3G and induces its degradation.</str>
    <str name="id">14528301</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Human immunodeficiency virus-1 (HIV-1) Vif is essential for viral evasion of host antiviral factor CEM15/APOBEC3G. We report that Vif interacts with cellular proteins Cul5, elongins B and C, and Rbx1 to form an Skp1-cullin-F-box (SCF)-like complex. The ability of Vif to suppress antiviral activity of APOBEC3G was specifically dependent on Cul5-SCF function, allowing Vif to interact with APOBEC3G and induce its ubiquitination and degradation. A Vif mutant that interacted with APOBEC3G but not with Cul5-SCF was functionally inactive. The Cul5-SCF was also required for Vif function in distantly related simian immunodeficiency virus mac. These results indicate that the conserved Cul5-SCF pathway used by Vif is a potential target for antiviral development.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Induction of APOBEC3G ubiquitination and degradation by an HIV-1 Vif-Cul5-SCF complex.</str>
    <str name="id">14564014</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Here, we apply the COmbined FRActional DIagonal Chromatography (COFRADIC) technology to enrich for ubiquitinated peptides and to identify sites of ubiquitination by mass spectrometry. Our technology bypasses the need to overexpress tagged variants of ubiquitin and the use of sequence-biased antibodies recognizing ubiquitin remnants. In brief, all protein primary amino groups are blocked by chemical acetylation, after which ubiquitin chains are proteolytically and specifically removed by the catalytic core domain of the USP2 deubiquitinase (USP2cc). Because USP2cc cleaves the isopeptidyl bond between the ubiquitin C-terminus and the ε-amino group of the ubiquitinated lysine, this enzyme reintroduces primary ε-amino groups in proteins. These amino groups are then chemically modified with a handle that allows specific isolation of ubiquitinated peptides during subsequent COFRADIC chromatographic runs. This method led to the identification of over 7500 endogenous ubiquitination sites in more than 3300 different proteins in a native human Jurkat cell lysate. </str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">A COFRADIC protocol to study protein ubiquitination.</str>
    <str name="id">24816145</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Immunoproteasomes and standard proteasomes assemble by alternative pathways that bias against the formation of certain "mixed" proteasomes. Differences between beta subunit propeptides contribute to assembly specificity and an assembly chaperone, proteassemblin, may be involved via differential propeptide interactions. We investigated possible mechanisms of biased proteasome assembly and the role of proteassemblin by identifying protein-protein interactions among human 20S proteasome subunits and proteassemblin using a yeast two-hybrid interaction assay. Forty-one interactions were detected, including five involving proteassemblin and contiguous beta subunits, which suggests that proteassemblin binds to preproteasomes via a beta subunit surface. Interaction between proteassemblin and beta5, but not beta5i, suggests that proteassemblin may be involved in the propeptide-dependent differential incorporation of these subunits. Interactions between proteassemblin and beta1, beta1i, and beta7 suggest that proteassemblin may regulate preproteasome dimerization via interactions with the C-termini of these subunits, which in the mature 20S structure extend to contact opposing beta subunit rings.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Protein-protein interactions among human 20S proteasome subunits and proteassemblin.</str>
    <str name="id">14733938</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Infection with the β-herpesvirus human cytomegalovirus (HCMV) is lifelong, causing limited disease in healthy adults, but life threatening in immunocompromised individuals. The viral kinase pUL97, a functional ortholog of cellular cyclin-dependent kinases (CDKs), is critical for HCMV replication and a target for antiviral drug development. Upon kinase inhibition, drug-resistant strains emerge with mutations in UL27, an HCMV gene of unknown function. Using a proteomics approach, we discovered that pUL27 is necessary and sufficient to degrade Tip60, a host acetyltransferase and interacting partner of HIV Tat. Consistent with this, the expression of Tat restored antiviral inhibition of an otherwise resistant HCMV strain. The functional consequence of Tip60 degradation was the induction of the CDK inhibitor p21(Waf1/Cip1) and cell-cycle arrest, representing changes necessary for the antiviral effects of pUL97 inhibition. Consequently, either increasing p21(Waf1/Cip1) expression or decreasing Tip60 levels improved the antiviral activity of the HCMV kinase inhibitor maribavir.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Antiviral inhibition targeting the HCMV kinase pUL97 requires pUL27-dependent degradation of Tip60 acetyltransferase and cell-cycle arrest.</str>
    <str name="id">21320693</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Proteasomes are the proteolytic complex responsible for major histocompatibility complex (MHC) class I-restricted antigen presentation. Interferon gamma treatment increases expression MHC-encoded LMP2 and LMP7 subunits of the proteasome and decreases expression of two proteasome subunits, named X and Y, which alters the proteolytic specificity of proteasomes. Molecular cloning of complementary DNAs encoding X and Y showed that their proteins are proteasomal subunits with high amino acid similarity to LMP7 and LMP2, respectively. Thus, interferon gamma may induce subunit replacements of X and Y by LMP7 and LMP2, respectively, producing proteasomes perhaps more appropriate for the immunological processing of endogenous antigens.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">cDNA cloning and interferon gamma down-regulation of proteasomal subunits X and Y.</str>
    <str name="id">8066462</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Dynamic reorganization of signaling systems frequently accompanies pathway perturbations, yet quantitative studies of network remodeling by pathway stimuli are lacking. Here, we report the development of a quantitative proteomics platform centered on multiplex absolute quantification (AQUA) technology to elucidate the architecture of the cullin-RING ubiquitin ligase (CRL) network and to evaluate current models of dynamic CRL remodeling. Current models suggest that CRL complexes are controlled by cycles of CRL deneddylation and CAND1 binding. Contrary to expectations, acute CRL inhibition with MLN4924, an inhibitor of the NEDD8-activating enzyme, does not result in a global reorganization of the CRL network. Examination of CRL complex stoichiometry reveals that, independent of cullin neddylation, a large fraction of cullins are assembled with adaptor modules, whereas only a small fraction are associated with CAND1. These studies suggest an alternative model of CRL dynamicity where the abundance of adaptor modules, rather than cycles of neddylation and CAND1 binding, drives CRL network organization.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Dynamics of cullin-RING ubiquitin ligase network revealed by systematic quantitative proteomics.</str>
    <str name="id">21145461</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Nephronophthisis (NPHP), Joubert (JBTS), and Meckel-Gruber (MKS) syndromes are autosomal-recessive ciliopathies presenting with cystic kidneys, retinal degeneration, and cerebellar/neural tube malformation. Whether defects in kidney, retinal, or neural disease primarily involve ciliary, Hedgehog, or cell polarity pathways remains unclear. Using high-confidence proteomics, we identified 850 interactors copurifying with nine NPHP/JBTS/MKS proteins and discovered three connected modules: "NPHP1-4-8" functioning at the apical surface, "NPHP5-6" at centrosomes, and "MKS" linked to Hedgehog signaling. Assays for ciliogenesis and epithelial morphogenesis in 3D renal cultures link renal cystic disease to apical organization defects, whereas ciliary and Hedgehog pathway defects lead to retinal or neural deficits. Using 38 interactors as candidates, linkage and sequencing analysis of 250 patients identified ATXN10 and TCTN2 as new NPHP-JBTS genes, and our Tctn2 mouse knockout shows neural tube and Hedgehog signaling defects. Our study further illustrates the power of linking proteomic networks and human genetics to uncover critical disease pathways.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Mapping the NPHP-JBTS-MKS protein network reveals ciliopathy disease genes and pathways.</str>
    <str name="id">21565611</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Proteins that fail to correctly fold or assemble into oligomeric complexes in the endoplasmic reticulum (ER) are degraded by a ubiquitin- and proteasome-dependent process known as ER-associated degradation (ERAD). Although many individual components of the ERAD system have been identified, how these proteins are organized into a functional network that coordinates recognition, ubiquitylation and dislocation of substrates across the ER membrane is not well understood. We have investigated the functional organization of the mammalian ERAD system using a systems-level strategy that integrates proteomics, functional genomics and the transcriptional response to ER stress. This analysis supports an adaptive organization for the mammalian ERAD machinery and reveals a number of metazoan-specific genes not previously linked to ERAD.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Defining human ERAD networks through an integrative mapping strategy.</str>
    <str name="id">22119785</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Cellular processes often depend on stable physical associations between proteins. Despite recent progress, knowledge of the composition of human protein complexes remains limited. To close this gap, we applied an integrative global proteomic profiling approach, based on chromatographic separation of cultured human cell extracts into more than one thousand biochemical fractions that were subsequently analyzed by quantitative tandem mass spectrometry, to systematically identify a network of 13,993 high-confidence physical interactions among 3,006 stably associated soluble human proteins. Most of the 622 putative protein complexes we report are linked to core biological processes and encompass both candidate disease genes and unannotated proteins to inform on mechanism. Strikingly, whereas larger multiprotein assemblies tend to be more extensively annotated and evolutionarily conserved, human protein complexes with five or fewer subunits are far more likely to be functionally unannotated or restricted to vertebrates, suggesting more recent functional innovations.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">A census of human soluble protein complexes.</str>
    <str name="id">22939629</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Normal human urine contains large numbers of exosomes, which are 40- to 100-nm vesicles that originate as the internal vesicles in multivesicular bodies from every renal epithelial cell type facing the urinary space. Here, we used LC-MS/MS to profile the proteome of human urinary exosomes. Overall, the analysis identified 1132 proteins unambiguously, including 177 that are represented on the Online Mendelian Inheritance in Man database of disease-related genes, suggesting that exosome analysis is a potential approach to discover urinary biomarkers. We extended the proteomic analysis to phosphoproteomic profiling using neutral loss scanning, and this yielded multiple novel phosphorylation sites, including serine-811 in the thiazide-sensitive Na-Cl co-transporter, NCC. To demonstrate the potential use of exosome analysis to identify a genetic renal disease, we carried out immunoblotting of exosomes from urine samples of patients with a clinical diagnosis of Bartter syndrome type I, showing an absence of the sodium-potassium-chloride co-transporter 2, NKCC2. The proteomic data are publicly accessible at http://dir.nhlbi.nih.gov/papers/lkem/exosome/.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Large-scale proteomics and phosphoproteomics of urinary exosomes.</str>
    <str name="id">19056867</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Protein interactions form a network whose structure drives cellular function and whose organization informs biological inquiry. Using high-throughput affinity-purification mass spectrometry, we identify interacting partners for 2,594 human proteins in HEK293T cells. The resulting network (BioPlex) contains 23,744 interactions among 7,668 proteins with 86% previously undocumented. BioPlex accurately depicts known complexes, attaining 80%-100% coverage for most CORUM complexes. The network readily subdivides into communities that correspond to complexes or clusters of functionally related proteins. More generally, network architecture reflects cellular localization, biological process, and molecular function, enabling functional characterization of thousands of proteins. Network structure also reveals associations among thousands of protein domains, suggesting a basis for examining structurally related proteins. Finally, BioPlex, in combination with other approaches, can be used to reveal interactions of biological or clinical significance. For example, mutations in the membrane protein VAPB implicated in familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis perturb a defined community of interactors. </str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The BioPlex Network: A Systematic Exploration of the Human Interactome.</str>
    <str name="id">26186194</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Variations within proteasome β (PSMB) genes, which encode the β subunits of the 20S proteasome, may affect proteasome function, assembly, and/or binding of proteasome inhibitors. To investigate the potential association between PSMB gene variants and treatment-emergent resistance to bortezomib and/or long-term outcomes, in the present study, PSMB gene sequence variation was characterized in tumor DNA samples from patients who participated in the phase 3 Assessment of Proteasome Inhibition for Extending Remissions (APEX) study of bortezomib versus high-dose dexamethasone for treatment of relapsed multiple myeloma. Twelve new PSMB variants were identified. No associations were found between PSMB single nucleotide polymorphism genotype frequency and clinical response to bortezomib or dexamethasone treatment or between PSMB single nucleotide polymorphism allelic frequency and pooled overall survival or time to progression. Although specific PSMB5 variants have been identified previously in preclinical models of bortezomib resistance, these variants were not detected in patient tumor samples collected after clinical relapse from bortezomib, which suggests that alternative mechanisms underlie bortezomib insensitivity.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Sequence analysis of β-subunit genes of the 20S proteasome in patients with relapsed multiple myeloma treated with bortezomib or dexamethasone.</str>
    <str name="id">23018640</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Replication of human immunodeficiency virus type 1 (HIV-1) in primary blood lymphocytes, certain T-cell lines (nonpermissive cells), and most likely in vivo is highly dependent on the virally encoded Vif protein. Evidence suggests that Vif acts late in the viral life cycle during assembly, budding, and/or maturation to counteract the antiviral activity of the CEM15 protein and possibly other antiviral factors. Because HIV-1 virions produced in the absence of Vif are severely restricted at a postentry, preintegration step of infection, it is presumed that such virions differ from wild-type virions in some way. In the present study, we established a protocol for producing large quantities of vif-deficient HIV-1 (HIV-1/Delta vif) from an acute infection of nonpermissive T cells and performed a thorough examination of the defect in these virions. Aside from the expected lack of Vif, we observed no apparent abnormalities in the packaging, modification, processing, or function of proteins in Delta vif virions. In addition, we found no consistent defect in the ability of Delta vif virions to perform intravirion reverse transcription under a variety of assay conditions, suggesting that the reverse transcription complexes in these particles can behave normally under cell-free conditions. Consistent with this finding, neither the placement of the primer tRNA3Lys nor its ability to promote reverse transcription in an in vitro assay was affected by a lack of Vif. Based on the inability of this comprehensive analysis to uncover molecular defects in Delta vif virions, we speculate that such defects are likely to be subtle and/or rare.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Comprehensive investigation of the molecular defect in vif-deficient human immunodeficiency virus type 1 virions.</str>
    <str name="id">12719574</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The National Institutes of Health's Mammalian Gene Collection (MGC) project was designed to generate and sequence a publicly accessible cDNA resource containing a complete open reading frame (ORF) for every human and mouse gene. The project initially used a random strategy to select clones from a large number of cDNA libraries from diverse tissues. Candidate clones were chosen based on 5'-EST sequences, and then fully sequenced to high accuracy and analyzed by algorithms developed for this project. Currently, more than 11,000 human and 10,000 mouse genes are represented in MGC by at least one clone with a full ORF. The random selection approach is now reaching a saturation point, and a transition to protocols targeted at the missing transcripts is now required to complete the mouse and human collections. Comparison of the sequence of the MGC clones to reference genome sequences reveals that most cDNA clones are of very high sequence quality, although it is likely that some cDNAs may carry missense variants as a consequence of experimental artifact, such as PCR, cloning, or reverse transcriptase errors. Recently, a rat cDNA component was added to the project, and ongoing frog (Xenopus) and zebrafish (Danio) cDNA projects were expanded to take advantage of the high-throughput MGC pipeline.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The status, quality, and expansion of the NIH full-length cDNA project: the Mammalian Gene Collection (MGC).</str>
    <str name="id">15489334</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Post-translational modification of proteins by ubiquitin is a fundamentally important regulatory mechanism. However, proteome-wide analysis of endogenous ubiquitylation remains a challenging task, and almost always has relied on cells expressing affinity tagged ubiquitin. Here we combine single-step immunoenrichment of ubiquitylated peptides with peptide fractionation and high-resolution mass spectrometry to investigate endogenous ubiquitylation sites. We precisely map 11,054 endogenous putative ubiquitylation sites (diglycine-modified lysines) on 4,273 human proteins. The presented data set covers 67% of the known ubiquitylation sites and contains 10,254 novel sites on proteins with diverse cellular functions including cell signaling, receptor endocytosis, DNA replication, DNA damage repair, and cell cycle progression. Our method enables site-specific quantification of ubiquitylation in response to cellular perturbations and is applicable to any cell type or tissue. Global quantification of ubiquitylation in cells treated with the proteasome inhibitor MG-132 discovers sites that are involved in proteasomal degradation, and suggests a nonproteasomal function for almost half of all sites. Surprisingly, ubiquitylation of about 15% of sites decreased more than twofold within four hours of MG-132 treatment, showing that inhibition of proteasomal function can dramatically reduce ubiquitylation on many sites with non-proteasomal functions. Comparison of ubiquitylation sites with acetylation sites reveals an extensive overlap between the lysine residues targeted by these two modifications. However, the crosstalk between these two post-translational modifications is significantly less frequent on sites that show increased ubiquitylation upon proteasome inhibition. Taken together, we report the largest site-specific ubiquitylation dataset in human cells, and for the first time demonstrate proteome-wide, site-specific quantification of endogenous putative ubiquitylation sites.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">A proteome-wide, quantitative survey of in vivo ubiquitylation sites reveals widespread regulatory roles.</str>
    <str name="id">21890473</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Mammalian proteasomes are macromolecular complexes formed of a catalytic 20S core associated to two regulatory complexes. The 20S core complex consists of four stacked rings of seven alpha or beta subunits. Three beta subunits contain a catalytic site and can be replaced by three interferon gamma-inducible counterparts to form the immunoproteasome. Cells may constitutively possess a mixture of both 20S proteasome types leading to a heterogeneous proteasome population. Purified rat 20S proteasome has been separated in several chromatographic fractions indicating an even higher degree of complexity in 20S proteasome subunit composition. This complexity may arise from the presence of subunit isoforms, as previously detected in purified human erythrocyte 20S proteasome. In this study, we have used a quantitative proteomic approach based on two-dimensional gel electrophoresis and isotope-coded affinity tag (ICAT) labeling to quantify the variations in subunit composition, including subunit isoforms, of 20S proteasomes purified from different cells. The protocol has been adapted to the analysis of low quantities of 20S proteasome complexes. The strategy has then been validated using standard proteins and has been applied to the comparison of 20S proteasomes from erythrocytes and U937 cancer cells. The results obtained show that this approach represents a valuable tool for the study of 20S proteasome heterogeneity.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">A quantitative proteomic approach using two-dimensional gel electrophoresis and isotope-coded affinity tag labeling for studying human 20S proteasome heterogeneity.</str>
    <str name="id">15887188</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>A prerequisite for proteins to interact in a cell is that they are present in the same intracellular compartment. Although it is generally accepted that proteasomes occur in both, the cytoplasm and the nucleus, research has been focusing on cytoplasmic protein breakdown and antigen processing, respectively. Thus, little is known on the functional organization of the proteasome in the nucleus. Here we report that within the nucleus 20S and 26S proteasomes occur throughout the nucleoplasm and partially colocalize with splicing factor-containing speckles. Because proteasomes are absent from the nucleolus, a recruitment system was used to analyze the molecular fate of nucleolar protein fibrillarin: Subtoxic concentrations of mercuric chloride (HgCl(2)) induce subcellular redistribution of fibrillarin and substantial colocalization (33%) with nucleoplasmic proteasomes in different cell lines and in primary cells isolated from mercury-treated mice. Accumulation of fibrillarin and fibrillarin-ubiquitin conjugates in lactacystin-treated cells suggests that proteasome-dependent processing of this autoantigen occurs upon mercury induction. The latter observation might constitute the cell biological basis of autoimmune responses that specifically target fibrillarin in mercury-mouse models and scleroderma.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Subcellular recruitment of fibrillarin to nucleoplasmic proteasomes: implications for processing of a nucleolar autoantigen.</str>
    <str name="id">12388758</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>An analysis of the subunits of the high molecular weight proteinase, macropain (multicatalytic proteinase or proteasome) from human erythrocytes has been conducted using N-terminal amino acid sequencing, gel electrophoresis and reverse-phase peptide mapping. This analysis provided evidence for the existence of 13 subunits of different primary structure. Five subunits were susceptible to the Edman degradation and yielded unique N-terminal sequences. Similarities among these sequences, however, indicated that the subunits are homologous. Two-dimensional gel electrophoresis discriminated 10 major components, which included two of the subunits for which N-terminal sequences had been determined and eight N-terminally blocked subunits. Tryptic peptide mapping indicated that all 10 of these components have a different amino acid sequence. Tryptic peptides from some of the subunits were subjected to amino acid sequence analysis, and the data indicated that all the subunits tested in this way are related by common ancestry. The data suggest that at least nine of the total of 13 subunits are encoded by members of the same gene family; the remaining four subunits have not yet been investigated in sufficient detail to establish their relationships. No evidence for a close relationship with any previously investigated proteinase family has been found. Finally, through a comparison of the 'latent' and 'active' forms of macropain, the study established a close similarity in the subunit composition of these catalytically very different species, although proteolytic degradation of selected subunits appears in the active form of the enzyme.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Relationships among the subunits of the high molecular weight proteinase, macropain (proteasome).</str>
    <str name="id">2306472</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The binding of integrin adhesion receptors to their extracellular matrix ligands controls cell morphology, movement, survival, and differentiation in various developmental, homeostatic, and disease processes. Here, we report a methodology to isolate complexes associated with integrin adhesion receptors, which, like other receptor-associated signaling complexes, have been refractory to proteomic analysis. Quantitative, comparative analyses of the proteomes of two receptor-ligand pairs, alpha(4)beta(1)-vascular cell adhesion molecule-1 and alpha(5)beta(1)-fibronectin, defined both core and receptor-specific components. Regulator of chromosome condensation-2 (RCC2) was detected in the alpha(5)beta(1)-fibronectin signaling network at an intersection between the Rac1 and adenosine 5'-diphosphate ribosylation factor 6 (Arf6) subnetworks. RCC2 knockdown enhanced fibronectin-induced activation of both Rac1 and Arf6 and accelerated cell spreading, suggesting that RCC2 limits the signaling required for membrane protrusion and delivery. Dysregulation of Rac1 and Arf6 function by RCC2 knockdown also abolished persistent migration along fibronectin fibers, indicating a functional role for RCC2 in directional cell movement. This proteomics workflow now opens the way to further dissection and systems-level analyses of adhesion signaling.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Proteomic analysis of integrin-associated complexes identifies RCC2 as a dual regulator of Rac1 and Arf6.</str>
    <str name="id">19738201</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The PARKIN ubiquitin ligase (also known as PARK2) and its regulatory kinase PINK1 (also known as PARK6), often mutated in familial early-onset Parkinson's disease, have central roles in mitochondrial homeostasis and mitophagy. Whereas PARKIN is recruited to the mitochondrial outer membrane (MOM) upon depolarization via PINK1 action and can ubiquitylate porin, mitofusin and Miro proteins on the MOM, the full repertoire of PARKIN substrates--the PARKIN-dependent ubiquitylome--remains poorly defined. Here we use quantitative diGly capture proteomics (diGly) to elucidate the ubiquitylation site specificity and topology of PARKIN-dependent target modification in response to mitochondrial depolarization. Hundreds of dynamically regulated ubiquitylation sites in dozens of proteins were identified, with strong enrichment for MOM proteins, indicating that PARKIN dramatically alters the ubiquitylation status of the mitochondrial proteome. Using complementary interaction proteomics, we found depolarization-dependent PARKIN association with numerous MOM targets, autophagy receptors, and the proteasome. Mutation of the PARKIN active site residue C431, which has been found mutated in Parkinson's disease patients, largely disrupts these associations. Structural and topological analysis revealed extensive conservation of PARKIN-dependent ubiquitylation sites on cytoplasmic domains in vertebrate and Drosophila melanogaster MOM proteins. These studies provide a resource for understanding how the PINK1-PARKIN pathway re-sculpts the proteome to support mitochondrial homeostasis.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Landscape of the PARKIN-dependent ubiquitylome in response to mitochondrial depolarization.</str>
    <str name="id">23503661</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Dendritic cells (DC) are professional antigen-presenting cells that activate CTL by presenting MHC class I-restricted peptides that are processed through the proteasome pathway. Previously, we reported that upon DC maturation the synthesis is switched towards the exclusive production of immunoproteasomes containing the active site subunits LMP2, LMP7 and MECL-1. In this study we investigated the mechanism by which proteasome assembly is regulated in mature DC. Quantitative analysis of mRNA expression showed very limited transcriptional induction of LMP7, MECL-1 and UMP1 in mature DC and a moderate mRNA increment for LMP2 and PA28alpha and beta. We investigated a role of PA28alpha/beta in regulating proteasome assembly in DC. PA28alpha/beta coprecipitated with 13S/16S proteasome precursor complexes but associated with mature constitutive and immunoproteasomes to the same extent. Furthermore, we determined the steady-state proteasome subunit composition in DC. Replacement of constitutive proteasomes by immunoproteasomes in maturing DC was very slow and occurred only to a minor extent. Our data suggest that the limited turnover of 20S proteasomes in mature DC probably contributes little to recently reported marked differences in antigen presentation between immature and mature DC and that alternative mechanisms may be responsible for this phenomenon.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Pronounced up-regulation of the PA28alpha/beta proteasome regulator but little increase in the steady-state content of immunoproteasome during dendritic cell maturation.</str>
    <str name="id">11745344</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The human immunodeficiency virus type 1 (HIV-1) relies on Vif (viral infectivity factor) to overcome the potent antiviral function of APOBEC3G (apolipoprotein B mRNA-editing enzyme, catalytic polypeptide-like 3G, also known as CEM15). Using an APOBEC3G-specific antiserum, we now show that Vif prevents virion incorporation of endogenous APOBEC3G by effectively depleting the intracellular levels of this enzyme in HIV-1-infected T cells. Vif achieves this depletion by both impairing the translation of APOBEC3G mRNA and accelerating the posttranslational degradation of the APOBEC3G protein by the 26S proteasome. Vif physically interacts with APOBEC3G, and expression of Vif alone in the absence of other HIV-1 proteins is sufficient to cause depletion of APOBEC3G. These findings highlight how the bimodal translational and posttranslational inhibitory effects of Vif on APOBEC3G combine to markedly suppress the expression of this potent antiviral enzyme in virally infected cells, thereby effectively curtailing the incorporation of APOBEC3G into newly formed HIV-1 virions.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">HIV-1 Vif blocks the antiviral activity of APOBEC3G by impairing both its translation and intracellular stability.</str>
    <str name="id">14527406</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The assembly of individual proteasome subunits into catalytically active mammalian 20S proteasomes is not well understood. Using subunit-specific antibodies, we characterized both precursor and mature proteasome complexes. Antibodies to PSMA4 (C9) immunoprecipitated complexes composed of alpha, precursor beta and processed beta subunits. However, antibodies to PSMA3 (C8) and PSMB9 (LMP2) immunoprecipitated complexes made up of alpha and precursor beta but no processed beta subunits. These complexes possess short half-lives, are enzymatically inactive and their molecular weight is approximately 300 kDa. Radioactivity chases from these complexes into mature, long-lived approximately 700 kDa proteasomes. Therefore, these structures represent precursor proteasomes and are probably made up of two rings: one containing alpha subunits and the other, precursor beta subunits. The assembly of precursor proteasomes occurs in at least two stages, with precursor beta subunits PSMB2 (C7-I), PSMB3 (C10-II), PSMB7 (Z), PSMB9 (LMP2) and PSMB10 (LMP10) being incorporated before others [PSMB1 (C5), PSMB6 (delta), and PSMB8 (LMP7)]. Proteasome maturation (processing of the beta subunits and juxtaposition of the two beta rings) is accompanied by conformational changes in the (outer) alpha rings, and may be inefficient. Finally, interferon-gamma had no significant effect on the half-lives or total amounts of precursor or mature proteasomes.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Intermediates in the formation of mouse 20S proteasomes: implications for the assembly of precursor beta subunits.</str>
    <str name="id">9311996</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The proteasome is the primary subcellular organelle responsible for protein degradation. It is a dynamic assemblage of 34 core subunits and many differentially expressed, transiently interacting, modulatory proteins. This paper describes a novel affinity chromatography method for the purification of functional human holoproteasome complexes using mild conditions. Human proteasomes purified by this simple procedure maintained the ability to proteolytically process synthetic peptide substrates and degrade ubiquitinated parkin. Furthermore, the entire purification fraction was analyzed by mass spectrometry in order to identify proteasomal proteins and putative proteasome-interacting proteins. The mild purification conditions maintained transient physical interactions between holoproteasomes and a number of known modulatory proteins. In addition, several classes of putative interacting proteins co-purified with the proteasomes, including proteins with a role in the ubiquitin proteasome system for protein degradation or DNA repair. These results demonstrate the efficacy of using this affinity purification strategy for isolating functional human proteasomes and identifying proteins that may physically interact with human proteasomes.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Isolation of human proteasomes and putative proteasome-interacting proteins using a novel affinity chromatography method.</str>
    <str name="id">19013454</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>High mutation frequency during reverse transcription has a principal role in the genetic variation of primate lentiviral populations. It is the main driving force for the generation of drug resistance and the escape from immune surveillance. G to A hypermutation is one of the characteristics of primate lentiviruses, as well as other retroviruses, during replication in vivo and in cell culture. The molecular mechanisms of this process, however, remain to be clarified. Here, we demonstrate that CEM15 (also known as apolipoprotein B mRNA editing enzyme, catalytic polypeptide-like 3G; APOBEC3G), an endogenous inhibitor of human immunodeficiency virus type 1 (HIV-1) replication, is a cytidine deaminase and is able to induce G to A hypermutation in newly synthesized viral DNA. This effect can be counteracted by the HIV-1 virion infectivity factor (Vif). It seems that this viral DNA mutator is a viral defence mechanism in host cells that may induce either lethal hypermutation or instability of the incoming nascent viral reverse transcripts, which could account for the Vif-defective phenotype. Importantly, the accumulation of CEM15-mediated non-lethal hypermutation in the replicating viral genome could potently contribute to the genetic variation of primate lentiviral populations.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The cytidine deaminase CEM15 induces hypermutation in newly synthesized HIV-1 DNA.</str>
    <str name="id">12808465</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Viral replication usually requires that innate intracellular lines of defence be overcome, a task usually accomplished by specialized viral gene products. The virion infectivity factor (Vif) protein of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) is required during the late stages of viral production to counter the antiviral activity of APOBEC3G (apolipoprotein B mRNA-editing enzyme, catalytic polypeptide-like 3G; also known as CEM15), a protein expressed notably in human T lymphocytes. When produced in the presence of APOBEC3G, vif-defective virus is non-infectious. APOBEC3G is closely related to APOBEC1, the central component of an RNA-editing complex that deaminates a cytosine residue in apoB messenger RNA. APOBEC family members also have potent DNA mutator activity through dC deamination; however, whether the editing potential of APOBEC3G has any relevance to HIV inhibition is unknown. Here, we demonstrate that it does, as APOBEC3G exerts its antiviral effect during reverse transcription to trigger G-to-A hypermutation in the nascent retroviral DNA. We also find that APOBEC3G can act on a broad range of retroviruses in addition to HIV, suggesting that hypermutation by editing is a general innate defence mechanism against this important group of pathogens.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Broad antiretroviral defence by human APOBEC3G through lethal editing of nascent reverse transcripts.</str>
    <str name="id">12808466</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The proteasome, a proteolytic complex present in all eukaryotic cells, is part of the ATP-dependent ubiquitin/proteasome pathway. It plays a critical role in the regulation of many physiological processes. The 20 S proteasome, the catalytic core of the 26 S proteasome, is made of four stacked rings of seven subunits each (alpha7beta7beta7alpha7). Here we studied the human 20 S proteasome using proteomics. This led to the establishment of a fine subunit reference map and to the identification of post-translational modifications. We found that the human 20 S proteasome, purified from erythrocytes, exhibited a high degree of structural heterogeneity, characterized by the presence of multiple isoforms for most of the alpha and beta subunits, including the catalytic ones, resulting in a total of at least 32 visible spots after Coomassie Blue staining. The different isoforms of a given subunit displayed shifted pI values, suggesting that they likely resulted from post-translational modifications. We then took advantage of the efficiency of complementary mass spectrometric approaches to investigate further these protein modifications at the structural level. In particular, we focused our efforts on the alpha7 subunit and characterized its N-acetylation and its phosphorylation site localized on Ser(250).</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Mapping and structural dissection of human 20 S proteasome using proteomic approaches.</str>
    <str name="id">12376572</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The 26S proteasome is a multisubunit complex responsible for degradation of ubiquitinated substrates, which plays a critical role in regulating various biological processes. To fully understand the function and regulation of the proteasome complex, an important step is to elucidate its subunit composition and posttranslational modifications. Toward this goal, a new affinity purification strategy has been developed using a derivative of the HB tag for rapid isolation of the human 26S proteasome complex for subsequent proteomic analysis. The purification of the complex is achieved from stable 293 cell lines expressing a HB-tagged proteasome subunit and by high-affinity streptavidin binding with TEV cleavage elution. The complete composition of the 26S proteasome complex, including recently assigned new subunits, is identified by LC-MS/MS. In addition, all known proteasome activator proteins and components involved in the ubiquitin-proteasome degradation pathway are identified. Aside from the subunit composition, the N-terminal modification and phosphorylation of the proteasome subunits have been characterized. Twelve novel phosphorylation sites from eight subunits have been identified, and N-terminal modifications are determined for 25 subunits, 12 of which have not been previously reported in mammals. We also observe different N-terminal processing of subunit Rpn2, which results in identification of two different N-termini of the protein. This work presents the first comprehensive characterization of the human 26S proteasome complex by affinity purification and tandem mass spectrometry. The detailed proteomic profiling obtained here is significant to future studies aiming at a complete understanding of the structure-function relationship of the human 26S proteasome complex.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Mass spectrometric characterization of the affinity-purified human 26S proteasome complex.</str>
    <str name="id">17323924</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Human immunodeficiency virus, type 1 (HIV-1) Vif protein plays an essential role in the regulation of the infectivity of HIV-1 virion. Vif functions to counteract an anti-HIV-1 cellular factor in non-permissive cells, CEM15/Apobec-3G, which shares a cytidine deaminase motif. CEM15/Apobec-3G deaminates dC to dU in the minus strand DNA of HIV-1, resulting in G to A hypermutation in the plus strand DNA. In this study, we have done the mutagenesis analysis on two cytidine deaminase motifs in CEM15/Apobec-3G and examined their antiviral functions as well as the DNA editing activity. Point mutations in the C-terminal active site such as E259Q and C291A almost completely abrogated the antiviral function, while those in the N-terminal active site such as E67Q and C100A retained this activity to a lesser extent as compared with that of the wild type. The DNA editing activities of E67Q and E259Q mutants were both retained but impaired to the same extent. This indicates that the enzymatic activity of this protein is essential but not a sole determinant of the antiviral activity. Furthermore, all the deletion mutants tested in this study lost the antiviral activity because of the loss of the activity for dimerization, suggesting that the entire protein structure is necessary for the antiviral function.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The enzymatic activity of CEM15/Apobec-3G is essential for the regulation of the infectivity of HIV-1 virion but not a sole determinant of its antiviral activity.</str>
    <str name="id">12970355</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The vif gene of human immunodeficiency virus type 1 (HIV-1) encodes a basic Mr 23,000 protein that is necessary for production of infectious virions by nonpermissive cells (human lymphocytes and macrophages) but not by permissive cells such as HeLa-CD4. It had been proposed that permissive cells may contain an unidentified factor that functions like the viral Vif protein. To test this hypothesis, we produced pseudotyped wild-type and vif-deleted HIV gpt virions (which contain the HIV-1 genome with the bacterial mycophenolic acid resistance gene gpt in place of the viral env gene) in permissive cells, and we used them to generate nonpermissive H9 leukemic T cells that express these proviruses. We then fused these H9 cells with permissive HeLa cells that express the HIV-1 envelope glycoprotein gp120-gp41, and we asked whether the heterokaryons would release infectious HIV gpt virions. The results clearly showed that the vif-deleted virions released by the heterokaryons were noninfectious whereas the wild-type virions were highly infectious. This strongly suggests that nonpermissive cells, the natural targets of HIV-1, contain a potent endogenous inhibitor of HIV-1 replication that is overcome by Vif.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">An endogenous inhibitor of human immunodeficiency virus in human lymphocytes is overcome by the viral Vif protein.</str>
    <str name="id">9811770</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Progression through mitosis occurs because cyclin B/Cdc2 activation induces the anaphase promoting complex (APC) to cause cyclin B destruction and mitotic exit. To ensure that cyclin B/Cdc2 does not prematurely activate the APC in early mitosis, there must be a mechanism delaying APC activation. Emi1 is a protein capable of inhibiting the APC in S and G2. We show here that Emi1 is phosphorylated by Cdc2, and on a DSGxxS consensus site, is subsequently recognized by the SCF(betaTrCP/Slimb) ubiquitin ligase and destroyed, thus providing a delay for APC activation. Failure of betaTrCP-dependent Emi1 destruction stabilizes APC substrates and results in mitotic catastrophe including centrosome overduplication, potentially explaining mitotic deficiencies in Drosophila Slimb/betaTrCP mutants. We hypothesize that Emi1 destruction relieves a late prophase checkpoint for APC activation.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Prophase destruction of Emi1 by the SCF(betaTrCP/Slimb) ubiquitin ligase activates the anaphase promoting complex to allow progression beyond prometaphase.</str>
    <str name="id">12791267</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>An affinity purification strategy was developed to characterize human proteasome complexes diversity as well as endogenous proteasome-interacting proteins (PIPs). This single step procedure, initially used for 20 S proteasome purification, was adapted to purify all existing physiological proteasome complexes associated to their various regulatory complexes and to their interacting partners. The method was applied to the purification of proteasome complexes and their PIPs from human erythrocytes but can be used to purify proteasomes from any human sample as starting material. The benefit of in vivo formaldehyde cross-linking as a stabilizer of protein-protein interactions was studied by comparing the status of purified proteasomes and the identified proteins in both protocols (with or without formaldehyde cross-linking). Subsequent proteomics analyses identified all proteasomal subunits, known regulators, and recently assigned partners. Moreover other proteins implicated at different levels of the ubiquitin-proteasome system were also identified for the first time as PIPs. One of them, the ubiquitin-specific protease USP7, also known as HAUSP, is an important player in the p53-HDM2 pathway. The specificity of the interaction was further confirmed using a complementary approach that consisted of the reverse immunoprecipitation with HAUSP as a bait. Altogether we provide a valuable tool that should contribute, through the identification of partners likely to affect proteasomal function, to a better understanding of this complex proteolytic machinery in any living human cell and/or organ/tissue and in different cell physiological states.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Affinity purification strategy to capture human endogenous proteasome complexes diversity and to identify proteasome-interacting proteins.</str>
    <str name="id">19193609</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Cyclin A is a stable protein in S and G2 phases, but is destabilized when cells enter mitosis and is almost completely degraded before the metaphase to anaphase transition. Microinjection of antibodies against subunits of the anaphase-promoting complex/cyclosome (APC/C) or against human Cdc20 (fizzy) arrested cells at metaphase and stabilized both cyclins A and B1. Cyclin A was efficiently polyubiquitylated by Cdc20 or Cdh1-activated APC/C in vitro, but in contrast to cyclin B1, the proteolysis of cyclin A was not delayed by the spindle assembly checkpoint. The degradation of cyclin B1 was accelerated by inhibition of the spindle assembly checkpoint. These data suggest that the APC/C is activated as cells enter mitosis and immediately targets cyclin A for degradation, whereas the spindle assembly checkpoint delays the degradation of cyclin B1 until the metaphase to anaphase transition. The "destruction box" (D-box) of cyclin A is 10-20 residues longer than that of cyclin B. Overexpression of wild-type cyclin A delayed the metaphase to anaphase transition, whereas expression of cyclin A mutants lacking a D-box arrested cells in anaphase.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Anaphase-promoting complex/cyclosome-dependent proteolysis of human cyclin A starts at the beginning of mitosis and is not subject to the spindle assembly checkpoint.</str>
    <str name="id">11285280</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Protein ubiquitination is a key regulatory process essential to life at a cellular level; significant efforts have been made to identify ubiquitinated proteins through proteomics studies, but the level of success has not reached that of heavily studied post-translational modifications, such as phosphorylation. HRD1, an E3 ubiquitin ligase, has been implicated in rheumatoid arthritis, but no disease-relevant substrates have been identified. To identify these substrates, we have taken both peptide and protein level approaches to enrich for ubiquitinated proteins in the presence and absence of HRD1. At the protein level, a two-step strategy was taken using cells expressing His(6)-tagged ubiquitin, enriching proteins first based on their ubiquitination and second based on the His tag with protein identification by LC-MS/MS. Application of this method resulted in identification and quantification of more than 400 ubiquitinated proteins, a fraction of which were found to be sensitive to HRD1 and were therefore deemed candidate substrates. In a second approach, ubiquitinated peptides were enriched after tryptic digestion by peptide immunoprecipitation using an antibody specific for the diglycine-labeled internal lysine residue indicative of protein ubiquitination, with peptides and ubiquitination sites identified by LC-MS/MS. Peptide immunoprecipitation resulted in identification of over 1800 ubiquitinated peptides on over 900 proteins in each study, with several proteins emerging as sensitive to HRD1 levels. Notably, significant overlap exists between the HRD1 substrates identified by the protein-based and the peptide-based strategies, with clear cross-validation apparent both qualitatively and quantitatively, demonstrating the effectiveness of both strategies and furthering our understanding of HRD1 biology.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Ubiquitin ligase substrate identification through quantitative proteomics at both the protein and peptide levels.</str>
    <str name="id">21987572</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Professional antigen-presenting cells secrete major histocompatibility complex class II (MHC II) carrying exosomes with unclear physiological function(s). Exosomes are first generated as the intraluminal vesicles (ILVs) of a specific type of multivesicular body, and are then secreted by fusion of this compartment with the plasma membrane. We have previously shown that in contrast to the sorting of MHC II at lysosomally targeted multivesicular bodies, sorting of MHC II into exosomes does not rely on MHC II ubiquitination. In search for proteins that drive the incorporation of MHC II into exosomes or functionally discriminate exosomal from plasma membrane MHC II, we first analyzed the total proteome of highly purified B cell-derived exosomes using sensitive and accurate mass spectrometry (MS), and identified 539 proteins, including known and not previously identified constituents. Using quantitative MS, we then identified a small subset of proteins that were specifically co-immunoprecipitated with MHC II from detergent-solubilized exosomes. These include HSC71, HSP90, 14-3-3ɛ, CD20 and pyruvate kinase type M2 (PKM2), and we speculate on the functionality of their interaction with exosomal MHC II.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">MHC class II-associated proteins in B-cell exosomes and potential functional implications for exosome biogenesis.</str>
    <str name="id">20458337</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) has a small genome and therefore relies heavily on the host cellular machinery to replicate. Identifying which host proteins and complexes come into physical contact with the viral proteins is crucial for a comprehensive understanding of how HIV rewires the host's cellular machinery during the course of infection. Here we report the use of affinity tagging and purification mass spectrometry to determine systematically the physical interactions of all 18 HIV-1 proteins and polyproteins with host proteins in two different human cell lines (HEK293 and Jurkat). Using a quantitative scoring system that we call MiST, we identified with high confidence 497 HIV-human protein-protein interactions involving 435 individual human proteins, with ∼40% of the interactions being identified in both cell types. We found that the host proteins hijacked by HIV, especially those found interacting in both cell types, are highly conserved across primates. We uncovered a number of host complexes targeted by viral proteins, including the finding that HIV protease cleaves eIF3d, a subunit of eukaryotic translation initiation factor 3. This host protein is one of eleven identified in this analysis that act to inhibit HIV replication. This data set facilitates a more comprehensive and detailed understanding of how the host machinery is manipulated during the course of HIV infection.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Global landscape of HIV-human protein complexes.</str>
    <str name="id">22190034</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Replication of human immunodeficiency virus type 1 (HIV-1) in most primary cells and some immortalized T-cell lines depends on the activity of the viral infectivity factor (Vif). Vif has the ability to counteract a cellular inhibitor, recently identified as CEM15, that blocks infectivity of Vif-defective HIV-1 variants. CEM15 is identical to APOBEC3G and belongs to a family of proteins involved in RNA and DNA deamination. We cloned APOBEC3G from a human kidney cDNA library and confirmed that the protein acts as a potent inhibitor of HIV replication and is sensitive to the activity of Vif. We found that wild-type Vif inhibits packaging of APOBEC3G into virus particles in a dose-dependent manner. In contrast, biologically inactive variants carrying in-frame deletions in various regions of Vif or mutation of two highly conserved cysteine residues did not inhibit packaging of APOBEC3G. Interestingly, expression of APOBEC3G in the presence of wild-type Vif not only affected viral packaging but also reduced its intracellular expression level. This effect was not seen in the presence of biologically inactive Vif variants. Pulse-chase analyses did not reveal a significant difference in the stability of APOBEC3G in the presence or absence of Vif. However, in the presence of Vif, the rate of synthesis of APOBEC3G was slightly reduced. The reduction of intracellular APOBEC3G in the presence of Vif does not fully account for the Vif-induced reduction of virus-associated APOBEC3G, suggesting that Vif may function at several levels to prevent packaging of APOBEC3G into virus particles.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The human immunodeficiency virus type 1 Vif protein reduces intracellular expression and inhibits packaging of APOBEC3G (CEM15), a cellular inhibitor of virus infectivity.</str>
    <str name="id">14557625</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Ubiquitination plays a key role in protein degradation and signal transduction. Ubiquitin is a small protein modifier that is adducted to lysine residues by the combined function of E1, E2, and E3 enzymes and is removed by deubiquitinating enzymes. Characterization of ubiquitination sites is important for understanding the role of this modification in cellular processes and disease. However, until recently, large-scale characterization of endogenous ubiquitination sites has been hampered by the lack of efficient enrichment techniques. The introduction of antibodies that specifically recognize peptides with lysine residues that harbor a di-glycine remnant (K-ε-GG) following tryptic digestion has dramatically improved the ability to enrich and identify ubiquitination sites from cellular lysates. We used this enrichment technique to study the effects of proteasome inhibition by MG-132 and deubiquitinase inhibition by PR-619 on ubiquitination sites in human Jurkat cells by quantitative high performance mass spectrometry. Minimal fractionation of digested lysates prior to immunoaffinity enrichment increased the yield of K-ε-GG peptides three- to fourfold resulting in detection of up to ~3300 distinct K-GG peptides in SILAC triple encoded experiments starting from 5 mg of protein per label state. In total, we identify 5533 distinct K-ε-GG peptides of which 4907 were quantified in this study, demonstrating that the strategy presented is a practical approach to perturbational studies in cell systems. We found that proteasome inhibition by MG-132 and deubiquitinase inhibition by PR-619 induces significant changes to the ubiquitin landscape, but that not all ubiquitination sites regulated by MG-132 and PR-619 are likely substrates for the ubiquitin-proteasome system. Additionally, we find that the proteasome and deubiquitinase inhibitors studied induced only minor changes in protein expression levels regardless of the extent of regulation induced at the ubiquitin site level. We attribute this finding to the low stoichiometry of the majority ubiquitination sites identified in this study.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Methods for quantification of in vivo changes in protein ubiquitination following proteasome and deubiquitinase inhibition.</str>
    <str name="id">22505724</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Epstein-Barr virus nuclear antigen 5 (EBNA5) is one of the first viral proteins detected after primary EBV infection and has been shown to be required for efficient transformation of B lymphocytes. EBNA5 is a protein that has many suggested functions but the underlying biology remains to be clarified. To gain further insight into the biological roles of the proposed multifunctional EBNA5, we isolated EBNA5 containing protein complexes using a modified tandem affinity purification (TAP) method and identified the protein components by LC-MS/MS analysis of tryptic digests on a LTQ-FT-ICR mass spectrometer. The modified TAP tag contained a Protein A domain and a StrepTagII sequence separated by two Tobacco Etch Virus protease cleavage sites and was fused to the C-terminus of EBNA5. Our results confirmed the wide applicability of this two-step affinity purification strategy for purification of protein complexes in mammalian cells. A total of 147 novel putative EBNA5 interaction partners were identified, 37 of which were validated with LC-MS/MS in split-tag experiments or in co-immuno precipitates from HEK293 cell extracts. This subgroup included the Bcl2-associated Athanogene 2 (BAG2) co-chaperone involved in protein folding and renaturation, the 26S proteasome subunit 2 involved in regulation of ubiquitin/proteasome protein degradation, and the heterogeneous ribonucleoprotein M (hnRNP M) involved in pre-mRNA processing. These EBNA5 interactors were further verified by co-immunoprecipitations from cell extracts of three EBV-positive lymphoblastoid lines. The combination of the Hsp70, Hsc70, BAG2 and 26S proteasome subunit 2 interactors suggests that EBNA5 might have a functional relationship with protein quality control systems that recognize proteins with abnormal structures and either refold them to normal conformation or target them for degradation. Our study also confirms previously identified interactors including HA95, Hsp70, Hsc70, Hsp27, HAX-1, Prolyl 4-hydroxylase, S3a, and alpha- and beta-tubulin.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Identification of intracellular proteins associated with the EBV-encoded nuclear antigen 5 using an efficient TAP procedure and FT-ICR mass spectrometry.</str>
    <str name="id">18457437</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>The human immunodeficiency virus-1 Tat protein inhibits the peptidase activity of the 20S proteasome and competes with the 11S regulator/PA28 for binding to the 20S proteasome. Structural comparison revealed a common site in the Tat protein and the 11S regulator alpha-subunit (REGalpha) called the REG/Tat-proteasome-binding (RTP) site. Kinetic assays found amino acid residues Lys51, Arg52 and Asp67 forming the RTP site of Tat to be responsible for the effects on proteasomes in vitro. The RTP site identified in REGalpha consists of the residues Glu235, Lys236 and Lys239. Mutation of the REGalpha amino acid residues Glu235 and Lys236 to Ala resulted in an REGalpha mutant that lost the ability to activate the 20S proteasome even though it still forms complexes with REGbeta and binds to the 20S proteasome. The REGalpha RTP site is needed to enhance the presentation of a cytomegalovirus pp89 protein-derived epitope by MHC class I molecules in mouse fibroblasts. Cell experiments demonstrate that the Tat amino acid residues 37-72 are necessary for the interaction of the viral protein with proteasomes in vivo. Full-length Tat and the Tat peptide 37-72 suppressed 11S regulator-mediated presentation of the pp89 epitope. In contrast, the Tat peptide 37-72 with mutations of amino acid residues Lys51, Arg52 and Asp67 to Ala was not able to reduce antigen presentation.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">The RTP site shared by the HIV-1 Tat protein and the 11S regulator subunit alpha is crucial for their effects on proteasome function including antigen processing.</str>
    <str name="id">12419264</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>Intracellular proteins are processed into small peptides that bind HLA class I molecules of the major histocompatibility complex (MHC) in order to be presented to T lymphocytes. The proteasome, a multi-subunit protease, has recently been implicated in the generation of these peptides. Two genes encoding proteasome subunits, LMP2 and LMP7, are tightly linked to the TAP peptide transport loci in the class II region of the human MHC. Inclusion of the LMP subunits may alter proteasome activity, biasing it towards the production of peptides with carboxyl termini appropriate for binding HLA class I molecules. Nevertheless, mutant cells that lack the LMP genes are able to process and present antigens at the cell surface at similar levels to wild-type cells. These results raise questions about the role of the proteasome, and in particular of the LMP subunits, in antigen processing.</str>
      <str>We have cloned the genes encoding a new proteasome subunit, MB1, which is closely related to LMP7, and that encoding a second subunit, Delta, which is closely related to LMP2. Expression of the MB1 and delta genes is reciprocal to that of the LMP genes: MB1 and delta are up-regulated in mutant cell lines lacking LMPs and down-regulated in the presence of gamma-interferon. The MB1 and delta genes are found to be located on chromosomes 14 and 17, respectively, raising interesting evolutionary questions about how the LMP genes independently became incorporated into the MHC.</str>
      <str>We suggest that the subtle phenotype of LMP-deficient cell lines results from the compensatory expression in these lines of two other proteasome subunits, MB1 and Delta.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">Proteasome components with reciprocal expression to that of the MHC-encoded LMP proteins.</str>
    <str name="id">7820546</str></doc>
  <doc>
    <arr name="medline_abstract_text">
      <str>A precise understanding of mechanisms used by human embryonic stem cells (hESCs) to maintain genomic integrity is very important for their potential clinical applications. The G1 checkpoint serves to protect genomic integrity and prevents cells with damaged DNA from entering S-phase. Previously, we have shown that downregulation of cyclin-dependent kinase 2 (CDK2) in hESC causes G1 arrest, loss of pluripotency, upregulation of cell cycle inhibitors p21 and p27 and differentiation toward extraembryonic lineages. In this study, we investigate in detail the role of CDK2 in cellular processes, which are crucial to the maintenance of genomic stability in hESC such as G1 checkpoint activation, DNA repair, and apoptosis. Our results suggest that downregulation of CDK2 triggers the G1 checkpoint through the activation of the ATM-CHK2-p53-p21 pathway. Downregulation of CDK2 is able to induce sustained DNA damage and to elicit the DNA damage response (DDR) as evidenced by the formation of distinct γ-H2.AX and RAD52-BRCA1 foci in hESC nuclei. CDK2 downregulation causes high apoptosis at the early time points; however, this is gradually decreased overtime as the DDR is initiated. Our mass spectrometry analysis suggest that CDK2 does interact with a large number of proteins that are involved in key cellular processes such as DNA replication, cell cycle progression, DNA repair, chromatin modeling, thus, suggesting a crucial role for CDK2 in orchestrating a fine balance between cellular proliferation, cell death, and DNA repair in hESC.</str>
    </arr>
    <str name="medline_article_title">An important role for CDK2 in G1 to S checkpoint activation and DNA damage response in human embryonic stem cells.</str>
    <str name="id">21319273</str></doc>
</result>
</response>
